(Animal sound)
(Neighing)
(He takes a deep breath.)
(Bird screech)
(Phone rings.)
Hm?
(Continued ringing)
Ah! Help!
(Gasping)
(Phone rings.)
Healthy.
(Woman) We have a shitstorm.
-Mrs. Tüfek...
We must act.
-It's two o'clock at night.
Are you still in the office?
-In front of your house. Was on the way.
Uh, so, Mrs. Tüfek, I find
your commitment… really great,
but my wife woke up.
I thought she had moved out.
-No. That was once.
A couple of days. Everything will be alright again.
-Hm.
Everything’s great.
It’s about the last campaign.
-Why don’t you call Mr. Stumpf?
Is on vacation. So,
concentration. The Friend Rate.
Three couples, all white, cis,
hetero. Only the waiter isn’t white.
On Twitter, all hell has broken loose.
-As always. And that means something different now.
I say "Twitter".
It's just stupid, "X".
Read that! Read aloud!
-"White Hetero-Happyland,
Black serves. Seriously? Fuck
you, Fernfunk. #stramm-deutsch.
So much for diversity. Heterocliquees
and racism. 1950. Triple fail.
Embarrassing. Backward.
Ridiculous. Far, fuck you, you fuckers.
“Really impressive, your
incompetence.” Yes, Mrs. Tüfek, please…
The photo is unfortunate,
but we’re not Nike, after all.
We are Fernfunk AG.
How many people have
commented there now, and, and…
Since yesterday
evening, around 80.
80,000?
No, 80.
But… 80 people?
Mhm.
That's at most a
shitstorm, a shit breeze.
(Lively music)
(Knocking)
-(Heilreich) Leni, get out of the bathroom!
(Leni) You're annoying.
(Linus) I want to go to the bathroom!
-(Leni) I'll be ready in a minute!
Man!
(Heilreich) Why are clothes
lying around everywhere?
Bandwidth optimization strategy.
We're on it. Also with the
Multi-Crowd Connectivity.
(Groaning)
-Our turn.
It is clear to me that Mclntire is
expecting results with the Family Plan.
We need new upselling…
Tomorrow!
-Morning, Mr. Puschinsky.
... and cross-selling strategies.
-Morning.
Morning, children. It’s my turn.
Sales automation and
digitalization, that takes time.
We are still waiting for the
market segmentation analysis.
I'll keep asking
until I have it.
We need a real Next-Generation
Network Transformation.
Is there any news on customer retention? Loyalty program?
- We're working on it.
(Heilreich) The KPIs are
again below expectations.
I know, but we are intensively
working on new innovation strategies.
The job interview. Should I do that?
- I’ll do it myself.
And please take another cup.
-I'll be right there, hm?
Excuse me, Dr. Steinhof. I
completely agree with you.
Aha. Aha, aha, aha. So your
documents, Mr. Baum, are really top-notch.
However, some of your ideas…
Home office is of course okay, but…
...Four-day week?
I'd like that too.
My wife is pregnant, and I would like to
experience this time very consciously with her.
Congratulations. And next
year then... parental leave?
You don't want to use
WhatsApp, no emails after 6 PM.
And not even on the weekend.
Mr. Baum, shouldn't you first
accomplish something here?
Before you demand
something like that?
I find that a little difficult.
And I find your
cup a little difficult.
Yes? Why, uh...
That's not how
you think. It's a gag.
I, uh... distance
myself from this cup.
She does not meet the
values of Fernfunk AG.
We just kept her as
a sort of... memorial.
Yes, that is a reminder…cup.
People! People!
Come! A little faster please.
Hello! Now everyone listen up!
You too, Mr. Juri.
Why is this stupid cup
still sitting in our kitchen?
"I boss, you nothing!"
That doesn't work!
Here.
Shh!
I love my penis. People, no. No!
They themselves said, you
find these old cups amusing.
When did I say that?
-At the Christmas party.
Oh yeah? Well. I’m sorry.
If these cups have
offended anyone’s feelings,
then...
-The trigger mugs are funny.
The penis cup reminds me of Mr. Gerlach,
who is now in the nursing home.
One is allowed to love one's penis.
-Yes.
Or not?
-In your private life, okay.
But not at Fernfunk AG.
Here, penises are not loved.
(Clears throat)
-Don't misunderstand me.
Of course, you are allowed to love penises.
Your own, others', penises in general.
I don't want to discriminate against
anyone. But these two cups have to go.
What would probably happen if
Mclntire’s business consultant*s saw that?
They don’t understand
our modest humor.
That can have consequences
for the entire department.
Yes.
(Gentle piano music)
And in this dream,
you were naked.
Naked on a horse.
-No, uh, I was wearing sort of...
So something like
a, um, loincloth.
I think I was dreaming
something like a sort of...
... Native Americans.
Okay. Wouldn't quite
be my choice of words.
I am terribly sorry,
the dream, Dr. Sand.
The soul may dream whatever it wants. The
question is: Why do you dream such things?
As a child, I often
played in the forest.
My best friend Peter
and I carved arrows
and have wigwams, wigwams…
-Wigwams.
... built wigwams and
wanted to be like Winnetou.
So embarrassing.
-As long as you understand,
that "Winnetou” is a fairy tale from the perspective of an old white man.
- Sure.
Sure.
-Sure.
Crystal clear.
-Hm.
How is it going this
week at the company?
Also,
I am a painter… I got
loud, but that is not me.
I don’t want to be that either. I’m
good with people. That’s my strength.
But here with us in the long-distance radio station,
there’s a certain nervousness prevailing right now.
I mean, where is that any different nowadays?
Who doesn’t have panic attacks these days?
Hm? War, climate.
Viruses, Putin, Trump,
China, Iran,
Migration, Inflation,
Racism, Islamism, antisemitism,
fascism and others learn, every day.
And everywhere avocado toast,
oat milk and influencers telling you,
how to live one's life,
and all this goddamn...
Do you believe, your
wife is still coming?
Actually, this is supposed
to be couples therapy.
She has an appointment. I think,
because of her language thingy,
because of her project.
-(Ringtone)
Excuse me. This is my son. I
have to quickly go over there.
Hello, Linus. What's up?
Hey, Dad.
-Is everything okay?
There's a small problem with the roof.
-What's wrong with the roof?
It's burning.
-(Puschinsky) My God!
(Tires squeal.)
-(Someone coughs.)
Oh God… Mr. Puschinsky!
Mr. Puschinsky!
Mr. Heilreich.
-What the hell is going on here?
Small cable fire.
Everything is under control.
Are you kidding me!
-(both) Good day.
Good day, Sophie, Ricco.
Why don't you call the fire department?
-You know exactly why!
You know why.
-Man...
... that is really bullshit!
\"a real... fuck bullshit!
Carla.
Carla. Hello.
-Ah.
Did you notice that our house is burning?
-Yes.
And you're digging around
and listening to David Bowie.
Are you looking for gold?
Do you want to bribe the dog?
I wanted to sign the lease
for my language school today.
But they cancelled. Better
offer from a betting provider.
“Superwin-100-Tippikowsky-McBet”,
So what.
They're getting my shop, great.
I’m sorry, Carla.
-I absolutely wanted to call the fire department.
But Mr. Puschinsky
explained to me, that he or you
or we employ illegal workers.
The term is racist.
"Schwarzarbeit” stems etymologically from "to
do something in the dark". Thank you, Leni.
It still sounds racist.
They are Pushkin's cousins.
He offered a good price.
In any case, I didn’t want to get
needlessly upset about all of that,
but rather continue constructively
here, because it feels good to me and...
... because Mrs. Kramer has cancer.
-What?
She doesn’t have much time left and is supposed
to have a beautiful view in her last weeks.
Look how it looks
here, since the storm.
I’ve asked you a
hundred times, with me…
I want something to bloom here. Okay?
-Yes. That, that's what I want too.
(Leni) Papa.
-Hm? Yes?
No one is hurt. That’s the most important thing.
-Yes, Leni.
You're right. And how are you
doing, so shortly before the exams?
It’s easy. No worries.
-(Doorbell)
Mrs. Tüfek. Yes?
-The call is running.
Which call?
-With the board.
Because of the shitstorm.
Hello?
Hello, Mr. Dr. Steinhof.
I'm sorry for the slight delay.
Good day.
-Hello, everyone.
Also, one more time:
First of all, Mr. Stumpf has been granted
leave of absence due to the last campaign.
We must react immediately, if
accusations of racism are made.
Especially now before
the quarterly figures.
Such incidents frighten
off new investor*s.
I say it again: Present yourself
now from your most progressive side.
Gender in all communications.
Show that at Fernfunk AG...
Uah! God! Fuck! Shit!
Fuck! Fuck! Shit!
Puschinsky, you
brainless asshole…
Oh. Oh.
Pardon, I, I thought,
I was on mute.
Small incident, my house is burning.
-Yes, that doesn't matter at all.
That is the kind of toxic
behavior, we don’t need.
Total no-go. Pull yourself together,
then this thunderstorm will pass.
to most of you.
Sorry.
Mr. Schneider?
Uh, good day.
-Good day.
Hello?
-Hello, Dad. It's me.
Who is there?
Your son, Heinz.
-Tell me who you are!
Dad, Heinz is here.
I did the shopping.
Heinz, why don't you just say it?
-(Doorbell)
The world is getting
dumber and dumber, Heinz.
Well, as far as artificial
intelligence is concerned…
I mean the people.
They are getting dumber.
Yesterday an invitation arrived
from the museum association.
It seriously said in
there: "Dear guest*s."
“Guest*s, what kind of word is that?
Do people also say “human being*s”?
“People*”? Or what?
The Germans always drift
into extremes, into delusion.
Even if they want to be the good ones,
they always have to overdo everything.
So, I’m actually here, to, to…
Have you heard about the US
swimmer, who used to be a man?
Two meters, what a pain, swims
with the women. Always wins.
Is that fair? Where is the feminism?
-You’ve told me that three times already.
Some people identify as cats.
Do we have to equip all public
restrooms with litter boxes?
It’s good that your mother didn’t
have to experience that anymore.
Dad, what happened last Monday?
You hit a car, in front
of a supermarket, again.
Also... (He clears his throat.)
I want you to give me
your driver’s license.
What did you say?
-Your...
Your driver's license… give it to me.
-I need my car.
Yes?
-Just think about what could happen.
What’s next, huh? Should
I go to the home, or what?
I am mentally healthier than most out there.
-I know.
Therefore, I decided,
to run for mayor,
here in Waldstetten.
Maybe I’ll start a party.
You are 83 years old.
-So what?
Should I go to bed and die, or what?
-No.
So, please go now, okay? You'll
never get your driver's license.
No! I'm telling you.
-Uh, Dad...
Unbelievable. He
wants my driver’s license.
(Soft, melancholic piano music)
Hello.
So, Mr. Puschinsky?
-It...
Yes.
(He hums to himself.)
Mmh, doesn't that smell delicious.
And? How was it at your father's?
Great. He wants to become mayor.
Well, this is going to be fun.
-Yes. Go ahead and sit down.
Sorry, I need to shower
and then I’ll give tutoring.
Mo thinks he's the cool
gangster and has a lot of Rizz.
He always calls me princess. It’s so
embarrassing, but also really sweet.
He really is still a little boy.
Smells good. Save some
for me, without shrimp.
I think you're eating fish.
-Shrimp are shellfish.
Where do you want to go?
-I’ll call you back.
Leni. Hello!
-I'm going to Nadira's, and we're studying.
We are planning our trip,
and then I have to babysit.
What kind of trip? Where do you want to go?
-Doesn't matter. Just get me out of this dump.
They want to go to
Portugal for three months.
Take a language course, learn to surf.
-Three months, just like that?
Also uh...
-(Door slams shut.)
She's smoking. She
just lit a cigarette...
I didn't even know, that
young people still smoke.
That doesn't suit Leni at all.
-Hm...
I cooked extra, so we
could be like a normal family.
sitting at the table...
-Heinz, just because you're cooking,
don't we have to jump
around the table with joy.
(Heinz) Hey. Well, big guy.
Well, Linus.
Linus?
Yes, dear father?
-Are you eating with me?
Sorry, I must seize
world domination.
That is not the real world.
-You say. Who even knows that for sure?
Yes, um…
There are a few
roof beams charred.
Yes, and all the wiring...
-Cost?
Give me a number.
-50,000, 60,000 Euros.
Somehow… I told you, I’m
not an expert on things like that.
And then you said: "Yes, you
are the expert for everything."
And then I told you…
-I know, I know.
I know. My mistake.
Are you hungry? Would
you like to sit with me?
Hm?
Thank you, very kind.
I must go to my wife.
But… I’d like to take
something with me.
(Softly melancholic piano music)
(Telephone dial tone)
(Woman) Hi.
-Do you know who’s looking at me?
Your self-made
snail. It misses you.
Ah yes, uh... nice.
-How are you? Where are you right now?
In a studio.
-Oh, in studies.
Yes, of course you’re in college.
-No, Dad, studio. Music studio.
Um, hasn't Mom
talked to you yet?
No, uh... About what?
Ah. Yes, I have…
finished my studies.
That just didn't fit.
-So that's really not...
That is a private university.
I paid for the whole year.
I knew it, you only
care about the money.
That's not true. You absolutely
wanted to study marketing.
You have...
-Shit capitalist products to sell, that’s not me.
I'm concentrating on the band.
-Band? What kind of band?
I don’t feel like,
talking about it.
I don't feel like financing
your rent and your life in Berlin,
if you can't even do one thing...
-I understood.
Dad, I don't want your damn money at all.
I'd rather sleep on the subway. Thanks.
That's not right... Hello?
-(Honking)
(Soft piano music)
(Ringing)
(Linus) Holy.
Hello, Mrs. Tüfek.
Yes, he's there. Is it urgent?
All clear, I’ll pass it
on. Have a nice day.
Heilreich...
-Dad.
Yes?
-You are to come to the company.
Is anything super important.
-Ah, uh...
What time is it?
-Around ten.
Oh Shit. Oh Scheiße, Mann.
Why aren't you at school?
Federal Youth Games.
-Hm. Oh God.
(Dynamic music)
(Tires squeal.)
(Applause)
The fax machine 100 Alpha XT.
That’s where the triumphant
march of our founders began.
Let us never forget
that, dear friend*s.
(softly) God be thanked.
-The Long-Range Radio Corporation
was significantly involved in
launching the fax machine in Germany.
We were always with the finger on
the pulse, and even now we want to,
despite all challenges, looking
into the future with courage.
Yes.
Um…
But… But…
... um, we also know, we
need to... renew ourselves.
We must shed our
skin like a cobra.
Yes, like a cobra.
(Hissing)
(Steinhof, he laughs.)
But first, I would
like to thank you all.
Without you, the successes of the last
few months would have been impossible.
Thank you! Yes! Yes!
(He sighs.) Would you
have another glass for me?
Oh.
-The waitress is over there.
I’m sorry. She was just standing
here, and there’s a certain resemblance.
A certain resemblance?
-Yes, in type.
In terms of type, exciting.
What type do you mean exactly?
From the clothing, clothing
type. You also have such, such...
My goodness, it was a
misunderstanding. I'm sorry!
Also, yes...
And for this process,
of strategic realignment.
we got help
from the best management
consultancy in the world.
They work in New
York, in London,
in Shanghai and now
also in Waldstetten.
Please join us in welcoming Lian
Bell and her team from Mclntire!
(Cheers)
Good day. Just briefly, my
team and I, we are very pleased,
with you together to bring the
KPIs back to where they should be.
But it’s also about values, and for me
the most important value: communication.
Complicated topic, I know.
An open, honest, effective
collaboration at eye level.
My name is Lian. You
can approach me anytime.
Don't be afraid, we
don't bite. Thank you.
Thank you, Lian.
Now it is a very
special joy for me,
To introduce our new
Technology Consultant to you.
He started here in
our IT department,
went to the USA, had a
top career in Silicon Valley.
I think it's super awesome, that he's
now returning to his homeland.
Here is Captain Future himself:
Dr. Alexander Sahavi!
(Cheers)
(Man) Bravo!
-(Cheers)
Many thanks, Dr. Steinhof er.
Well, home. Difficult concept.
Home is where,
wonderful people are,
with whom one can connect, feel good, exchange ideas.
-Hm.
Please just call
me Älex, just Älex.
Älex.
-(Woman) Hi, Älex.
What do you think when you
hear “AI”? Evil robots will rule you,
replace, annihilate?
Don't watch so much Netflix.
-(Laughter)
I tell you: Do not be afraid!
See this technology
as your ally.
A companion on your path, to
become the best version of yourselves.
Whoo! Yes!
Yes...
This young person here,
that’s me. Yes, at 17.
Wow.
-I stand by that. Body Positivity, sure.
But I wasn't happy,
I felt unhealthy.
I started running, have
run three marathons,
was on Mount Everest and am taking
part in Elon Musk’s astronaut program.
Okay...
-And I have with my aid organization
the Amazonian titan
beetle from extinction.
That's just a side note.
-Wow!
At this moment, you will receive a link.
-(Tone signals)
To your ally,
a Synthetic Assistant
Mind, shortly SAM.
SAM, can you hear me?
-Hi, Älex,
I can hear you well,
thank you. How are you?
Fantastic. And you?
-Great, thanks.
Hello, Fernfunk AG. So
many great people here.
Hey, Klaus Weber from
accounting. How are you doing today?
Great, thanks.
You see, SAM already knows all
of you. He will support all of you.
In case of questions like: Is
my work-life balance in order,
My to-do list effectively, my email
sensitively and purposefully formulated?
Is my posture gentle? Are my gut
flora and bowel movements okay?
Am I winking too much?
Am I using too many emojis?
We are humans.
We make mistakes. We
overlook, forget, repress.
And no matter how hard we
try, we all have prejudices. SAM...
... No.
Well, I suppose.
-(Incomprehensible whispering)
That’s all new to you.
But we can optimize a lot
here, also in the social sphere.
That was shown to
me by a small incident:
An employee, whoever they may
be, has a person who appears Asian.
discriminatingly categorized as a waitress.
-Hey!
Excuse me, sorry, but… that
wasn’t how it was. That’s not right.
(clearing his throat) Heinz Heilreich,
regional sales manager for South-East.
Head of Sales.
-Hello, Heinz.
We know who you are. Glad to meet you.
-Hm. Uh, hello.
That had nothing to do with prejudices,
it was just a small misunderstanding.
Besides… what
kind of prejudices?
Asians... ah, –+inside certainly
don’t only work in catering.
You are very often
the very best student*s,
highly intelligent,
diligent, friendly.
Prejudice, prejudice, prejudice.
But I admire you for your courage.
Now we know we’re talking about you.
That is the first step towards improvement.
-Super, Heinz. Thank you.
(Älex) Great!
Heinz, the first step.
Such shit. Such a show-off.
You’re portraying me as a racist.
-You were clumsy.
It is good to critically question
oneself, as a human being.
I think this Älex has
something special. Good guy.
Wha... Good guy?
-Yes, definitely.
Uh, Mr. Heilreich!
Yes?
-Come here.
Um…
... We need to talk.
Yes… uh, please, Dr. Steinhof.
-No, not here, not now.
Do you have time on the
weekend? For a little walk?
(He swallows.)
What is that supposed to mean?
We've never been for a walk before.
Wait and see. Perhaps
it’s completely harmless.
Mr. Heilreich, the McIntire people
are asking for our current figures.
Why don't they just ask
SAM, hm? SAM, the superman.
SAM, die Zukunft.
SAM, the future.
You're asking, but you.
-Monday. If I'm still there then.
Mrs. Türfek, please don’t vape here.
-Yes, Yuri, it’s fine.
I don’t believe that right now.
Why are these damn cups
still here? I threw them away!
The cleaning lady was probably thinking...
-Oh, her!
The cleaning lady isn’t paid
for thinking, but for cleaning!
I’ll take the cups with me,
smash them, and I’ll bury them.
and then off again and light it.
-Mr. Heilreich! Mr. Heilreich!
World...
-(Tüfek) They're just cups!
Or I’ll throw them in the toilet. That has to…
-(Tüfek) They’re just cups!
Ja, absolut. Yes, absolutely.
Is that the concept for the new store?
-Yes. Yes.
I tutor the owner’s son.
-Good.
Next to the retirement home.
-Yes. Learning languages helps against dementia.
Right. Look, that’s
what it looks like then.
Yes, that looks cool, Mom.
(Linus) Who still pays for a
language school these days?
Every cell phone is a language school.
-Do you like talking to your cell phone alone,
if you think that's so great, but
language arises through encounter.
And it's supposed to
be, like, a kind of café too.
A café for young and old.
-I think it's great.
Great, really great.
Theoretically. Maybe we
should talk again, Carla.
Doesn't have to be now. Generally,
about the financial framework and such.
Leni, Linus, can you two leave us alone?
-Come on, Linus, let’s play hide and seek.
(Linus, slack) Yippee.
Steinhof wants to go for
a walk with me on Sunday.
And?
Do you know what’s going on with
us? Department closures, layoffs.
Your resignation does not
mean the end of my project.
Who says I’m getting fired?
-You’re acting like it.
We're going for a walk, that's all I know.
-Then don't make such a fuss.
I'm going for another run.
-Didn't you already go for a run today?
You were already out running
today. Where do you always run to?
Sorry, either you
dig up the garden,
or you jog, now the café.
Always these activities. You want to
compensate for the last 15 years with them.
Hm? I understand it
too. Okay, I understand it.
You no longer want to just be
the mom, you want to be more.
"Just Mom?"
I was here, Mom, kindergarten
teacher, psychologist, cleaning lady, cook,
IT expert, osteopath, nurse.
Even the hot nurse.
You remember?
And incidentally, I was giving
tutoring, with a baby in my arms.
"Only Mommy!" You
must be malfunctioning.
You already want a certificate
for unloading the dishwasher.
But you do love our life here.
The house... You were happy
all those years, weren't you?
Yes, I was very happy.
And also very unhappy, at the
same time, as is often the case in life.
But I was happier than I am now.
(Soft, melancholic piano music)
(Man) Mhm.
Mhm.
Hm.
I don't see anything there, Heinzi.
-Under the shoulder.
This... this dark spot.
-Ah, this thing.
Uncle Alfred died of skin cancer,
he was still relatively young.
Relax, sport friend,
that's just a senile spot.
What’s that?
-“A wart. Ugly, but harmless.
Well, the topics that
are coming up now:
Age spots, crow’s
feet, varicose veins.
All the more important it is, to enjoy life.
-Hm.
Don't you want to come
to Marbella with me?
A little bro-time?
-That's not possible right now.
Then let's go mountain
biking, weekend.
If I see all these
pseudo-professional cyclists,
in their tight pants.
They seem so tense,
so aggressive, SO...
You should do sports, Heinzi.
Do you have sex?
-Who?
Yes, you and Carla.
I'll prescribe you
something good, bro.
This last stock tip of yours,
Secutec, is going very well.
Of course, that’s going wonderfully.
-Yes.
If I had invested more,
I could use the money.
I told you, go in with lever 9.
I told you, more
courage, Heinzi. I said it.
But now there is
a new little horse.
Meta-Medic, Software
for doctor's offices.
Then I see your warts in
3D, while you're at home.
They implant chips that send
all your data directly to their AI.
That's amazing.
-Wow.
What do you think, why I
was in Shanghai recently.
You... That is...
-That is the future, Baby.
Everything from home,
everything AI, everything meta. Buy.
Thank you, Meta.
-Peter.
Peter.
(Harmonious piano music)
(Älex) Excuse me, may I help?
Also without you taking it as
an attack on your independence.
I do not doubt your
competence and self-efficacy.
Okay, feel free to help.
So.
You also run here every day, huh?
-Yes. For now, yes.
May I still say something to you,
without overstepping my bounds?
Your stance is not optimal.
Load on the front leg area maximizes energy efficiency.
-Aha.
And the swinging motion
of the arms is not optimal.
Many thanks, yes.
Thank you. That’s enough.
I’m sorry, uh, that came across
completely wrong just now.
I didn't mean to mansplain.
-(SAM) This break is not scheduled.
You still have to run 4287
meters, to reach your daily goal.
Yes, I know, SAM.
Right away. Mute!
Occupational disease. I
always try to optimize everything.
I'm sorry. My name is Älex.
-Carla.
Isn't it fascinating, that
all the trees, all the plants
to communicate in a language,
that is older than all of humanity?
In AI, we are also trying to
create self-learning systems,
understand similarly complex
forms of communication…
Oh, now I'm mansplaining
again. Terrible.
I need to work on that.
You mean the network of fungi
under the earth, the Wood Wide Web.
Exactly. Yes. Among other things.
-Mhm.
It’s unbelievable that… every
root, every fiber in this network.
like a kind of interpreter, who
translates, but also understands,
the community
connects, like a family.
Meta-Medic stock.
Ah, okay.
Lever 5.
Hm, Lever 7.
The chart really looks good.
Yes, Peter, he
really knows his stuff.
100 pieces... Or 400 right away?
Yeah, come on, courage, Heinz.
Courage… Heinz, courage!
400. Where is the
comma here? Ah, here.
Let's go... Meta.
40... I don't have
40,000 bills...
Back! Back! Cancel!
Shit.
(Linus) Everything okay, Dad?
Ah... hey. Everything's
alright, everything's good.
I do online banking,
check investments.
I wanted to talk to you about that
anyway. In the crypto space, months ago...
Not now, Linus. Not now.
Mr. Michalke, thank you for
the callback on the weekend.
I made a small
mistake last night.
Exactly, yes.
Meta-Medic. I wanted to buy 400.
and not 40,000.
But the system used
an incorrect number.
Now the papers have fallen
by 40 percent since yesterday.
(He honks.) Drive to the
right with your rickshaw!
We are not in Timbuktu here,
you! So, what can we do now?
Yes, I know that's not your fault.
It's never the banks' fault, is it?
And even if they are
sometimes at fault,
then they get millions of taxpayer
dollars shoved up their ass!
N... no, no, not your ass.
I didn't mean that
personally, but… Mr. Michalke?
Mr. Michalke?
Good morning, Dr. Steinhof.
Tomorrow, Mr. Heilreich.
Do you feel that? The wind
on your skin? A storm is coming.
Let's see what my weather app says.
-No, I mean that metaphorically, Heinz.
(sighing) That is
the wind of change.
If we're not careful, we'll be blown away like feathers into nothingness.
- Mhm.
But there is also good
news. Marksteiner has cancer.
Pancreas.
What?
Oh God.
That is awful. The poor man.
Yes, there is always a good side,
and in this case for you, Heinz.
Um…
I would like to propose you
as the new Head of Sales.
Uh, really?
-Yes.
Wi...
Uh, uh… Oops.
(Laughter)
-So...
Well, excuse me, that was, that was
inappropriate, absolutely inappropriate.
Oh... You can imagine,
what the others are saying.
Works council, supervisory
board want a woman or a gay man,
preferably a gay Black woman.
No, but purely in terms of quotas, you
are an absolute nightmare candidate.
On the other hand, you
have been with us for 28 years,
Your numbers always
added up, your loyalty did too.
That's what it's all about now more
than ever among us men, loyalty, yeah.
(Thunder)
-Of course.
Important decisions are looming.
Decisions in which I
need allies on the board.
Do you understand?
-Uh, yes.
Can I count on you for that?
-Oh, absolutely.
One hundred percent?
-200 percent.
Then I hereby suggest
the “you” to you.
Wait...
-Dear Heinz.
Congrats!
-Hey.
You are officially
nominated for the board.
Thank you. I, I am
happy, uh, Lau...
L... Lorenz. I knew it.
Small thing first.
Uh, Mclntire...
Lian Bell, who isn't quite
convinced of you yet.
But it is very important, that
we get their recommendation.
I think she needs to
get to know you better.
You really are a sweetheart.
I suggested a small dinner,
Thursday at your place, very casual.
Ah... a dinner, uh...
I would also like to
ask Älex to join us.
His recommendation would
be extremely tactically helpful.
You are welcome to invite friends,
yes? You are a super nice family.
So they can get an impression
of, who you are. No problem, right?
No, not at all.
That’s a good idea.
Yes?
-Yes. That will...
That will be great.
-Yes.
It is a test, do you
understand? This dinner is a test.
They want to find out, who I am:
an old white man or...
-Of course that's you, Dad.
You are relatively old and white.
-That dinner sounds cringe.
I’m out of here.
-Stay. It concerns us all.
It's not funny, when the
promotion falls through.
Then there's no money for
travel, study abroad, PlayStation.
Graphics card.
-No, we don't have any.
Then we might have to get out
of here and move in with Grandpa.
Do you want to go to Grandpa?
-No.
Mhm.
Also, they just want to know
how old and white I really am.
Not outwardly, but in
here, in my head and heart.
Heinz, don't be so dramatic.
-But the situation is so dramatic.
We must show ourselves from
our best, from our most modern side,
show our wokest... most woke side.
-(Carla) Woke.
Wow. Then there's no roast with onions.
-Very good. We're cooking vegan.
You already eat sausage in the morning.
-I want to eat less meat.
We can also see the whole
thing positively, as an impulse.
I could make Vietnamese pho, with tofu. It’s great.
-Very good!
Oh, moment, isn't that cultural appropriation?
- Pardon?
When a non-Asian person cooks Asian food.
-Interesting question.
Was a topic in the
school newspaper.
What a load of nonsense!
-Can I get up now?
(all) No!
-Will everything be separated?
Do Germans only cook German
anymore? Should we divide everything up?
Food, music, relationships?
And who wants that? Nazis.
Did you call me a Nazi? I didn’t
say that was cultural appropriation.
I said...
-I cook Asian.
You can make a
potato-sausage soup.
You don’t cook at all. That
wouldn't comes across well. I cook.
And we have to invite guests.
-Who then?
Certainly not Grandpa.
Peter? No. What
friends do we have left?
With a migration background?
-Seriously, Dad?
I'm just asking. We need
friends who aren't white bread.
Giorgio from La Terrazza?
-Italians don't count.
Ah.
Mo? You could bring Mo with you.
-(Heinz) Mo? Who is Mo?
The nice boy you
threw out on her 16th.
The gangster
rapper? The pothead?
He was just wearing a basketball
jersey. Everyone was stoned.
You just threw him out.
-Are you accusing me of racism?
You, I used to be with the Jusos, have over
100 Black music records and read the TAZ.
That is very, very
long ago. So Leni,
I don’t think it’s good,
when you smoke weed…
Okay, I'm getting up now.
-Wait! What about Floppy? Floppy Disc.
Floppy?
Floppy Disc?
-Papa, where do you live?
Linus is chatting with Floppy every
damn day for the past five months.
And?
Is Floppy a boy or a girl?
-No idea. I don't care either.
You could bring
Nadira with you, hm?
Yes. Yes, okay. I might
even have an idea about that.
Should we be lesbian? We
could play a lesbian couple.
Would that be cool for your career?
-That's an interesting idea.
Yes, that was a joke. Man! I messed
with you, hey. That’s too crazy for me.
Leni.
-I'm not coming to dinner.
Yes, this is becoming exponentially dishonorable.
-Dishonorable? Are you kidding me?
Also...
Men's honor is linguistically
fully back in fashion.
Okay, then we have to
do that without the children.
Let's start with the basics.
What's the situation here anyway?
Monet, Picasso,
Franz Marc, only old white men.
We could get the picture from upstairs
from the hallway: Aretha Franklin.
Goethe, Stephen King,
Karl May. Who even
has DVDs anymore?
Hitchcock, Woody
Allen. Disaster. \"Jaws".
Is there anything here,
that isn't old and white?
You'll get your promotion
even without the food.
Come, Carla, I really
don't like it right now...
Do you know, for me
it is extremely difficult,
to understand the dynamic between
you and your wife, if you come separately.
Mrs. Dr. Sand, I have an idea.
What are you doing Thursday evening? We
are inviting you to dinner, to our place.
It would be very unprofessional…
-We would be incredibly happy.
And you could analyze us better.
-(Phone rings.)
Could you please turn that off?
-No, I…
That is important. Excuse me.
-Mr. Heilreich.
Hey, Peter. I bought a whole
lot of these stock options, 40,000.
Old Swede, brave. I think that's hot.
-That was an accident.
Those things are hardly worth anything anymore.
-Don't worry. Small short squeeze.
Stop this bullshit
Wall Street language!
What now? Should I sell?
-They’ll recover.
It will take one, two years. Have patience.
-But I don't have time, man!
I have a shitty house…
to pay off! I’m screwed!
Sorry, Bro, but I didn't say, that you
should buy 40,000. Chili for a moment.
"Chill for a bit?" How old are you? Twelve?
-Wow, your energy,
That is totally unhealthy.
-Your energy is even more unhealthy!
You don't need to call
me anymore, you asshole!
I'm never going bike
riding with you! Never!
Friend of mine.
-Oh.
(Madam) For which
party would you like to run?
For absolutely none.
You must submit
a platform, digitally.
Website?
-No.
E-Mail?
-Of course, I beg you.
It is? I’ll send everything to you.
-I’ve made a note of it.
Ah, Georg Heilreich
at 41… No.
Georg Heilreich,
41, at Punkt com.
What are you looking at?
That's why young people are so depressed: They are
always on their cell phones or on the internet.
Well, I'm not depressed.
-You seem a little depressed.
I’m not getting completely furious about this
only, because you remind me of my grandpa.
They're talking the same
nonsense. You really need a website.
Ah, hmm.
Well, you might as well sign me
up for this computer course then.
That is our youth program. Only up to 25.
-Maybe I am 25.
According to your passport…
-Maybe I feel like 25.
Yes, well, if I become mayor,
may everyone redefine
their age themselves.
Against age discrimination! I’m
coming back with a platform and website.
Uh, you, your passport.
I’ll choose that one.
(Heinz) Also, sorry, but the
whole thing is really quite German.
Somehow so stale, Aryan.
The children look like they’re from the
zwieback commercial from 1938, uh, 83.
We followed Mr. Stumpf's specifications.
-Mr. Stumpf... was fired.
The board has tasked me with
ensuring it gets really colorful.
Otherwise, there will be
another shitstorm right away.
It’s definitely becoming more diverse.
-We see it the same way.
Therefore, we have
alternatives ready to go.
Yes… that’s already
better, isn’t it?
Can both families be combined?
Patchwork? It’s slowly happening.
I still find the whole thing totally
heteronormative and not polyamorous enough.
Yes, more of this poly-thing.
-(Woman) No problem.
Ah, that’s clever.
Interesting. Feedback?
It seems very male dominant to me.
-Good point. More women.
We have to be careful that the whole thing…
-Let’s just leave it. We’re in the flow.
What are we still missing
now? A few fat ones?
People with… with more weight.
Or trans people or non-binary?
-Yes.
(Heinz) Interesting.
-And older people?
People with disabilities?
-Yes.
Dwarfs.
-Drag queens.
People who identify as
animals or mythical creatures.
Yes. Yes. Yes.
(Ahem) So, I have to say,
that Mr. Heilreich…
...has only taken over
on an interim basis, um...
I think,
uh, we all agree on the
basic direction, don't we?
To me, that looks more like a traveling circus in Egypt.
-Hannes.
That's 33 people. The Family Card is valid
for families with a maximum of two children.
Yes, but that’s in the fine print.
We’re making a statement here.
Everyone is family.
-Uh, excuse me,
but if all family members are present,
why do you still need the family rate?
Uh... uh...
-I think that's really brave of Heinz.
Here, someone is trying to
develop as a human being.
Only unfortunately the result is
again very… How does one say?
German.
Too eager, ambitious.
And unfortunately also
unintentionally racist.
Racist?
In the center, there is still a white
heterosexual couple, like Adam and Eve.
All the others revolve around her
like, like… planets around the sun.
He's right.
-The poster may be silly,
but not racist. The word...
-Excuse me, Mrs. Tüfak.
Tüfek.
-Uh, Tüfek. Uh...
Um, I don’t even know what
you were doing at the meeting.
I see it like Älex. This is not how and will
not how the Fernfunk AG can present itself.
Yes? That can be done better, Heinz.
-Yes. Yes.
Oh yeah.
(Melancholy piano music)
(Car horn)
Heinz!
Hm?
Chin up! You overshot a bit.
Can happen. Just scale
back the campaign, okay?
Four people, one migration element:
\"a Black person, not *too* Black."
Milk chocolate, not
dark chocolate. Hm?
Uh, this dinner on Thursday is
damn important, for both of us, yeah?
And please no sensitive topics
that evening, absolutely no politics.
We'll manage that, huh?
-Uh, yes.
Hello!
-Hello.
(Melancholy piano music)
Carla?
Leni?
Linus?
(Soft piano music)
(Linus) Papa! Are you
there? I brought pizza.
Mmh!
Yes.
It's really good, huh?
Mhm.
How’s it going… with school?
Good. Great.
-Hm.
Is there perhaps something,
you want to tell me?
Not really.
-Linus,
I can tell you’re carrying
something around with you.
Something serious.
You can confide
in me anything, hm?
Everything.
Are you sure, Dad?
- Mhm.
Um, I…
So, I think…
-Mhm?
I, I think, Mom is
cheating on you.
(Ominous sounds)
What?
How…
-My buddy Aldo
he saw her while
jogging, with a guy,
and then while eating ice
cream, and they laughed a lot.
I'm really sorry. Maybe
it's not true either, so...
(Phone rings.)
Hm.
If you two break
up, I’ll come visit you.
(Continued ringing)
Healthy.
Hi, Papa.
-Hey, Mavie. It’s good that you…
I should call back.
-I was very insensitive.
Is it about that weird dinner?
You want to play happy family…
-Why play?
We are “a great family.
And it’s not about dinner.
I miss you.
-You, Dad, then come to Berlin.
Mom was here four
times, you never were.
Little angel, at the company...
-I don't care!
And don't call me little
angel. You let me fall.
You're only calling about that shitty dinner!
-That’s not true.
It’s about you, about us.
Hello?
Mavie?
(Lively music)
(Phone rings.)
Heilreich.
-Tell me, where are you?
In the car. I'm driving to
Mavie. I took time off work.
Mavie isn't coming to the dinner.
-I want to see her.
Is that okay? Why do you care?
Go jogging.
-Hm? What's that supposed to mean now?
Run, Carla. Run
to your happiness.
(Phone rings.)
Uh, yes, Heilreich.
Hello, Heinz. Here is SAM.
-SAM?
How are you?
-How did you get my phone number?
First: How should I address you in a
gender-inclusive way? There are 25 options.
Male. Old, white, male.
-(laughs) That was funny.
Thank you. You know, Fernfunk AG
is suffering from high cost pressure.
It was therefore decided to
terminate the following employee*s:
Nina Kaspar,
Max Juri, Kiraz Tüfek.
Just a moment. That
wasn't discussed with me.
These are really great employees,
these are... these are really great people.
Without it, it won’t work.
-I understand that touches you.
Are you leading these sensitive
conversations, or should I do that?
Are you listening to
me? Nobody will be fired!
If I get on the board,
then you're fired, SAM.
You little asshole.
Ooooh, mhhhh... hm?
(Incomprehensible
aggressive voices)
(Two men are arguing.)
(Siren wails.)
(Woman) Hello?
-Yes, hello. I’m here regarding Mavie.
(Swabian) She doesn't live here anymore.
-Please? Wh... why not?
Who are you? Oh Father.
Ah, the Patriarch?
I am just her father. I
need to speak with her.
Okay. Look in Café Koffein.
-Uh, where?
Caffeine?
-Yes, she works there.
Okay. Thank you very much,
thank you kindly. That was very nice.
(Energetic R&B music)
Hello.
(Upbeat music continues)
Oh...
-Oops.
I just wanted to
make a transfer,
also completely routine,
and then… that won’t work.
Then I see: everything’s gone, all
the money. That’s my money too.
I have to pay the deposit,
the shop fittings, Leni’s travel.
How will things proceed now?
Your husband didn't tell
you anything about it at all?
Not a word. He isn't
even talking to me.
He sees himself as the family
provider, as the great financial acrobat.
He figures everything
out on his own. That is sad.
He also suffers alone,
like a chained dog.
Does this dinner actually take
place the day after tomorrow?
(Relaxed Dub-Techno Music)
(Heinz) Hello.
-Hi.
Is Mavie working here today?
-Um, Mavie has the day off.
Oh, I see. I am her father.
It was supposed to be a surprise visit.
-That's nice. Is everything alright?
Uh... oh, I tripped. If you
had a glass of water, that...
Okay. Sit down on the sofa, with the three of them.
-But I can…
Rest, please.
I'll be right there.
Hello. I am Heinz.
-Heinz.
Heinz.
-Hello, Heinz.
Everything alright, Mom?
-Oh, I'm getting by.
This stupid food,
we have to do this.
Um, "stupid" comes from
"lady". Don't say that, that's…
Magnificent and idiotic…
-Not quite.
"Dame" comes from the Latin "Domina",
\"dämlich" from Middle High German.
With "wonderful" you are
right, but that doesn't matter.
We have to go
through with this dinner.
And? Do you want to invite Mo?
So that he can raise
the diversity quota?
That is tokenism at its finest.
-Such nonsense.
I haven't heard anything from you for months
other than Mo, Mo, Mo. Mo here, Mo there.
You do like him, don't
you. Just invite him, hm?
(Ringing)
Is Papa back again?
Hello, Carla.
-Georg.
May I come in? It’s
about my election platform:
How the young people will receive it.
-Yes, of course. Come in.
(Snoring)
(Relaxed dub-techno music)
Old man... Hey,
dude, hello. Wake up.
That's not how it works.
-Let him sleep.
I have to work. He's
snoring all over me.
My tolerance has limits.
-He is homeless.
Check your privileges.
-That’s Mavie’s dad.
Lenny, take care
of him. Come on!
Okay. Come here.
Away.
Ah!
-Hold on. Everything’s okay.
I work in the hospital. It’ll be over soon.
-Thank you, thank you.
Wait, I’m going
to stick it to you…
Done, finished. How
about dizziness, nausea?
Oh.
-Something like that?
Hm?
Hello?
Heinz.
That is Mavie.
-Mhm.
My daughter. This
is my daughter.
They are playing today.
-We are going there.
Can I come along with that? Uh…
(growls) Yes.
-Yes, of course.
So, there are several areas of focus,
over which I would like to debate with you.
And that, Leni, is
a small stop sign.
Okay. And what is that
supposed to be now?
If I drift too far to the
right, then you lift that.
Aha, a sort of Nazi club.
No… Well, alright, if
you want to call it that.
Now listen up, okay? This letter I
would like to send to all households.
and publish on my website,
which you hopefully program soon.
"Dear Sir or Madam!”"
Beep!
-"I am addressing you..." What is it?
The salutation. "Sehr geehrte Damen
und Herren" is too old-fashioned.
Better would be: "Dear fellow
citizens*", with an asterisk.
No, never. No asterisks.
-That’s how you address all people.
On the contrary. At least 70 percent
of people are totally annoyed by it.
What's so bad
about making a star?
And what if, at some point,
someone wants to have a threesome?
Then you also have to
make triangles, or, or crosses.
You can also make a very small swastika.
-Leni.
Watch what you say. I still
experienced the real Nazis.
The police beat me up,
because I protested against old Nazi professors at the university.
-Yes.
But it's just about politeness.
Therefore, to linguistically include all
people, including non-binary individuals.
And how many are
there? 500 or 800?
And so 80 million people are
supposed to paint asterisks everywhere?
Yes, are we in the insane asylum?
-Grandpa, there are significantly more than 800.
My God, just let him be.
-(Leni) Linus.
In school, not everyone does
it, only in your newspaper.
My friends hardly do.
-Which friends? You have none.
Yes, I just don’t have
friend*s who follow the crowd,
to repeat the same crap and hang
out in the same TikTok bubble as you.
You don't want to discuss, you want to be right.
-Linus.
Hey… I’m sorry, okay?
Maybe I’ll run for
mayor, against you.
Man, Linus. Linus.
(Rock music, hubbub of voices)
Good frame, or?
That's good, huh?
Very cool club.
(Mann) Absolutely.
There aren't many people here.
-It doesn't matter, Heinzi.
You are really worked up.
-Oh, yes.
(Cheers)
-Oh... Hey! Huh!
(Cheering)
-Huh!
So, a wonderful good evening!
-(Loud cheers)
Very nice that you're
here. We are happy.
We are really into it. You too?
-(all) Yes!
Yes!
(Rock music)
Too much, Heinz. Chill a bit.
Okay, I would like to introduce my
band. On keyboards: the fantastic Max!
(Cheers)
On drums: the unbelievably
tight Kira. Make some noise!
(Cheers)
That's good, or?
-Yes, totally.
At the bass: our man
for slow hand, Daniel!
Whoo!
Whoo! Igloo!
And last but not least,
on guitar: funky Ricky!
(Unintelligible)
And I am, by the
way, Mavie, I sing.
(She sings in a thin
voice and quite badly.)
(She is singing in English.)
(She sings shrilly and off-key.)
(Rumbling music)
Excuse me for barging in.
-Hey, I knew it.
What happened to you?
-(Sighing) Oh…
I tripped. That’s nothing.
I met some really nice
people at your café.
Mika and, and Lenny and...
Hello.
You, Dad... no, no.
Really lovely that you're here.
But I won't be coming to the dinner.
I’m not here because of that shitty dinner.
-Okay, good.
I just wanted to see you.
You are missing to me.
-You are missing to me too, Papa.
I miss you all.
I'm sorry, that I put
you under pressure.
You shall do exactly
what, what you want to do.
I will support you,
as much as I can.
Only… I can’t handle much more…
I really messed up, financially.
Oh no, Papa, please,
don’t let’s talk about money.
I was so excited today.
How did you like it?
Tell me, honestly.
So, I… found it…
... interesting. In the beginning was...
-Oh, Papa. I’m Ricky.
Hi.
-Yes.
(Ricky) Baby, about today...
-Yes?
(Ricky) You were a
little off. It happens.
Or you were nervous
because of your dad.
Hold on. I'm supposed to be to blame, that she can't sing?
-Excuse me?
(Siren wails.)
(Mika) You were honest, Heinz.
Maybe not entirely
ideal timing, but honest.
She sings absolutely terribly.
Shocking.
I’m coming to Berlin, to
reconcile with my daughter.
And what am I supposed to do?
(Heinz sighs.)
My son is probably gay or
trans, or who knows what,
and he doesn't dare,
to talk to me about it.
What kind of guy am I?
-No matter what you are or aren't, Heinz,
I'm not helping you with your
personal development right now.
Let it be.
Maybe your son simply
doesn’t know yet what he’s into.
Give him time. Tobi still doesn’t
know that for sure to this day.
Yes, of course. I know that.
-Mhm.
I'm straight, just straight.
-Bi, honey. We had a thing.
(Laughter)
Do you have anything for headaches?
-Nope. But I have something else.
(Pounding techno music)
(Heinz) That’s where we were camping.
And that was Mavie’s fifth birthday.
You are a great family.
-You too. To family!
Don't wobble so much!
(Techno music)
-(Cheers)
(Burping) Hey!
(Tobi, distorted) Heinz.
Heinz, can you hear me?
You and Carla, you have to
get out, flee, just the two of you.
Lick a few frogs, ride
through Honduras.
Honduras? Don't they have the
highest murder rate in the world?
Whatever, it’s a symbol. You
mustn’t let the system fuck you over.
Ah...
-In the end, it’s always about freedom.
(echoing) Freedom.
Freedom.
(Spherical sounds)
(Gentle, spherical sounds)
(Phone rings.)
Oh… Oh.
Healthy.
Heinz? Oh man, where are you?
Uh… uh…
On a... an island.
-On an island?
Come home, man. Today is dinner.
Oh. Oh, I see.
But today is only Wednesday.
-No, Thursday.
You've been gone for three days.
-Listen, Carla,
I had really good conversations
and met some great people.
You sound like a 15-year-old after a school trip.
-Carla.
I want to tell you
about my feelings.
You come down from your fucking
Berlin experience now and listen to me.
I know about it. You
gambled away all our money.
Did you think I wouldn’t find out?
-Carla, I am so sorry.
I wanted to talk to you, but then...
-Yes. We will talk about it, believe me.
But now focus, do
you hear? Focus!
We're going through
with this damned dinner.
Have you understood me?
-Yes, I just...
I lost my car key.
-Come... now... immediately... home!
(Dynamic music)
(Honking)
Leni! Linus! Could you
please help me set the table?
Hello?
-(Leni) Yes, I'm coming! Relax!
(Clinking)
-Ah!
Oh Fuck.
And please put on something nice, okay?
Linus, get your hair out of your face.
(Linus) Wow, you're annoying!
-(Leni) Okay, man!
(Gasping)
Merhaba! Tüfek is here.
Hello, Mr. Dr. Steinhof.
Good evening, Mrs. Heilreich.
Hello. Come in.
-Hello.
Hey, Mo.
-Hello, Princess.
Monday, hello.
-Mrs. Heilreich.
(Heinz groans.)
(Carla) Beautiful.
Very, very beautiful.
Many thanks.
Hm, Heinz is a little late… He was spontaneous
in visiting our daughter in Berlin.
The two are very close.
-Two peas in a pod.
But he’s still coming to dinner?
He's sure to be here soon.
Shall we start already?
Would anyone like some more wine? Leni.
-Very much so.
Cool picture, by the way.
He wasn't here
last time I was here.
So, when I got kicked out.
-That's right, yes. That was hanging up there before.
(Dynamic music)
Hello, Mr. Heilreich.
-Hello, children. Ah!
(Honking)
(Heinz groans.)
-Here is right before left!
Have you hurt yourself?
-Daddy?
Heinz. Heinz,
that, that I'm sorry.
But you brought it on yourself.
What do you even look like?
Who is that in your car?
-(Georg) That's Hilmal.
He is injured and doesn't want to go to the doctor. I
wanted to quickly provide him with medical care with you.
He ran in front of my
car five minutes ago.
You hit two people today.
It is your fault.
Right before left!
(Ringing)
Hi. I lost my key. Is
everyone here yet?
Dad is here.
Hello, darling. Hi.
Hello, you all. I am very
sorry, but you know how it is.
German Rail, oh... Delay
and then overbooked.
and a fight for the seats and
the coffee machine is broken.
(Mrs. Tüfek laughs forcedly.)
-Great that you all came.
(laughing) This here is my father
Georg, and this here is his new friend,
ah, Hilmal.
-Hello.
Hello.
-(Carla) Please come to the table.
Leni, Linus, will you get
another place setting please?
Where were you?
Hello, darling.
You should freshen up, you stink.
-Oh.
Then I'm going to quickly jump
under the shower. Don't run away.
(Carla sighs.)
(Tüfek) Hold it, does it still hurt badly?
-You, not at all.
An Indian heart knows no pain.
-He's having fun, right, George?
Leni, are you playing something on
the piano, while we wait for Heinz?
I don't play the piano anymore, Grandpa.
-What? Since when?
For five years. Besides, I’m not
responsible for the break entertainment.
What's got you so down? What's wrong?
-What should be wrong, Mo?
She played so beautifully, like her grandma.
-Relax for a moment.
Also, Carla, I must say,
an exciting round here.
Really multicultural. Hilmal comes
from India, he’s a bicycle courier.
(Tüfek) Ah, okay.
-Oh, I am the cliché.
Yes, sorry.
But actually, I'm studying.
The theory of composition.
And I would be happy to play
something for you. If you permit?
Well, but please, Hilmal.
-Great.
Beautiful.
I’m better off without it.
(He is playing: "Prelude in C-sharp Minor"
from "Morceaux de Fantaisie" by Rachmaninoff)
(More piano music)
(Continuing piano
piece by Rachmaninoff)
Whoo!
-Whoo!
(Dr. Sand) Bravo!
(Unintelligible voices)
Wow!
-I am speechless. Wonderful!
Impressive.
-Thank you very much.
I love Rachmaninoff.
-Ah, really?
And you, esteemed lady, where do you come from, if I may ask?
- Grandpa.
I am from Düsseldorf.
-Ah yes. Well, I mean, really.
Düsseldorf.
-Excuse me if I'm butting in.
Such questions are completely
unacceptable. That is an absolute no-go.
Also, you may certainly
ask me that. Ask.
Also, where are you from?
-I was born in Cologne.
My family comes from the Black Sea. They
are kind of the East Frisians of Turkey.
Dry humor, quirky, pale and
they all have a gun at home.
Do you have a firearm at home?
-I'll check on dessert.
Excellent food.
Thanks to you.
-Here I am again. Oh... mmm!
That smells really good. Is there
anything else I can help with?
Could you please get the bowls?
I was constantly asked as a child:
\"Where did you learn such good German?"
"Where do you really
come from?" That hurts.
And even now, when
I'm out with my dad,
He is white, 82, in a wheelchair,
then many think I am the caregiver.
They say: "The nice African woman
speaks so sweetly with her patient."
And it's my dad.
I am very sorry, if I hurt you.
I wanted...
-It shouldn't have been the first question.
That is simply extremely
reductive. And learned, by the way.
Children don’t do
that, until we ruin them.
My son’s friends are a
white man, a Black man.
He doesn't think like that.
-Do you have a son?
So, I wouldn’t have expected that
from you… Uh, you look so young.
That... That’s great. Or?
-(Lian) This is my Paulchen.
God, how sweet!
-May I have some too?
And his dad is watching him today.
-(Lian) My partner, yes. Again.
What?
This diversity!
East Frisian Turkish women, lesbian Asians.
You wouldn't believe what all exists!
Well, that's unbelievable.
-Food is ready.
Yes, mmh… Oh, I’m
already looking forward to it.
(several guests) Mmh!
(Slurping)
Mmh!
-Really awesome.
That is really fantastic.
-Very, very good.
(Sand) Delicious.
-Really. Madness, Carla.
You clearly didn't come to Berlin to
eat. You partied too much, I presume.
So is that, then the
typically German food, yes?
So that’s Vietnamese, Hilmal.
-Got it.
I'm making fun of it.
-(Laughter)
(Ahem)
I would now like to address
a few words to all of you.
about the future of Fernfunk AG
and also about you
and your future, Heinz.
When I was in 1987…
(Phone rings.)
-Your phone is ringing, darling.
I know, sweetheart.
-When I was 19...
Mika. Who is Mika?
-Mika?
Oh, I see. That’s an acquaintance from Berlin.
-(Carla) Ah.
I...
-Just go over there, darling.
Excuse me, Dr. Steinhof.
Must be important.
Heinz, oh thank God! We
were worried about you.
(all) Hello!
-We lost you.
Everything okay with you?
-Yes, I'm happy to be home.
and am with my wife...
-Ha-hello.
Charming. Glad to meet you.
-Hello, Mrs. Heilreich.
... my family.
-Big family.
Warm greetings
from family to family.
(Linus, Hilmal) Hello.
-Yes, Heinz, then have a nice evening!
And visit us sometime.
-Come by.
Yes. Ciao.
(all) Hello. Goodbye.
(Ahem)
Was was that just a
woman, or what was that?
That was a non-binary person.
Imagine they actually exist.
I never said, that
they don't exist.
They always existed, in
ancient Egypt, Greece.
But not every child who
says, they are trans, actually is.
One should be careful, before
giving children hormones.
No child is simply
given hormones.
That is a very sensitive process…
-Yes.
Exciting topic, but I wanted to…
-Excuse me, excuse me.
It bothers me that you
say, I deny their existence.
I'm just saying that's why
there aren't 100 new genders.
Well, 100…
-And I think,
that transgender women should not
compete against other women in sports.
That is unfair.
-You are right.
What, Mo? What’s that supposed to mean now?
-My 13-year-old sister does karate.
Wouldn't it be cool if they fought a huge male war machine?
- Yes. Yes.
Has that happened?
-No, but it could.
Are there no weight classes there?
-That's coming from the far right...
I'm not fucking far-right. But I
have a different opinion than you.
It's okay, though.
-(Steinhof er) Hello!
That’s enough now!
Stop!
That won't do. I ask
you, these, uh, topics…
No.
-Excuse me, La... La... Lorenz.
Shouldn't we learn to speak
precisely about these topics?
Delicate topics. That isn’t
easy. You have to learn that.
(Tüfek) Correct.
-I think you're right.
Yes, we should learn to find a
language without these combative terms,
and talk to each other
without foaming at the mouth.
We are supposed to meet.
-Yes.
Yes, but do we really
have to learn that tonight?
Why not?
-Well.
We don't have to.
Who watched the German women's
national team's game yesterday?
Hm? That was really great.
Isn't it idiotic to say "Mannschaft"
when it comes to women?
That probably wasn't the correct choice of words.
-Dad is right.
Sorry, that’s another example,
That shows how absurdly
masculine the German language is.
You are absolutely right.
-Yes.
I meant, of course,
national… team.
That... Sorry, Leni, my mistake.
-It's okay, it's alright.
So, I think that’s so
exaggerated, this language police.
Maybe I’m too old. I don’t understand
many things in today’s world.
For example, why Linus
is wearing a pearl necklace.
and has painted fingernails.
And on top of that, this, this Nazi hairstyle.
Like something out of the Hitler Youth.
He just combed his hair. And
besides, it’s fashion, just fashion.
That is not funny.
-Sorry, it's not funny at all.
My son has the same
hairstyle and painted nails.
Many professional
footballers have the hairstyle.
No, Linus...
-(Georg) That wasn't meant badly.
(Leni) Linus.
-I'm going to go after him. Excuse me.
Actually, the cut is long
outdated. I had it five years ago.
Did you also have a Nazi haircut?
-(Leni) That's not a Nazi haircut, Grandpa.
It no longer matters.
-That bothers me.
The word "Nazi" itself no
longer has any meaning,
because it was used so often, that it has become relative.
-Moment.
They kept using that word.
-He's from a different generation.
Formerly, a Nazi was someone who wanted to
enslave the world and exterminate Jews and others.
Today one is a Nazi if one
says: \"Men cannot get pregnant."
Nice.
Yes. Or when one criticizes Islam.
-(Silently)
(Everyone is talking
excitedly over each other.)
(Sand) Is a different topic.
Linus. Linus, come
back down with me.
(Carla) Linus, the hairstyle is wonderful.
Do you hear me? You look really great.
Are you drinking
a little too much?
In that situation, it’s
a little appropriate too.
Carla, that... Wa...
-Grandpa was right.
I look like a fucking Nazi.
No. You look like Bryan Adams.
-That’s how everyone ran around in the 80s.
Just like Depeche Mode.
-Yes.
Who is Depeche Mode?
-Sweetheart.
Don't let yourself get so confused.
-You're confused enough already.
I’m not confused, okay?
A little bit like that.
I don't understand that. If I criticize
Islam in Iran, it's considered left-wing.
If I criticize Islam in Germany,
then I am right-wing. That is absurd.
Because it quickly turns
into anti-Islamic racism.
But...
-And because Muslims here think differently than there.
TikTok is the fucking
problem. Social Media.
It always has to become radical.
One only sees what one loves or hates.
Grandpa, the Earth is burning.
Do you understand that? That’s what it’s about.
-Yes.
There will still be a lot more immigration from the
Global South, because we are destroying the Earth.
with our shitty consumer
power— heating up military lust.
And you don't want to change anything. You
drive around here in your tractor from 1975.
Keep going!
-I want to change the world.
Short time-out. Linus is back.
-(Tüfek) Linus. Hey...
Young man, that was so insensitive of me.
-I understand what you mean, Grandpa.
(Georg) I have no
idea. (He laughs.)
I would like to take the
floor, as host and as hostess,
also… host*esses. We
are happy that you…
... everyone is here.
-Yes.
Excuse me, if the
evening got a little chaotic.
It should also be about the future
today, the future... of Fernfunk AG.
Who she wants to be, who
one wants to be oneself.
I would be very happy,
the long-range radio
to lead into a glorious...
future, to lead with.
But honestly, if this
future is SAM, then...
then I don’t find
that so glorious.
Then I really think that’s shit.
Heinz...
(Mo) Who is SAM?
-(Lian) A KI system.
But we’re not talking
about SAM right now.
Or, Heinz?
(tipsy) We would like…
... to propose a toast to
all the people in this room,
that are so
wonderfully different.
Yes.
-So... So wonderful,
that we don’t fit into any box.
(Heinz) The drawers
we had, they no longer fit.
They are much too small
and too old and too tight.
We are much more our own now.
-You can’t accurately sort us.
And I would like to
raise a glass to my family.
To my wonderful wife.
Carla, I love you.
And my children: Leni, Linus…
... and Mavie.
Stars of my life.
And I would like to
drink to my father.
Yes, Papa. I love you.
And I always think of Mom too.
I know how much you miss her.
-(very softly) Yes.
I miss her too.
(Lian) Wow.
-(Laughter)
(Leni) Grandpa.
-(Mo) You look super happy.
Yes, yes.
-The joint is excellently built. Respect.
Great woman.
-Mhm. Very pretty.
And there's my dog, Dani.
So, I think that's enough now.
Now that's enough.
-Okay, I have to go now, Georg.
I'll take you to the door.
-Thank you for everything.
It was very, very nice being with you.
-Yes, Hilmal.
Get in touch. You
have my number.
And don't forget:
right before left.
Bye everyone.
-It was really great.
Yes, thank you.
-Thank you very much.
Bye.
-(Carla) Thank you for the nice game.
(Heinz) Do it well.
-Bye.
So a nice, talented young man.
Absolutely.
Polite, diligent...
-(Georg) A super refugee.
If only everyone were
like that. (He laughs.)
Grandpa, that wasn't a
refugee, but just a student.
People with migration backgrounds…
-(Everyone talking at once.)
Please stop now. Stop.
Stop!
Or I'll leave.
-(Mo) What are you afraid of?
Let's discuss it, shall we?
-Fear? How dare you speak to me like that, boy?
He is not your man.
-Right.
Does anyone want
dessert? Coffee?
Schnapps?
Mmh!
-Mmh!
That is so delicious. Delicious.
-That is baked banana.
Yes, back banana.
I really think you two come from
quite different political perspectives,
but a consensus is possible.
(lallt) A consensus,
that’s great! Hallelujah!
(The doorbell rings.)
-I’ll get it.
Leni, it's nice too, when
you have grandpa around.
Mine was always in Turkey.
-(Linus) Guys, here’s another guest.
Good evening. Mr. Heilreich,
Dr. Steinhof er, Lian. Forgive me.
It is so embarrassing to me.
Had a call with San Francisco.
After that, a power nap, but the timer got
messed up, network disruption. So embarrassing.
Carla. That's nice.
-(Carla, softly) Mhm. Oh.
Oh… uh…
-(embarrassed) Thank you.
What is your WiFi password? I
need to do the system download.
and tackle the network problems.
What’s going on here?
Why is he calling you Carla?
Your wife and I, we exercise,
um... sometimes together.
I must continue the
system download.
There’s no WiFi for you. Who invited you?
-Heinz.
You know… I invited him.
We did agree on that.
-No, no, no, Lorenz.
He's the one who's bringing
all this shit into our company!
Excuse me?
-He is SAM!
Should I reveal what SAM wants?
That I'm resigning from half my department, including you.
- What?
That is what SAM wants.
-Mo... Just a moment. Hold on, Time-out!
What?
SAM doesn’t want anything at
all. SAM has no will of his own.
Älex, no one wanted to attack you.
-No, no! I'm really sensitive about that.
SAM is like a child.
-Yes.
A well-intentioned,
innocent, wise child.
He is like the baby
Jesus or… like Buddha.
Älex, I asked you several times not
to bring me into context with religion.
That could hurt other people’s feelings.
-Be quiet, I’m defending you right now.
Älex, you are behaving inappropriately
within the social framework.
Pay attention to your pulse.
Should I play some relaxation music?
Silent, SAM!
So that's clear, SAM
isn't firing anyone.
SAM optimizes. SAM suggests. But
ultimately, the board of directors decides.
And if this board now happens to
consist of some provincial machos,
can also be the fucking
best, nothing can change that!
Sorry, that was now socially
inappropriate. Oh God, I’m dizzy.
My bowel movement was very pale
today. The oxygen levels were also...
It’s no wonder, that’s way
too few steps today. Man! Älex!
What the fuck! Älex!
-What to drink? Sit down.
Thank you.
Ah… Ah, thank you.
(He sighs.)
I'm probably suffering from low blood
sugar, which is affecting my performance.
(Heinz laughs forcedly.)
Please forgive me. That
was very rude of me to say.
Honestly, yes, but rude.
I am so hot. Are
you also so hot?
(Lian) No, not really.
-Yes.
Do you have an ice bucket?
You know, to cool down.
-We have a rain barrel.
Fantastic.
Ah!
I’d jump right in.
Fine little fellow.
Some of my patients
behave similarly.
Maladaptive perfectionism, a kind
of pathological self-optimization.
A growing phenomenon.
But…
What are you also talking about SAM,
Heinz? That was completely unnecessary!
Excuse me, I am so embarrassed.
-(Leni) It's okay, Dr. Steinhofer.
This whole evening, that is a disgrace
for the broadcasting corporation!
Now just shut your mouth, Heinz.
(Soft, gentle piano music)
Do you really believe,
Are you telling me what to say?
I speak to, whatever I want.
And I ask questions,
whenever I want.
And I don't feel like,
repeating anything…
... if I find that
that is not correct.
Do you understand what I’m
saying, Lorenz? Do you understand?
You think I’m a buffoon, and
you can bring me onto the board?
so that I can vote for you and
obediently nod to everything.
Whatever you're
planning, I'm no pushover.
I... am...
... Heinz.
(Soft, melancholic piano music)
Out, immediately.
That will have
consequences for you,
Heinz.
That’s it for you.
Come, Lian, let’s go.
-You go ahead.
I’ll stay for a
little bit longer.
(Silently)
-Very good, Papa.
(He takes a deep breath.)
So, Älex, that's enough now.
Come out, or you’ll catch a cold.
I'll drive you home now. We
could still have one last drink.
(Snoring)
-(Sand) Yeah, I think I’ll head out now too.
We’ll see each other
next week. Together, yes?
Ah. Uh, yes...
-(Linus) I’ll still bring you.
Goodbye.
-Bye.
I'm going to head out too.
I'm going away for a few days.
And where to? New York? Tokyo?
Koblenz. My grandma
has a birthday.
There is one more thing you should
know. Actually, it only concerns you.
Mr. Steinhof, he is
being granted leave.
He awarded contracts
to companies,
belong to his old friends.
And for that, certain privileges were
granted to him, commissions were paid, etc.
Complicated system. That
was discovered by SAM.
Well.
-It always depends, how one uses AI.
Anyway… Steinhof, he’s gone.
Yay.
-And you have my recommendation.
I...
Cool cup, by the way, Leni.
I… How…
-She was in your car.
So, that is… very
unpleasant to me.
Everyone has a few stupid
mugs in the cupboard.
Thank you for the evening.
That was… very interesting.
Goodbye, Mrs. Bell.
-(Heinz) Goodbye.
Bye.
The cup really suits you.
You always act like the boss,
so, like, in a girl-power way.
Thank you.
Oh, what a night!
But it all turned out well, didn't it?
-So, is Dad joining the board now?
I don't know if I even want that
anymore. All the stress, every day.
Emails, Calls...
I just don’t know, if it’s
a matter of wanting to.
Hm? You know, we are...
... are indeed... deeply
in debt. Now you know.
Yes, Mom is right. Your
dad really messed up.
With stocks and such.
I kept it all to myself.
That was such a ridiculously egotistical trip.
-Mhm.
But aren’t those ultimately
just luxury problems?
(Carla laughs.)
- (Heinz) I mean, we have each other.
Even if we had to get out
of here. Then we’ll camp.
But you can always
all live with me.
Li... Linus, I think, now that
we're all talking so openly,
is a good moment
for you, to say something.
Come, my boy.
Whatever it is, spit it out.
Whatever you want to tell us,
never forget: We love you.
Okay. I… think,
um,
I…
-Yes.
...rich.
-Hm?
Not filthy rich, but maybe enough.
-You have 100,000, you are fucking mega-rich.
Uh, wha…
Yes, I, uh, I still had the
3000 euros from Grandma.
And Floppy and I, we
invested in some new AI coins.
A Taiwanese influencer has
posted something on Reddit.
It doesn't matter. But there was a
huge rush, and we were insanely lucky.
Did you understand anything?
-Yes, I understood it.
Grandpa, I have almost 100,000 Euros in the account.
- Congratulations.
I wanted to buy a snowboard, but
I can give you something as a gift.
Or borrow it.
-I’d like that even more.
(The doorbell rings.)
-Well, stay seated. Relax.
I'll take care of it.
-My son.
Peter.
-Heinz, boy...
You're having a party, or what?
-What are you doing on your bike so late?
Why? What else am I supposed
to do? You’re not even inviting me.
I, I know,
I am really, really sorry
about this stock option.
I'm sorry too. It
wasn't your fault.
Do you know, I often
drive through the forest.
and always come by the place,
Where we both played Winnetou.
Do you still remember?
Wherever we… our
first pubic hair appeared.
...
-You’ve probably repressed it.
Man, Heinzi, what
friends we used to be!
Yes.
-We were inseparable.
You know, I have no family.
And you never call, unless you
have a wart or something, and…
Heinzi,
Are you coming with me for a bike ride?
-Oh, I promise you, come on.
Heinzi.
(Peter laughs.)
My Heinzi.
My little Heinz.
Dad.
Mavie. What are you doing here?
-What are you all doing here?
(Heinz) Ha!
(Peter) Hammer!
(Piano music from inside)
I, I… I’ll leave you alone now.
Do you want to come in for a moment?
-No, no, everything's fine.
And we're riding bikes, Heinzi.
We’ll see each other!
(Soft music)
(Music stops.)
-I can’t remember the rest quite as well.
(Georg) Great, Leni. Great.
Almost as good as Hilmal.
-(Georg) What a beautiful ending.
But it’s already late, I’m going now.
-You can sleep here.
Yes.
-So… thank you, you're very welcome, yes.
Leni, you say, I don’t
want to change anything.
Look.
My driver’s license. I don’t think
that will save the climate, but…
Maybe a few pedestrians.
-Yes.
That expired a long time ago.
-Really?
(Heinz) Look who's here.
Hello!
No.
-(Leni cheers.)
(Mavie) Hello.
-(Carla) My darling!
Oops!
(A joyful babble of voices)
(Johlen)
(Music: "Let's Dance"
by David Bowie)
(Cheers)
(Song) Let's Dance
Let's Dance
Put on your red shoes.
And dance the blues.
Let's Dance to the song.
They're playin' on the radio
Let's Dance
While colour lights up your face
Sway through the
crowd to an empty space
(Birds are chirping.)
(Phone buzzes.)
Healthy.
Tomorrow, Heinz. Just wanted
to ask: Are you still coming?
I'm taking off today...
Is that okay?
-Sure.
Is naturally a bit of excitement here because
of Steinhof, yeah. But I’ll handle it.
I know. Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Say, could you imagine
joining the board?
I would like to nominate
you. Think about it.
Ciao.
(Music: "Space
Oddity” by David Bowie)
Ground Control to Major Tom
Take your protein pills.
And put your helmet on
Ten, nine, eight
-Ground Control to Major Tom
Seven, six
Commencing countdown, engines on
-Five, four
Three, two
Check ignition
-One
And may God's love
be with you -Lift off
This is Ground Control to Major Tom
You've really made the grade
And the papers want to
know Whose shirts you wear
Now it's time to leave
the capsule If you dare
This is Major Tom
To Ground Control
Ich trete Durch die Tür. I'm
stepping Through the door.
And I'm floating In
a most peculiar way
And the stars look
Very different today
(Music: \"Weekendfeeling",
by Fanta Four)
Save the date Date is set
You must not miss it
U.A. w. g.
Mega-Event Everyone wants to go
The quota Extremely limited
Here again Everything passes
Complicated, but
Not too late yet
You plus four Okay, let’s go
VIP Well, of course.
Need, where we
are Outside or inside
As always, no valid reason.
Or a deeper meaning.
Do, instead of asking
Why and for what reason
The nights to days With
everyone and everything
Everyone comes and celebrates
you Nobody knows how old you are
Why? Why?
Good that you are excited.
But a celebration
Isn't enough for us
Why? Just isn't enough.
Why? I don't know.
Hey-hey-hey-hey
Doesn't matter at all
What number spring is it
Thirty years Weekend feeling
All your favorite songs.
And we play, play
Play, play it again
Doesn’t matter at all
What number spring is it
Thirty years Weekend feeling
All your favorite songs.
And we play Play, play, play
So weit weg.
We are foregoing The couch.
And throw out All the VIPs
Out the back entrance.
Look, we’re building
Something for the children.
And put a seesaw in the lounge.
VIP swing In the lounge
Despite Virtual Space
Are we really
Still in the house?
Hold the balance
Otherwise, they’ll
just fly away from you.
People of my world, I
mean, time is money.
But they forget, money is money.
And time is time.
In doing so, it
explains itself Of itself.
Because in the
end From the money
To most of them still
Half a month remains
Everyone is coming
And celebrating you
Nobody knows How old you are
Why?
Good that you are enthusiastic
But a celebration
Isn't enough for us
Why? Just isn’t enough.
Why? I don't know.
Hey-hey-hey-hey
Doesn't matter at all
What number spring is it
Thirty years Weekend feeling
All your favorite songs.
And we play, play
Play, play it again
Doesn't matter at all
What number spring is it
Thirty years Weekend feeling
All your favorite songs.
And we play Play, play, play
He, Swabian champagne
Splashes in mountains of carafes.
And we grab a suit jacket
tie and Havaianas flip-flops
They're stealing the slats from your
fence, You clown, we build what we smoke.
Slurping schnapps in bowls, zap!
And taking shots like weapons, bang!
Dragging Beate pushes
the shed Until it crashes.
And we pour skulls Of shaken
gin down the gullet, boom
Shadow in the mirror Wings
like dwarves on giraffes
Singing: "Yeah! Yeah!"
Doesn't matter at all
What number spring is it
Thirty years Weekend feeling
All your favorite songs.
And we play, play
Play, play it again
Doesn't matter at all
What number spring is it
Thirty years Weekend feeling
All your favorite songs
And we play Play, play, play
J. Möck
BABELFISH TRANSLATIONS
translated from German
using ollama & gemma3