(Bird chirping)
(Woodpecker drums)
(Humming)
(Owl hoot)
(floaty punk rock)
(Pneumatic hammer)
Good morning, Mrs.
Pasternak. You look delicious.
-Little slimeball.
-Thanks for the coffee,
I made potato soup.
You do it in the basket.
Great!
Hi. Only good news allowed.
Yes, as always.
-Good morning, neighbor.
-Morning.
(Baby gurgles)
There’s the little
screamer, too.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
(loudly) Boo!
Hey, what's that supposed to
mean? Are you crazy, or what?
-Being startled always helps me.
-With hiccups, you idiot. Asshole.
-(Man) Mornin', fuzzball, -Are
you getting everything wet?
Yeah, all good, dude.
-Hey, Fussel, -Yeah.
-Fang.
-You're the best,
For you, dude. Enjoy your meal.
(soothingly) Yes...
-Excuse me.
-Sorry.
Man, that's cute.
-I think that's awesome.
-What do you think is awesome?
That you’re buying meat.
Most amazing women,
are vegan, you know.
So tense tofu aunts, That's
not for us, right, Durutti?
Oh, Durutti,
The leader of the anarchists
in the Spanish Civil War.
Don't talk rubbish, do you
know Buenaventura Durruti?
It was… (she clears
her throat) 1896 to 1936.
I study political science.
Carnivore and also intelligent.
Do you perhaps have a sausage?
Yes.
-Come here.
-Maybe one more for the dog?
Come here, Durutti,
Hammer lady, hm? I've got this.
-Yes, I'm already home.
-Ah. It was very nice to meet you.
-Yes, me too. Take care.
-You too.
-Bye.
-See you then.
(Mrs.) Adonis!
Adonis!
Little Adele,
You're called Adonis? Awesome.
Adonis.
I have him! I have him.
Thank God.
There you are, my dear Adilein.
The mistress was so worried.
Came towards me. Then I
thought, that one has escaped.
-Good thing you were there.
-No problem.
Thank you. Wait.
-Here, -That isn't necessary.
Tie it tighter next time.
-Good morning.
-Morning.
Hello.
Mr. Poschka, come
with me right away.
No! I've been waiting for
two hours. It's my turn now.
That is an internal
process. Come here.
Dude, you're off,
Relax for once.
Go to a meadow, run through it.
We have a problem.
We have an internal audit.
There are some controllers in the
house. There's one standing there.
-Don't look so obviously.
-Crazy,
And now they are checking
the long-term customers,
and in your case…
Why, what is it?
They receive welfare benefits, well,
since welfare benefits have existed.
And before that...
I know your private situation,
and I fully understand.
I mean, you know
that too, right?
With all that you
accomplish, that is…
unbelievable.
Mrs. Linde,
You are my rock
in the raging sea.
They have my back. For
the really important things.
Glad to hear it. How
is little Ali doing?
Hm? Oh, I see.
That’s tough.
They have now diagnosed
him/her/them with Tourette's syndrome.
What?
Refugee child,
and now this, too.
Luckily, no one understands him
when he rants and raves in Afghan.
The mother addicted to
pills, the father never there.
I am the big brother,
the one he never had.
His is on the pressure plate…
What? That's terrible.
Yes.
Quite dreadful. (clears throat)
Yes...
This can’t go on like this.
You need to take action.
Yes, active.
(passionate moaning)
-Everything okay? Yes
No.
Why not?
I am pregnant.
(Fussel laughs)
No, really. Really, now.
But you couldn't
possibly know that yet,
Not by you. I’m
three months along.
Ah...
Is that a problem for you?
No. I can live with that.
(Punk rock)
Oh, fuck.
Come on, man!
-Keys lost.
-Idiot.
(Fussel) I got this letter
from the pension scammers,
They want to know
every single thing.
Yesterday, "Unsettled Times".
What I did from August
1991 to February 1994.
‘91… I only have completely
blurred memories.
What business is
it of theirs, anyway?
They are coming to the clinic.
Huh?
An absolute emergency. A
miracle that went so quickly.
They want to make
an example out of you.
Cut off all allowances,
everything. Rent, health insurance.
They have me in their sights,
disciplinary investigation.
-Man, they accuse me of having thrown you...
-What kind of clinic?
I told them what a
selfless person you are.
Yes -That didn't help.
Also, my brother-in-law
is a psychiatrist,
He has been initiated and
written a certificate for you.
You will be admitted
to therapy immediately.
He secured a place
in a beautiful clinic.
Mrs. Linde, what
are you talking about?
-From burnout.
-Burnout?
You have a burnout.
Six weeks of inpatient stay.
and then a medical certificate
of incapacity for work.
Stationary? Mrs. Linde,
I’m not good in captivity.
You know what
burnout is, Mr. Poschka?
Please, you can
find information there.
It must be. We're all
in the same boat now!
Oh God, here he comes.
Oh, the legendary Mr. Poschka.
Mr. Poschka?
(Punk rock)
(Punk rock transitions
into quiet guitar sounds)
-That must be the new one.
-I've got this.
Good morning.
Welcome to the Berghoff
Clinic... Mr. Poschka.
Our reading room.
-Common room.
-Do you have Sky?
-Please?
-Because of football.
Or is there a pub around here?
-Um...
-That's okay.
Our patients should
not leave the grounds.
How now? Are we
prisoners? Is this a gulag here?
(with accent) "You can take
everything from me, but not my freedom."
Please be a little
careful with the jokes.
not only in the
interest of the patients.
My grandfather was
murdered in the Gulag.
Oh, sorry. I didn’t
mean to do that.
Mr. Wagner?
That is your new
roommate, Mr. Poschka.
Hi.
You can call me
Fussel, everyone does.
(distressed) Man,
Günth... (he clears
his throat) Günther,
Prof. Dr. Gunst will conduct
the introductory meeting with you.
Dinner is at six.
At six? (Door closes)
Isn't that more
of a brunch, then?
Does it bother you if I smoke?
Stinks.
(sighing) Okay.
-(Mann) The bladder protects
you., -(Frau) I can’t do that.
-(Man) Just let go.
-(She sobs)
(Anleiterin) In
stillness lies the power.
(sobbing) I can't do
that. I can't do that.
(Mann) Yes, you
can. You can do it.
-(Man) How lovely,
a new one, -Hi.
Hi. I am Datty.
-I am Fussel, -Fussel? Cute.
(Snuffling sounds)
And who are you?
(Puppe) Fuck you,
you spaz. He's mine.
Excuse me, he’s in a
really bad mood today.
Hey. (quietly) Pull
yourself together.
We both said, that we
need more freedom, hm?
I'm just kidding,
That is my job.
Puppeteer for children,
Perhaps you've heard of
them? Datty and the Dateheads.
No,
Among the little ones, I
am one of the big ones.
Okay. Mhm.
We'll see each other, won't we?
(Doll) But he has a great ass.
(Geese honk)
(Birdsong)
(loud quacking)
No. That’s because you
used the wrong detergent.
He always gets
those red pimples.
And when Jonas has
his German test tomorrow,
then slip a glucose
tablet into his lunchbox.
Don't forget, that Kira tomorrow
at half past three to the...
Oh, yes, yes of
course. I have to as well.
So then, I… I love…
Yes, goodbye.
-(Rustling)
-(she startles) Oh God.
Sorry. I thought, here
cell phones are prohibited.
Oh, I see. No. Yes.
Don't tell on me, please.
That was my family,
I have to go to them...
Also, they can’t
manage on their own.
There are so many things.
The washing machine...
Aha.
I am, by the way, Andreas.
But everyone calls me Fussel,
Why?
-What “why”?
-Why do they call you Fussel?
Oh, that’s a nickname
from my school days,
because I had such
sparse beard growth.
You still have the same
nickname from school days?
Yes. Why not?
Yes.
I must.
Okay.
(he exhales heavily)
(thoughtful music)
(loud quacking)
(he screams)
(he splashes into the water)
Old man!
Shit.
(he laughs and cheers)
(loudly) Yes! Yes! Yes!
(Man) Quiet, people
want to sleep here.
(softly) Man, am I stupid?
(he spits)
Also, Mr. Poschka.
Warm welcome to us.
Impressive.
That is really a
very thin patient file.
Dramatic attestation
from the colleague:
Immediate inpatient therapy
strongly recommended.
Yes, but… no history,
no medication.
No outpatient therapies?
I just tried for a
very long time,
to settle my
problems with myself.
I didn't want to burden anyone.
That's just how I am.
So, so. Well then…
1.82 meters, 72 kilograms,
44 years old, single.
Children?
-Hm?
-Oh, a daughter,
I have a daughter.
They just briefly forgot them?
No, I… I was lost in
thought somewhere else.
Concentration problems.
That’s just typical, isn’t it?
Okay.
Mr. Poschka.
How are you doing today?
-Tired.
-Mhm.
Also, more than tired,
Completely exhausted.
Headaches, dizziness,
It... it's just all
too much for me.
Are you allergic to anything?
Yes, for example,
against the AfD.
Sorry, I always get a
little silly when I’m nervous.
No, no allergies.
Closer.
(muffled heartbeat)
(Flashlight beeps)
-Drugs?
-No, thank you,
The joke is old.
But they smiled briefly.
(A rooster crows)
Good morning.
(Fussel groans)
(Doctor) We have a new arrival.
Warm welcome, Mr. Poschka,
here in our little club.
Do you want to tell me
something about yourself?
Mr. Poschka?
Huh?
We would like to
get to know you.
Oh 50…
(hesitantly) I would like to…
Maybe someone
else could go first?
Really bad headaches.
Sure.
Is there anything
on anyone’s mind?
Yes, me.
I lay awake the entire night,
because my company has a very
important contract negotiation today.
-(Fussel) Today is Sunday.
-Excuse me?
Today is Sunday.
And you have \"a contract
negotiation on Sunday?
If things were different,
I wouldn't be here now.
(clears throat) So,
anyway, my attorney must
to lead the
negotiation, because I…
I’m not there, you know.
Yes, it concerns
very large properties.
an absolutely essential
transaction for my company,
and I spent almost the entire night
developing negotiation strategies.
I can't turn that off,
it's driving me crazy.
Mr. Lamprecht, how would you
describe the importance of your company?
assess your life?
(He clears his throat)
The company is already…
That is very...
Maybe…
Hm?
Maybe you're just afraid that...
it could come to a good
conclusion even without you.
I know that from my children.
I am always proud, when they
manage something on their own,
and at the same
time, but I am also sad,
that they don’t need
me as much anymore.
Real estate, you say, huh?
Real estate investments,
to be precise.
I run a company…
I’ve always wanted to
know how that works.
Nice that you are
contributing, but...
How can one sell something,
that doesn't belong to them?
What do you mean?
I mean… the Earth,
You didn’t knead
that yourself, did you?
It's just there. We
all live off of that.
Eight billion shoot
me dead people,
And why are there a few
among them who can simply say:
That part of Earth here, from
here to over there, it belongs to me.
Where on Earth did they
get that piece of land?
Bought from the
owner or inherited.
No, you don’t understand me.
That can’t possibly have an
owner. That's common knowledge.
I mean, someday some guy
in the Stone Age, simply put:
My cave., My cave
courtyard. Mine.
That's bullshit, you understand?
He had no right to do that.
And so it went on beautifully,
And now it’s your turn.
Only because your
great-great-great-great-grandmother…
simply grabbed a piece of land
back then, are you now here...
Mr. Poschka. No.
That's like selling
rainwater or wind.
They intend to do
that, the corporations,
What is all this supposed to
be? What is this hippie stuff?
Dude, you’re
selling stolen goods.
That is outrageous!
Hey, that’s so unfair, man!
You are a huge asshole!
(arguing amongst themselves)
(Nurse) Please sit down.
(they are shouting
at each other)
(Splashing)
-(Nurse) Just put it back on.
-(Fussel) Sorry, sorry...
-Excuse me, I think she...
-(Rosi sobs)
(Nurse) Just sit back down.
(Splashing)
Sorry, I was a little heated.
It really pisses me off when things
like that happen. All these crybabies,
And their "First World Problems."
I just can't deal with that much,
It's a symptom of burnout,
outbursts of aggression.
You should actually know that.
I…
The guy earns millions
of thalers with his crap,
and then he bawls, because
that stresses him out so much.
(he imitates crying)
Boo-hoo-hoo.
(softly) Boo-hoo,
The machine will just crush
you. You brought it on yourself.
And you are here because…
Your therapist wrote:
Exaggerated emphatic feeling.
Yes, that shit really
breaks my heart,
Hm... The carrots... Yes.
Hm... No carrots.
Potatoes, yes.
Although… No.
I’m not hungry at all.
(she groans annoyed)
Next.
Hello, I’ll take these
chicken nuggets and noodles.
(A ringing in the ears
begins) Everything okay?
-Hey, hey.
-It has to go, it has to go.
Mrs. Gröning, don't hit.
Don't hit her in the ear, okay?
-What does she have?
-Tinnitus, it’s always there.
(Gröning) It is always there.
It is always there. Always.
I'll take another
plate, meatball,
Calm down, a few more.
I love this stuff. Thanks,
I have the chicken
nuggets and noodles for you.
Are you okay?
- Mhm.
Enjoy your meal.
Hi.
Where is your shrink?
With electroshock therapy.
There's no other way.
Is that kind of shit real?
Small joke.
Here, all they do
is talk, talk, talk.
And a little gymnastics.
Gymnastics is voluntary.
Why are you here?
I mean, you're perfectly
normal. Except for that doll.
Well, it is tiring, constantly
working with children.
Arno, I didn't say that,
It was agreed, that we
would all make the decisions,.,
Now it is.., Hello?
(in a high voice) What, you’re
leaving? You want to do your own thing?
(with a deep voice)
Yes, I want to evolve,
Butterfly. Metamorphosis,
What meta?
(deeply) To pupate,
(high) Fuck dolls,
Stay here, with me,
(softly) Hey, hey. Get lost.
Hey, hey, hey. Don't
touch Schnurpsi. Leave him,
Don't touch it,
Leave your damn
fingers off my doll!
A few things came
together back then.
Tax audit, private crap,
(Screams)
I probably overreacted a bit.
(he roars with all his might)
I don’t know if I can
ever do that again.
And what's left for me
then? I have nothing else.
Get a really good night’s
sleep, then you’ll be alright again,
Does it taste good?
(electrical humming)
Did I fall asleep?
Two hours.
(yawning) I... I’ll soon
be one of you here,
Why are you crying
again? What’s wrong?
(Datty) He does that sometimes.
Awake, burned-out
ones of this earth!
You need more power.
You are elevator music.
More Sex Pistols!
(floaty punk rock)
Come!
Yes, come on, hop, hop! Come
on! You here too, you yoga rejects,
Günther, come.
This is not voluntary.
Come on.
Come on, back there!
Come, come, come!
Hop, hop! Go!
Get up, you pill-poppers!
Hey. You are still with
us. You go over here.
-Shall we play offside?
-Are you serious?
They are one more.
You are the referee. So,
Günther, you go in goal,
-Stand compactly.
-Compactly.
(Datty) Don't sit down.
Put it between the chairs.
-(Fussel) Heads or tails?
-Tails.
I thought so. Okay.
Come on.
You must flip the coin.
What are you doing?
You said I should throw.
Okay, you sausage
heads can start.
-Come on, Rosi, come on, do it.
-I can't.
-If you don't like something, whistle.
-What?
-(Datty) The
whistle, -Blow into it,
I'm not stupid. I have a
doctorate in literary studies.
All the better. A
whistle, madam.
(soft whistle)
You do it. Günther,
you've got him.
(Lamprecht) Yes! That’s
one to nil by Lamprecht.
(he is overjoyed)
How awesome is that? Yes!
Hey, guys, where…
-Where are you guys going?
-That’s really too brutal.
That's really too
dangerous. But never mind.
Wait a moment.
Guys, wait a moment.
(Geese honk)
(louder whistle)
("Crazy Town" by Richard
Myhill, bouncy Ska rhythm)
(one doesn't understand him)
I want to be in the Bubble too!
(Music stops)
(Datty) Günther?
-(Fussel) Harsh, -Günther?
(Fussel) Everything okay?
(general groaning)
(Fussel) Was it good?
Come down, sweetie.
Yes, I am out of breath.
Oh, there’s the coin.
-Günther, I'm sorry about
that, -You were the one.
-Okay? Yes.
-Merle, is everything alright?
-Yes, I kind of have a...
Unsteady on your feet?
-That was fun.
-Now we're going to shower.
-You did a good job.
-Thank you.
-Oh, hi.
-Hey.
Don't you have a home?
Emergency service.
Ready for what?
They are far too
lazy, to cause trouble.
You clearly don't.
I am something special too,
Not as special as you think.
(he laughs)
What do you want to
be, when you grow up?
Please?
If you grow up, what
do you want to do?
(Fussel smacks his lips)
Good morning.
Good morning,
Mr. Poschka. You are late.
Well.
Also, yes, good. Let's
just start with you then.
You still owe us a performance.
Who you are, what
brings you to us…
All clear, so, let's go.
My name is Andreas
Poschka, friends call me Fussel,
I am here because I’m completely
burned out, like all of you,
And I live in a socially
problematic area.
and just take
care of the people,
I'm fully on board with
that, that's really my thing.
What kind of people
are you helping there?
Yes, there is for
example… Little Ali.
That might be a brand.
Refugee child, Afghan,
speaks no German.
and practically
always attracts trouble.
Go ahead and tell [me].
Yes… (he clears his throat)
Recently, for example,
There I see Ali standing on
the playground down below,
and then there are
also these three tree-tall,
really nasty, vile guys,
tattooed skinheads,
they’re standing
around him and shoving…
(Scene becomes silent)
(light music)
(silent scene)
Well, but all that sympathy,
that naturally takes its toll.
You are not burned out.
It comes in waves.
You're just here on
vacation, you parasite.
If the fortress here is
supposed to be a vacation…
I bet you haven’t worked a
single day paying income tax.
And later we can
continue to fatten you up.
-You are a burden to us
all, -Money, money, money.
That's all, you can think of?
You must really be
a very sad person.
Tell me, who actually
gives you the right to do that?
I don't have the strength,
to argue with you, Anatol,
-Do you have family?
-The whole world is my family,
No children?
-Yes, a daughter, -Really?
And how old is she?
(He clears his throat) Eight.
Eight. And what’s her name?
-Lina.
-Lina?
My middle one is also eight. Is
Lina coming to the open house?
-No.
-Why not?
Also, I…
I often have to think of my
children here in the clinic.
That I want to be with them very
quickly, because I miss them so much,
But that, you know…
That’s a good goal too,
that one feels better,
so that one can
quickly get back to them.
Mr. Poschka, there you are. I
was just about to speak to you.
Mr. Poschka!
(Fussel sighs)
Mrs. Linde? What
are you doing here?
(Merle) What did
you say, my darling?
What kind of woman?
Why is a woman
cooking lunch for you?
Has Dad the...
Wait a moment, could you
quickly pass me my dad?
Mhm.
(Dr. Gunst) He is
a liar, Mrs. Linde,
(Frau Linde) That's
not true. He is deeply...
(Dr. Gunst) He is one of those
people you believe anything from,
because one wants
to believe them.
Mr. Poschka is a seducer,
They’ll fire me if this
comes out and if that’s true.
-You can’t do that to her.
-I’m not doing anything to her.
If the welfare office cuts my
benefits, I will be homeless.
Not if you go to jail.
You made all of this up?
There isn’t an Ali at all?
I have observed over the past few days,
how the patients have been reacting to you.
You reach people.
We used to be here 19
doctors, therapists, nurses.
Now there are eleven of us,
Yes, and?
We simply no longer
have the time and capacity,
to do justice to all patients.
No, right?
(he laughs) No!
Yes, if you want to stay here.
If you want me to believe
your Münchhausen story,
then you need to
make yourself useful.
Yes, okay, then I’ll make
you the animator here.
No, I don’t need a
cheerful busybody.
I need someone, who
really helps this person,
who listens to them, engages
with them on an equal footing.
What is that supposed to be?
An undercover therapist or what?
That’s definitely not legal!
Legal, illegal, who gives
a damn. Wasn't it like that?
Listen, amusing tramps
is one thing, fine and good.
But they repair
it, I can't do that.
They don't want to
confide in anyone for me.
I'm doing everything wrong.
Pack your things. I am
very sorry, Mrs. Linde,
Okay, I'll do it, I'll do it,
Okay, I’ll do that.
Mrs. Linde?
Mrs. Linde!
That was a close call.
(piercing scream)
What happened?
She shoved the pen into her ear.
Call an ambulance quickly.
Mrs. Gröning, please stay calm.
-(Fussel) What happened?
-Please go to your room.
No, no, no, no. Don't
touch. Stay calm.
The hands go down. Very calm.
And help is coming right away,
All good, all good.
(thoughtful music)
May I?
Sorry, there was a
little ketchup on it.
(Datty) She’s a
total control freak.
And besides, she has four children,
man, house, station wagon in the carport.
With that, everything
has to be flawless.
And one day, that's when
the shit really hit the fan.
(Thunderclap)
(Child) Mom?
Merle?
(he sighs)
Also, what’s wrong?
I love you. Will you marry me?
What?
You do hear me, though.
It’s all falling apart.
Everything breaks.
(soft guitar music)
(Television) ...Afternoon
noted the DAX
after all, 0.9% firmer
at 10,012 points,
Their high score,
however, is 10,323 counters.
still far from the
desired 10,800 mark,
While in the Asian markets…
So, let's turn off the Dagobert
Duck television for once.
and don't always just
think about money,
That, in fact, makes
you stupid and unhappy.
Well.
Old man, let me
tell you a story.
My father was just like
you, He had a dowel factory,
Always just worked,
Always shit on it.
And then he died, at 52.
Stroke.
I tried to be sad.
I really tried, to miss him.
Tears are welling up in my eyes.
-You don’t believe me, do you?
-Nope,
Are you compulsively
lying, or are you just a loser?
Dude, we're all losers,
We all didn’t buckle
up in the carousel.
and flew out of the curve.
That’s why we’re here,
Only I never felt like
wearing a seatbelt.
And you think your bank
account protects you in some way,
But all this coal-shoveling
is fucking irrelevant...
You have absolutely no idea.
Okay, then tell me.
(ominous music swells slowly)
Please all come together, I
have an important announcement,
No matter what you're doing
right now, it can't be that important.
like that, what I
have to tell you now,
I was good with
numbers even as a child.
But you can’t
calculate everything.
Sometimes things
don’t go as planned.
And then one must be
able to react spontaneously,
otherwise, others
simply eat you up.
Mrs. Dr. Gunst says I have a
pronounced deficit of spontaneity.
and psychosocial inflexibility.
That is to say, you are a
smart aleck and a know-it-all.
No, that is to say, I have a
psychosocial flexibility deficiency.
Okay.
Jürgen, I’m sorry,
Do you know that
feeling, when you think,
You deserve, to be spat on?
15 people were laid off,
just because I made a mistake.
That’s like with a cell phone.
After a few years, the battery
always discharges faster and faster.
As soon as you charge it,
it’s immediately empty again.
Eventually, work is over.
(Subway trains rattle
and squeak ever louder)
Sell your company,
and your Porsche.
Hm?
I don't have a Porsche.
(strained groaning)
(Fussel) Man, you won't believe this.
Even the pee-wee aunt gets more done.
Not so easy, to get
your ass in gear, huh?
One more could still go.
"Text Ideas"?
Are you a fan of Texte Ideas?
(singing) "Slap power in
the face, victory to passion.
We will win! We will get you!"
-The first album.
-The best album.
I was with the
guitarist for six years.
Seriously?
What are the guys up to?
I was hoping for a revival.
Jonas now has a blog.
Thomas is now a
big shot in the SPD.
The loser has an online shop
for condoms and air fresheners.
-No! Yes
And Max?
Max... Max has
drunk himself to death.
Live fast, die young.
-I wanted to ask you something.
-(annoyed) What?
What actually happened
to Günther’s face?
I’m supposed to help him, right?
If you help him, then
as quickly as possible.
In ten days, his therapy ends,
unless a miracle happens by then,
does he then end up in
a closed psychiatric ward,
Wow. To the psych ward?
But that can’t be done.
He’ll go under there.
Yes.
Yes, and what am I
supposed to do now?
Just be yourself.
Only better.
(mischievous music)
What are you doing? Have
you never seen “Prison Break”?
"Papillae"?
"Escape from Alcatraz"?
-Didn't see any of it, man?
-Nah,
(Datty) Where do
you guys want to go?
-To have a little beer.
-Why don’t you let me know?
Yes, then come.
-Okay.
-Come.
-Psst! Yes
(atmospheric pop music)
(light, airy disco-funk)
Günni...
-Do your friends call you Günni?
-No,
You, I’m worried about you,
Hm? What’s wrong with
you? What happened?
Tell me.
You don’t want to expose
yourself like that, I understand.
We're all in the same boat.
We are all overwhelmed
and insecure, all of us,
You don't.
You know, when I became
a father, I was really in shock.
War… war absolutely not planned.
Nora, also Lina’s mother, and I…
We weren’t even properly together.
But it just happened anyway.
(Nora) What smells so bad here?
-Everything okay?
-Everything okay.
(Baby crying)
-Are you still quite
alright? „Fuck!
-Not at all, everything is okay!
-The pizza is ready.
(He coughs) I wanted
to make dinner,
You only build crap..,
And then is…
Nora came to life.
Car accident.
Lina then went to Nora’s mother.
I naturally wanted to
continue seeing my little one.
Andreas, she needs a father,
not stupid remarks and loud music,
-She had plenty of fun,
-And your horror stories!
Happy Birthday! (Shouts)
She’s into horror stories.
She probably got that from
me. So, more like spooky,
You weren’t at her
ballet performance,
She cried terribly,
And now you show up and
want to go camping with her,
-Yes, to make up for it.
-What? Until next time?
Dad! I packed a compass,
-Hey, little mouse,
-And cookies,
Lina, it won't work out
this time with the camping,
-Andreas has another appointment,
-But I packed everything up,
Of course we’re going camping,
I also have a few Chinese firecrackers with
me, then we’ll launch fireworks into the air,
Behave yourself like an adult,
Do you always have to interfere,
you narrow-minded witch?
What the hell is
all this bullshit?
Man, you always
make such a fuss, hey!
“Dad...
-That disgusts me, man!”
I don’t want to go
camping anymore,
-What? But why not?
-I want to stay with Grandma,
But Lina…
You are mean,
-Oh come on, Lina, -To
yell at Grandma like that,
Little mouse…
I won't let anyone take
my daughter away from me.
Lina is the best, that
has ever happened to me,
By a mile.
And what about me?
I only build crap.
Your grandma is right. I
would just mess up the little one.
-Hey, Fussel,
-Datty, stop it.
-I love you.
-Stop, you're annoying me now.
You're annoying. Stop
with the bullshit, man!
Man!
Sweetheart.
Sweetie…
Are you a faggot, or what?
(catchy pop Schlager music)
(Battle cry)
(Schlager music
continues to play)
(Roar)
Let me go, you wanker!
(Datty) These
filthy farmers. Idiots.
(as a doll) That comes from
the incest here. No, Fussel?
-You're getting on my nerves.
-You fought for me.
Yes, great!
I wanted to chat with
Günther in peace and quiet.
Not that kind of
psycho bullshit,
You freak! No wonder the
children are afraid of you.
What?
Shitty bed, hey.
Lint?
(he sighs) What is it?
It was a nice evening.
Mhm.
I…
I am...
Entrepreneur, you know?
I have tanning salons.
Eleven branches
throughout the north.
It's also been going
very well so far.
At least financially.
I was always on the road
between Flensburg and Glückstadt.
Lübeck, Mölln...
Idiots everywhere.
Eventually, my wife was
gone. I was never home, either.
And if so, always on the phone,
there was always something going on.
(fragments of conversation)
I’ve also had too much to drink.
And then snorted cocaine.
Come on, you
asshole! Get lost, man!
Then I forgot things,
messed them up.
And then, a few weeks ago…
was over.
God, please don't
let me down now,
(Tires screech)
(Horn)
I can’t remember
anything at all.
How I got there, got out.
And you know what?
I didn’t care either.
Suddenly it was clear to me,
that everything is meaningless.
Sunbeds, it's all pointless.
Do you only get skin cancer from
tanning and look like a leather handbag.
And for what?
Pointless.
Everything is pointless.
(Computer) Welcome to Sweet
Sun, Your tanning program is starting,
I have always
dreamed of traveling.
To the Arctic Circle, It must
be so beautiful up there.
But then, of course,
it was all too late.
Then I fell asleep.
Can't quite remember
anymore, but it felt…
It felt somehow right.
I believe, I probably
just wanted to vanish.
Therefore, I'm constantly
crying. My tear ducts are blocked.
(Fussel takes a deep breath)
Burnt.
Stay that way.
I am crying forever now.
Shit, I wish I had burned.
I still want that too.
Simply not to be there anymore.
(soft voices, joyful greetings)
Hey, Fussel,
Well, Datty.
Are you sulking?
I'm sorry, I was drunk.
You really annoyed me
with your terror puppet.
(thoughtful music)
(Datti’s doll speaks
unintelligibly)
(Nurse) His mother,
We picked her up from the
senior living facility today.
You have to imagine that.
He is over 50 years old,
and only his grey
mother worries about him.
Cool.
That guy is completely messed
up. I don't know what I should do.
(melancholy guitar sounds)
-Oh, hey.
-How could you do something like that?
What?
How could you abandon your
children? Explain that to me.
What are you talking about?
You did leave your daughter,
didn't you? How old was she then?
What is that supposed to mean?
My husband wants a divorce.
Oh shit, that’s really
messed up. I’m really sorry.
We have four children, Four,
He's not just leaving me,
he's leaving the children too.
Don't you men
love your children?
Of course, I love my daughter.
Why aren’t you with her?
Why doesn’t she visit you?
I mean, don't you care?
No, of course not. It's a
little more complicated,
Oh, it's complicated. What is
it? How often do you see her?
-Often enough.
-Yes, how often?
Yes -Tell me, how often?
I sometimes oversleep
appointments.
-What kind?
-Just any one, I guess.
-Birthday or what?
-Yeah, could be.
How can someone forget
their child's birthday?
Don't you have a heart?
Say, do you want
to interrogate me?
(she sobs) He
can’t do this to us.
Excuse me.
Okay, fine.
Fussel,
What I told you tonight,
I’m doing that now.
Yes, do that.
Yes, of course.
Do you really mean that?
Yes, do it. You have to do that.
Fuck.
(Knocking)
Merle, it...
I’m sorry about your husband.
Totally shit,
Yes.
You really are a super mom.
You have everything under
control. You know the rules.
You are everything,
what your children need.
You can't explain to a child
why his father just leaves.
(Datty) Help! Help! Fussel!
Help!
Lint!
-Thank God he was
too heavy, -Too heavy?
-Inform Dr. Gunst.
-Günther!
Lint,
I just wanted to say goodbye to
you. You are my best friend, after all.
-And the only one.
-"Say goodbye"? What are you talking about?
What kind of shit
are you doing here?
I told you everything, didn’t I?
As we were talking last night.
I asked you, if I should do it,
and you said:
"You must do that."
I can’t take this anymore.
Do your shit alone.
(fast-paced punk rock)
Good morning, Mrs. Pasternak.
-Where have you been?
-Away.
I was worried. I thought
something had happened to you.
-Accident, or… drugs.
-Drugs?
The caretaker had
to check on you.
He aired you out first.
Man.
Just to disappear…
I couldn’t sleep for worry.
Excuse me.
(melancholy music)
Linde is my name.
-Bergstedt.
-I know.
(distant children’s laughter)
We must help Fussel.
Günther.
-I’m worried about Fussel,
-What about Mr. Poschka?
I have his address,
Let me have that. Where
did you get that from?
You broke into the office.
Psst.
(mischievous music)
What's going on here?
Have you looked at the time?
-Fuzz, help.
-We're stealing the clinic bus. Active.
Come with.
You're all out of your minds, aren't
you? You guys are really... nurses!
(muffled gong)
-Datty!
-Okay, who’s driving?
Who of us takes the
weakest medications?
-Weren't you angry at Fussel?
-It's too exhausting for me.
Anatol?
Hey, Anatol. (Enters)
-(Anatol) Oh man.
-This way.
-Stop!
-Shh. Not so loud.
Merle, be reasonable.
You're not like that.
Yes, I am. Here. Come.
Come.
Also?
-(Günther) Amitriptyline.
-(Datty) 100?
-225 -That’s even worse than me,
A miracle that you can walk.
Um, trazodone.
That's not so
bad. You can drive.
And, wait a moment...
Moclobemide,
What? They're giving you that
and MAO inhibitors together?
Yes -(Datty) Passenger seat,
-What kind of pills are you taking?
-Me? I have no idea.
Small and red.
Far in the back. Better.
-Anatol.
-No, no, keep me out of this.
Anatol.
Only Maprotiline 50, I will be
discharged the day after tomorrow.
You must help us.
(Doll) Go on, take a
chance, you sausage.
Please.
(Sound of a kiss)
Ugh! Will you guys stop it!
I need to concentrate.
Merle.
(energetic punk music)
Come on. Yeah!
Shit.
(Woman angrily) Did you
even turn the machine off?
(Man) Can you help
me carry that up?
No, I have the baby.
Can you do that alone,
can you manage it? Man!
Sorry, it’s dripping here.
No shit, Captain Obvious.
The idiot tried to wash.
Here, take this.
The rags are back there. What
do you want with the towels?
Those are the good ones from my
mother., Dude, come on. Get a cloth.
Get going!
(soft electric guitar sounds)
(powerful rock music)
Next exit!
Thank you, Mrs. Linde,
(a long cheer)
(Horn)
-Hey!
-Square!
Yes, there it is. Here.
-Here...
-Well? Well?
Poschka, Poschka,
Moment. Be quiet.
Poschka, Poschka...
Fussel isn't the type
for a doorbell sign.
-Poschka? Yes
-Are you looking for Fussel? Yes
He wanted to go to
his daughter, he said.
(Doorbell)
Yes, I have it.
In case of emergency,
contact: Petra Bargkoppel.
Swinehagener Street 6, Hamburg.
-Papa!
-My dear!
I missed you.
Is that your tent? Do
you want to camp here?
Andreas, what
are you doing here?
Listen, Petra, I…
I’ve thought a lot.
I was even in therapy,
I love my little big one.
And there… is a
huge hole without her.
A huge hole, here.
It is my fault. I messed it up.
I thought I could sweet-talk
my way through with her.
and just have fun,
and you do the rest.
That wasn’t good.
I understood that, really.
But now… I want to be
a real part of your life.
I'm not building
any more shit, okay?
You’re not building
any more bullshit?
You just broke into my place.
(Doorbell)
We are camping here
tonight. Right under your eyes.
I missed you too, Dad.
Who is the first in the
tent? Attention, ready, go!
Hi.
-(Anatol) Yo.
-(Merle) Good morning.
Good day.
Andreas. Andreas.
Andreas.
I just want to spend time with
her. You don't have to worry.
-Lina, come into the house, -No.
-Lina.
-No.
Lina, your father and I
have something to discuss.
Now that’s enough! Get
out of my way. Please,
What are you doing here?
What is this supposed to mean?
Active.
Who are they?
These are my friends.
-So, come on, Lina.
-(Doll) Ease up a bit.
Who are you, actually?
Favor. Dr. Günther Gunst.
I am a psychotherapist at the
Soltron Clinic in Bad Mückensen.
Mr. Poschka is undergoing
treatment with me,
and we all here,
Dr. Anatol... Liliak,
Sister Merle, Mrs.
Linde from physiotherapy.
and Mr. Datrus…
Mr. Datrus is a patient,
who needed some fresh air.
We are here to see Mr. Poschka, who has
made enormous progress in the development
made to his
personality, to support…
That is absurd.
You burst in here. You're
confusing the poor child.
I am not confused.
Excuse me, but Andreas
has done a lot for us.
Lately, Mrs. Bargkoppel.
(Anatol) Merle, what
are you doing there?
Perhaps you could
still give him a chance,
Mrs. Bargkoppel?
Do you have children?
-Yes, why?
-Would you entrust him with your child?
Yes, all four.
(Frau Linde) Me too.
Mine is already out of the
house, but yes, I would do that.
-(Merle) Anatol.
-What is it?
-I don’t have any
children, “Now.
He could also look
after my plants.
Yes.
Lint really means
a lot to all of us.
Please, Grandma.
Let me at least try, please.
We are all careful,
Thank you. For
everything and for…
You know.
-Bye, Grandma.
-Buckle up, Lina.
(Puppe) Well, did you
butter up the old woman?
Get lost.
(calm rock music)
(Dr. Gunst) Kitchen work,
cleaning, and you talk to the patients.
But you can’t spend the rest of
your life working for room and board.
Well, I’m still recovering
from my burnout.
So? Already heard about it…
-Well, Lina, are
you excited? Yes
Camping with Dad.
If I get out of here,
I’m going camping too.
And trekking. Hiking.
North Cape is
supposed to be great.
For months on end,
the sun doesn't set.
There are Northern Lights.
There are then colors in
the sky. Yellow, red, blue.
It must be crazy.
North Cape. I'm doing it.
(Lina) Really?
That's why it's called a low-pressure
area. It pushes everything down.
The mosquitoes are
flying around down there,
and the swallows want
something to eat and... Oops.
-Papa, the tent is burning.
-Oh, fuck.
Not so bad. It's just
a small hole. Shit!
Whatever. Oh man!
What are we going to do?
We're playing Fireball,
To the other side, go!
Attention, and…
(powerful rock song)
The beautiful ball!
Active!