[Intro music, Trumpet
fanfares and rooster crowing]
[Clapping]
[Clearing throat]
[Coughing]
[Bad coughing]
Excuse me.
[Sniffling]
[Nose blowing]
[Fly buzzing]
[Clapping]
[Fly swatter claps]
What's expected...
Hm?
Ah,
Water is waiting.
That must be said yes to.
[Slurping]
About the East Frisians
unfortunately, up to this very day,
many misconceptions
are widespread.
The whole truth but
alone, stands in this book.
The book, of the Frisians.
[Assenting sigh]
And what is written in it?
Emden Lending Library,
due date August 15, 1924.
[Clears throat] That
will be expensive.
But the Frisian is also
threatened by dangers.
He has had three natural
enemies since time immemorial.
The sea,
the storm,
and his wife.
With everyone,
he is done so far.
You come home now
immediately you old goof!
Yes, honey, I'm
coming right away.
More, or less.
But all that, is
nothing, against the
threat, that this
tormented land...
Uhm, uhm...
This blessed land now faces.
[Click] Start the film.
[Revolver clicks]
[Revolver clicks again]
[Revolver clicks two more times]
Nothing works here... [Shot]
[Intro music]
Look at that, wind turbines!
-That's what they call deserted!
-Wait a minute, Mr. Grödel!
This is the last village
before the coast.
Honestly, Mr. Grödel, it
looks much better back there.
Course North,
Northwest!
Well, that's better.
It's nice and flat here.
And deserted.
Even flatter.
And always
more deserted.
This is just perfect
for our purposes.
Flat, deserted, straight as an
arrow, and no natural obstacles.
Isn't that right, Mr. Grödel?
That looks really good!
And how it will look
afterwards!
[Loud laughter]
[Laughter ends abruptly]
Wait a minute!
What's that?
Looks like a advertising column.
Nonsense!
Way too big!
Could be an old
lighthouse.
Maybe someone still lives
there.
In a advertising column?
No one lives there.
That could
cause problems.
I have to take a closer look at that.
Binoculars!
Huh?
Is something moving there?
On the contrary.
There's someone lying in bed
and snoring!
That can't be! Impossible!
Yes!
With all that noise,
and at this hour?
[Cuckoo clock rings] [Helicopter
noise in the background]
[Cuckoo clock rings again]
[Cuckoo clock rings]
Ouch!
[Dial tones, phone ringing]
Hello?
Frauke?
You probably don't know me, but do you
remember the Frisian party, last week at Köhnemanns?
Yes, the handsome blonde
man who was facing you?
Yes?
The one who put his arm around
you, and kneaded you with his hands?
I was the one
who watched you.
[Click, then ringing]
Hello?
[Phone receiver slams down]
Good morning!
Why are you trembling
so much?
Why are you
so nervous?
What is it?
[Oboe music]
Oh, I see.
Moment.
[Creaking]
[Hissing]
[Plop]
[Pop music]
That's enough!
To central command! Over!
I would never have thought that
someone lived in such a tower.
That can change
very quickly!
At Warp Speed 1000!
[Fiendish laughter]
[Inhale]
[Crackling]
Oh!
Ah! Ouch!
Gymnastics.
Up, down, up, down,
up, down, up, down.
And now the
other eyelid.
Up, down, up,
down, up, down.
[Giggling]
Morning guys,
Breakfast time.
[Otto whistling]
[Chicken clucking]
Schildi...?
[Rattling]
Good morning!
Man, I almost forgot you.
Want fresh food, or rather something
from the can, from your feeder Otto?
Toads would buy "Eat It!", because
"Eat It!" contains the new PCV1.
So that we can make your
shell soft and cuddly! Hihi.
[Otto whistles]
[Click]
[Humming]
Well,
strong day!
[Country music]
Customers!
Let's come to the highlight
of our voluntary Friesland
tour, Friesland's most Frisian tower, presented
by
Friesland's freshest tour guide, followed by
souvenir sale.
[Bus honks twice]
[Low noise]
[Violin music]
[Noise ends]
[Splashing]
[more water splashing]
[Toothbrush sound]
[Gargling]
[Newspaper rustling]
[Pfeifmusik]
[Menschengerede]
[Crowd gasps in astonishment]
[Increased clicking
of cameras]
Moin!
[Crowd falls silent]
Achse, you wouldn't know
how
we greet each other here.
In Russia, they say Mahlzeit,
in Scandinavia Ciao,
Nastrovje, Servus, Grützi,
nobody greets like that here, not even a cow.
Because now you are in Friesland,
I'll tell you and you rejoin.
In Friesland, greetings are different.
In Friesland, you say...?
[Complete silence]
[Louder]
In Friesland you say...?
[Seagull cries]
[Shouting]
In Friesland you say...?
-[(whispering]Shit.
-Shit.
Shit. Shit.
No no no,
Moin!
-Moin! Moin!
-That's it!
And now you can
go right in
here, and look out up there,
and
then you can
pick-pick-pick-Pictures!
Okay?
Pick-pick-pick!
Putt-putt-putt!
Come.
[Otto imitates chicken noises]
And kick off your feet,
when you come back out.
But now you go
in first, everyone in.
And look out, admire how we Frisians have cleared away
the mountains to reveal this unique landscape underneath.
So flat, it's like a disk, you
know it, from the Beatles, Yesterdaich!
[Giggles]
Souvenirs!
Handmade! Made by hand,
in Friesland!
Not 2 Marks, not 4 Marks,
no, 6 Marks!
Very cheap!
[Otto sings] Happy he who has a home,
home makes even the stupidest one full.
As long as there are
tourists
who love my souvenirs so much
that they drive
to my
lighthouse and empty their
wallet here.
Wave goodbye,
wave...
[Otto hums on]
Yes, Grödel,
Yes.
There he will become true, the ancient
dream of mankind, the dream of jet propulsion.
There she comes,
my test track.
There he will drive,
my speed glider.
Oh, what is driving?
Jet, Grödel!
Jet, at a speed of 1000!
[Makes hissing noise]
[Laughter]
Yes.
I don't see any problems,
Mister Van Devil.
The area is totally flat,
almost deserted.
The land belongs to a
Baron von Platt,
who is broke,
he sells without any problems.
What then,
Grödel?
No problems?
Nothing to blow up,
nothing to concrete,
no one to bribe,
no one to corrupt?
Is there nothing out of the way
to clear? That's just awful!
Grödel,
what is that?
A small lighthouse,
Mister Van Devil.
Ha? Well,
I knew it, that has to go.
Does anyone else live there?
-Yes, but he's a small fish.
-Grödel?
Even small fish
can stink.
That is very true,
Mister Van Devil.
But we can only buy the rest
if we have this fish on the hook.
The bait, Grödel?
- The usual? Okay.
- Understood.
[Cheerful music]
But don't underestimate
the natives, Grödel.
[Otto whistles]
Whoever grew up in this harsh, serious
land will become harsh and serious themselves.
And tough as
beachgrass, Grödel.
The wind may bend
it, but it can't break it.
Do you understand what
I mean, Grödel?
You have to adapt, Grödel.
It's
all at stake!
[Door slams shut]
[Engine starts]
[Engine noises]
[Sheep bleating in the background]
[Sheep bleating]
[Knocking]
This is my home.
Untouched nature, far from
progress and technology.
Shepherd control center
to Bello four,
unknown blue sheep
crosses herd seven,
Bello four,
please report.
[Dog voice] Roger, it was just Otto.
[Tire squealing]
In the book of the Frisians it is written,
giving work is more blessed, than taking work.
And it is a sublime feeling,
for
the employer, to place his
precious
raw material into
industrious hands,
so that
beautiful, useful, and profitable things may arise.
[Door opens]
Moin!
[Door closes]
Resupply!
-How's it going?
-Everything is stuck with Grandpa again.
What? Grandpa, come on in!
So, everything is
going wonderfully!
And everything in the interest
of environmental protection!
Recycling!
Too bad,
that the blank
with delivery
wrapped in so much paper.
But otherwise...
Great!
And what about my bucket?
-Ready.
-Aaah!
[Clattering]
-Here.
-Hm hm.
For an heirloom
it still looks too new.
[Clattering]
[metallic clinking]
And a pen,
please.
[Clattering]
Clean work.
[Shot]
[Clinking]
[Groaning]
I'll get you too!
[Shot]
[Clinking]
Ha ha!
[Car horn]
[Hunting music]
[Honking]
[Shot bangs]
[Two shots bang]
Well done, Baron!
Thanks!
One must
stay in practice!
-That was a master shot!
-Yes sir!
They're gone.
This will teach the vegetables
not to mess with us anymore.
Apropos "mess", I
have something for you.
What is it, again?
Where?
Well, in the car!
Now show me!
Unpack it!
-But not here.
-I'm so curious!
We don't want to arouse
the envy of the neighbors.
Apropos neighbors, recently your colleague came
home with supposedly
two freshly skinned rabbits,
his wife naturally wonders why
he already skinned them.
He says:
"I didn't skin them.
I caught the two
in the act.
And I said, you don't have to get dressed
again, I will shoot you right away!" [Laughter]
So, now enter
the good parlour.
I am curious,
what you have brought me this time.
You will be surprised,
Herr Baron!
Yes, I am looking forward
to it, haha.
Everything a little untidy
with me, but
after my clean maid,
my niece, Frauke,
decided
to live with long-haired
apes,
instead of taking care of the household,
everything is going to pot.
There's nothing like a decent brush cut.
Yes, like here, short
at the nape of the neck, wonderful!
-Haha...
-Now let me see it.
[Loud inhalation]
There he is.
The last remaining
original champagne cooler from
the house of
"Von und zu Habsucht”.
A wonderful piece.
Especially
the double coat of
arms, with the
double trunks,
I recognize
among thousands!
"Von und zu Habsucht".
-Magnificent!
-Fits well here.
Noble, noble,
nobler.
And that's why I'm
giving you a Nobel Price.
Take a look
in my wallet.
-That doesn't look good.
-Yes, Ebbe, my dear.
But what follows naturally?
The flood, oh what
do I say flood?
I'm not really supposed
to
say anything yet, but a
spring tide is announcing itself
to me.
Ah, and when that springs, then they
also let something spring for me, yes?
[mischievous laughter]
[Cock-a-doodle-doo]
[cheerful folk music]
[Pig grunting]
[Clattering]
Stop, Karin.
[Pig squealing]
Good heavens!
[cows mooing]
That's not how it works.
Karin, I think you're
making a mistake there.
Me?
Why?
The tea bag doesn't
belong on the compost heap.
But tea is organic.
Ok, but
not the bag.
The bag is
regular waste.
I think you're exaggerating a bit now.
[Engine noise]
No no, with oraganic- and regular waste
there are no compromises for me.
[negative sigh]
That's oraganic.
It's normal,
I'm telling you.
Too bad Frauke
isn't here now.
She has a calm way with
these kinds of problems.
Are we supposed to wait until
Frauke comes home from kindergarten?
Excuse me if I butt in, but I think
you're making this unbelievably easy.
You Otto, how
do you mean that?
[quietly]
Give it here.
So, pay attention!
Instinctively you were
incredibly right.
Karin.
The tea
is of course organic.
And you were
terribly right.
Jan.
The bag is of
course not oraganic.
That's what I'm saying.
Yes, but what
is this?
[all]
Normal!
Now I have to wonder
how you treat our nature.
And how you treat our
environment.
This is clearly a
multi-component waste.
Waste paper,
waste metal,
and waste string.
And you wanted to
dispose of all this together?
Hm?
Yes, and now?
Now you are missing the three disposal
units for waste paper, waste metal, and waste string.
It would be great, of course, if you had the three
natural, full-value buckets made of ore metal for this.
And what a coincidence, I happen
to have a complete set with me.
[light music]
Heavy as new,
here!
[Clatter]
All you have to do is
label it! [metallic clatter]
Great!
[Clatter]
But,
Otto?
About the money for the buckets, could
we maybe offset that with the milk?
Yes, of course!
The milk
for the cocoa!
[Child's voice] But when
will we finally have cocoa?
-I want my cocoa too!
-Me too!
Watch out!
Then the little lamb asks the big lamb,
"Shall we tidy up our stable?"
And what does
the big lamb say?
[all]
Nöö!
And the little lamb asks further,
"Shall we brush our fleece?"
[all]
Nöö!
...says then the big lamb.
And the little
lamb asks, "So,
what do you want then?"
-Cocoa! Cocoa!
-Otto is coming right away!
And brings us
our milk.
[Joyful music]
Fast as the wind!
[Tire squealing]
Yes, I brake
for women too.
Please.
[Honking]
And?
[Whistling]
[Engine starts]
[ Bus stop ]
Yes, that's how you make
friends, through helpfulness,
attention,
and kindness.
No wonder I'm quite popular in
my home country, I dare say, or?
There he is!
Extremely popular!
Madness!
-I want an autograph!
-Me too!
[Wild trampling]
Mama!
[Paper rustling]
[Handbrake screeches]
[Door slams]
[Otto groans]
Careful, step.
[Door squeaks]
Tatadada!
[Alle]
Otto! Cocoa!
Now you're getting
your cocoa!
Can you tell them the
story of the little lambs?
I'm at the part where the
caterpillar tells what it can turn into.
My favorite part.
Hello, little weasel.
Well? Well? Just say
something to the children!
Well? WELL?
Is your weasel sometimes
also so lazy?
And so tired?
Yes, downright
sluggish?
There's now the new
Weaselquick for that.
Yes, Weaselquick makes
your weasel quick too!
Tail up, zip,
Weaselquick on, zap...
Otto, you're telling the
story of the caterpillar?
So, says the little caterpillar to
the two lambs [ominous music]
"Now you should get to
know me, because I
am Galaxor, the
intergalactic
monster hunter, ha ha!
And I'm looking for the
biggest danger in our universe."
Then the silicon mountain split open, and out
stepped the most terrifying creature in our star system.
[Grunting noises]
Ui, ui, ui, ui!
Lilo!
Tiffi! Mr.
von Bödefeld?
Ui, ui, ui, ui!
Galaxor unsheathes
his laser cannon!
I will show you now how
much I love you, little caterpillar.
You are allowed to sit on my
nose, then we will hop through
the grass, and then I
will tell you that you are now ripe.
I'll blow your brains out!
[Otto makes shooting
and fighting noises]
[Scream]
Look,
the caterpillar that
transforms itself
into a
butterfly, into a
swallowtail.
[Excited hustle and bustle]
And how to swallow a tail, that
I'll explain to you next time.
[Cups clinking]
Frauke, I have a good
feeling, it will happen tonight.
-What?
-I have prepared a surprise.
A little soup:
Slurp, slurp, slurp.
Then a few bites:
Chomp, chomp, chomp.
Then a little: blab, blab, blab. You
don't mind a conversation, do you?
-Yes, where?
-At my place!
Oh, Otto.
-Oh Frauke, come on!
-But not in Benno's Tower.
Why Benno's Tower?
Because it still belongs to
Benno, your older brother.
And because everything
reminds me of him.
His style, his taste,
his sense of beauty.
And the whole well-kept atmosphere.
I promise you, nothing will be left
of it," nothing will remind you of him.
I swear to you, I will
erase Benno from our lives.
[Sighing]
Nevertheless
[Deep breath.]
So, you think, that I'm someone like Benno,
would take advantage of the situation, and here, and there..
Otto please, not in
front of the children!
So you think I'm someone
who would do that, thank you.
Please stop with the jokes.
So are you coming?
Yes.
-Do you swear?
-Yes.
The Frisian oath?
It's fine by me.
[Otto's happy noises]
[Chirping]
[Splashing]
Hm, Frauke will be pleased with that.
A soup - the Friesian way.
And now we tear a banana its virgin peel
from its body and crush the still twitching flesh!
Now we strike behind, an
unsuspecting cabbage head, on the skull!
A little oil,
for the last anointing.
Ha ha!
A handful of chickpeas,
[Giggling]
Add a shot of curry.
[Loud crash]
[Coughing]
Now I'll try...
[Slurping]
[Sharp exhale]
[Clearing throat]
We pour the whole thing under
constant stirring into the sink.
[Clattering]
Maybe Frauke
doesn't like soup either.
I still have
my hearty salad.
[Harp tones]
Och, Schildi!
That's Frauke's salad!
But you would be
quite good for the soup.
Ah yes, you are
Benno's toad.
Benno...
[Pop music starts]
Nothing shall remind you of Benno anymore.
Who likes to remember
the insignificant older
brothers, of significantly smaller
brothers, uh,
uh, more important, smaller brothers anyway.
Nothing shall remind you
of him anymore.
[Otto whistles]
[Doorbell rings]
[Wood creaks]
[Otto whistles]
[Rumbling on the stairs]
Moin!
We are the new neighbors, so
there's something to drink today.
We want to celebrate our
neighborhood as good Frisians.
We came here on
foot, now we want
to buy one [clinking]
[Paper rustling]
...drink.
Did you just say
something about buying?
No no, drink.
Come in, come in.
[Crashing] But
really, just for drinking!
No no sir, you said something
about buying right there.
And then you're exactly right with me.
How about an East Frisian phone?
Hello Mommy, Daddy,
oh,  busy.
We actually had
something bigger in mind.
Something bigger?
Moment.
Hello Mommy, Daddy.
We'd like to buy your land.
How?
My land?
My tower?
My home?
Gentlemen, a Frisian never
separates from his land.
For money, pah!
-We thought about 250,000.
-Where do I have to sign?
[Rustling of paper]
Hereby acquires the
company Highspeed Unlimited all
property and
usage rights for the construction of a
test track for testing the high-speed glider
"Tempo 1000".
Wait, there was just talk of 250,000!
Yes yes, I will insert the
purchase price now, 250,000!
[Bell rings]
Go on,
write!
[Bell rings again]
-Who is it?
-Who should that be?
Traveling people,
beggars, peddlers. Write!
[Bell rings faster]
Write, I
will take care of it.
[Crashing]
Unbelievable,
Here I gat a unique chance to
do a bogus sale
and some people come at the best time
for the conclusion of a contract...
[door bell]
I can't believe this, this has to be...
Otto. I'm sorry. It's a bit late...
What do you want here?
We have a date.
Where?
Here' at your place.
That doesn't work for me at all today.
Otto, what is going on here?
[inaudible whispering]
You?
[steps]
[creaking]
Gentlemen, you bought this lighthouse from this man?
Indeed, if you don't mind...?
This lighthouse doesn't belong to this man.
The rightful owner is his brother,
Benno. And he would never sell.
Isn't that right, Otto?
Eh, Benno? Benno?
Never heard the name.
Otto, stop the nonsense.
That's what I promised,
there's no Benno with us.
Forget what you promised,
and finally tell the truth.
But I don't know any Benno, I hear
the name for the first time, how was that?
Benni? Bennu?
Benno?
Hears like a dog's name!
Benno! Bow-wow!
I know what you promised, but it's about
something more important, our homeland.
Otto, I beg you.
Otto!
[Bang, then creaking]
Oh Schildi, you traitor!
Oh, if you mean my
brother Benno,
okay, of course,
he was here, but he's
now in America,
in the land of unlimited vanity.
Then we can tear up
the contract. Yes, ok.
Are you crazy? It can
become legally binding quickly.
Wait and see first, what
the boss thinks about it.
Oh, yes.
[inaudible whispering]
[Pub chatter]
In the book of the Frisians it says:
The Frisian drinks little, but often,
and then a lot.
Frieda, this coffee
was a bit too cold.
If you want something warm,
then you have to order a beer.
-You're in for one!
-And who gets the other?
[dirty laughter] That
hasn't changed to this day.
Except that he might
drink a little more today.
[Glasses clink]
[Total silence]
[Piano sounds]
[Silence again]
[startled inhalation]
[Coin clattering]
[Coin hits the slot]
[Pop music starts playing]
[Murmuring in the crowd]
[Accordion playing]
[Otto sings] Tiny little schnapps,
silent, still, and neat.
Better not to drink them,
knock you off your feet.
Great big mugs of beer,
golden, cold, and bright.
Keep them at a distance,
or you're out tonight.
Brimming, brimming glasses,
are you thinking clear?
Don't believe the stories,
knock it back - cheers!
[Crowd cheers]
Yes!
[The crowd cheers loudly]
[Normal pub noises]
Wait a minute, Pastor.
Well, what do
we have here?
[Glasses clink]
Spade uh...
-And?
-Spade uh...
[Porcelain clinks]
Seven...
Spade seven!
[Screaming]
Hey!
-What's that?
-Wait, you don't hit a man with glasses.
You don't have
glasses on.
I'll get some quickly.
[Porcelain clinks]
Frieda!
A bottle of the best,
for me and my friends.
Hehe, thank goodness
I don't have one.
[Laughing]
But I'll be back on my feet soon.
Give it here, cheers!
This has to be celebrated.
So, may I congratulate you?
Have you inherited,
Baron?
Much better, Herr Assessor, I am
selling the inheritance of my niece.
[Laughing]
[Soft laughter]
Uncle, I want to know everything
about your shady dealings now.
That's none of your business, whether
I sell to Highspeed or anyone else.
Highspeed, some
multinational corporation.
-A nasty company.
-Exactly.
And what they have planned for
our country doesn't interest you?
Ah, the people
have money, that's enough.
They have money,
I can confirm that.
Who needs
this Highspeed nonsense anyway?
[Approving murmur]
Let's ask the majority.
Imagine,
gracious lady, you get
in here at 8 o'clock
you are
in Paris at 9 o'clock.
Paris?
What am I supposed to do
in Paris?
What about my crabs then?
They have to be eaten by
noon, they taste best when fresh.
Well then, get back in then, and
"zack" you are home again an hour later.
Home, that's nice.
Where do I sign?
You see, gentlemen?
That is the proof.
What is all this supposed to mean?
Without Benno's
property, nothing runs here.
And you, you stay
on your land.
Wait and see, wait and see!
Your clean Benno skipped town
a year ago.
He didn't care a whit
about his country.
What rights does he even have
left?
And what about
my customary right?
I go there, I live there,
I heat there,
Go-Live-Heat Right!
[cheerful Quieklaut]
And I have rights too.
[sad music]
271 Marks
and 30 Pfennigs!
They're still open,
since Benno's farewell party.
Exactly... eleven endless months
[Sighing]
and three long weeks.
Thank you Frieda, thank you.
Then this Benno has
precisely one week,
to reclaim his land.
And, as the
old Frisian law prescribes,
through planting a tree
by one's own hand.
I've never heard of that.
Where does it say that?
So it says, black on white,
in the book of the Frisians.
[surprised sigh]
And further the
book says: "If the homeland
is
threatened, only one can help in times of need.
A young man, noble,
pure and good,
with brown hair,
and great courage."
Great, I'm
out of this one.
And there will never
be one like that here.
[Dirty laugh]
Psst, they're going to make out
right now.
[Giggling]
He doesn't want to make out.
- Maybe he can't?
- Everyone can do that.
Not now, they're not
making out again today.
[Disappointed sigh]
After all, she was with him
yesterday.
What did they do
then?
Probably just chatted
again.
What are they always chatting about?
As it happens, I can
read lips.
And therefore I can tell you
that Frauke
demands Otto to
save the homeland immediately.
That's totally
uncool.
Der da
shall save the homeland?
He can't even make out.
If she kisses him, he will
certainly get an organism.
Frauke, you don't believe
what people say
about us, that I am only marrying you because
you inherit a fortune from your uncle, do you?
I would marry you even if you
inherited the fortune from someone else.
Besides, we
love each other platonically.
And if it's a boy, he shall
be named Plato, yes?
Otto please, it's about
our homeland, our future.
Future?
You know what is in
the book of the Frisians.
Benno must plant the tree
within at most four days.
Then the land is ours.
Our country, our home,
our child.
And we call
the child not Plato.
We call it
after our grandfather.
Ah no,
then he would be called Grandpa.
Yes, but first Benno
has to plant the little tree.
You have to go.
Okay.
I'm going into town.
[Car door opens]
[Car door slams] And I'll
take a look at the place.
[Cheerful music]
[Engine noises]
[Children's groans]
Now he's gone.
It's pointless, I think he
won't learn it anymore.
[Music gets louder]
[Engine noise]
[Ominous tone]
[Music continues]
[Car door slams]
"Highspeed Unlimited, we are hiring,
tree butcher, crusher, cement pourer.
We're clearing out forests,
rivers, all kinds of creatures."
But that's not nice,
no no!
If someone breaks something here,
then we ourselves.
After all, it's our home.
[electrical chirping]
[electronic door opening]
[softly]
Aha...
[No sound]
[No sound again]
[Bang]
[electrical chirping]
[electronic door opening]
[Footsteps echo]
The earth is loaned to us
but no one
said anything about returning it, tss...
[softly]
Hmm?
[Footsteps echo]
[Clinking of glasses]
-Where are we going?
-To
the executive floor.
The answer is correct.
[Elevator opens]
[Glasses clinking]
How long have you
been working for us,
tomorrow not
anymore counted in?
[Elevator doors close]
[Glasses clink]
HIGHSPEED UNLIMITED
[Music starts] [Glass clinks]
It's been
a few years since this
corporation shed its
good old
name, GViUZwB, Society for the
Destruction
of Intact Environment
and Destruction
of Valuable Building Stock.
We have reluctantly followed
the advice of our corporate psychologist,
[Loud glass clinks]
Highspeed Unlimited, that
sounds cooler,
more technical
-Pssst!
- and possibly more deceitful,
but gentlemen,
[loud clinking]
You are supposed to serve after
the presentation, are you deaf, man?
[more noises]
Say it.
Or are you mute?
[Approving noises]
All respect, a deaf and
dumb waiter, good for secrecy.
Excellent
service here.
[Loud clattering]
He's blind too.
-Better safe than sorry.
-Psst!
And now, ladies
and gentlemen,
I would like to present our
latest
project, Our high-speed
glider, Tempo 1000,
please follow me.
[quietly]
Champagne!
[Clinking]
-Brakes checked?
-In order.
-Flight recording?
-Off.
-Oxygen?
-In order.
-High-speed signifier?
-Tested -Secret signal? -On.
-Machines ready for start?
-Ready...
-Shield up?
-Up.
-Switches?
-Off.
-Scotch whisky?
-On the rocks.
-The pants? -Dirty.
-Laundry? -Clean.
-Asshole-
-Son of a bitch. -Confirmed!
Gentlemen, you are about to
witness a unique experiment.
This is the original model
of our planned test track.
Please memorize this
landscape well.
You will never see it in
this natural state again.
Highspeed guarantees that.
Our high-speed glider,
Speed 1000, ensures that.
Start the test run.
Please put on the
headphones and safety glasses.
[General dressing]
Prototype on start position.
[Click]
[electronic siren]
Ready for takeoff!
[Electric hum]
[Hum gets louder]
Ignition ready!
[Hum gets even louder]
Go!
[loud bang]
[loud hiss]
[Applause]
[Sizzling]
[Hissing]
[Clatter]
[Satisfied sigh]
Champagne!
An exceptionally
successful demonstration,
Mr. von Devil.
That was to be expected.
Isn't that harmful to people?
[Laughter]
Harmful? No.
Deadly!
[Giggles]
[Laughter]
[Clapping and laughter]
Champagne!
[Loud exhalation]
[very quietly]
Champagne.
[Loud exhalation]
[Music starts]
[Otto makes hissing noises]
[Sounds of a tower falling over]
[Drum roll music]
Are there any further
problems, Grödel?
There could be a problem with the owner of
that lighthouse there, he lives in Florida, but...
What, he's alive?
Does it have to be so?
Actually no, no.
Then initiate
the necessary.
Yes, sir.
What do you mean?
El Cucaracho.
[Whistling]
[Uptown music starts playing]
Boss! Overseas call.
It's the devil from Germany.
[Loud crackling]
-Hello?
-Hello, El Cucaracho.
We have
a small problem.
A man is giving us trouble,
his name is Benno Groß.
We are sending him tonight
to the Dirty Disco, 11:30 pm.
Identifying feature:
white glove.
Solve the problem
in your own way.
Should you fail,
we will deny knowing you.
This call will self-destruct
in a few seconds.
[Crackling]
[Boing!]
[Cheerful country music]
[Birds singing]
And that's what they want
to destroy.
How much I hate this kind
of people I can't even say.
Speaking of "hate", don't you feel like
coming over to my place tonight, and...
Otto please, you have to go to
Florida, you have to find Benno's house.
His last address.
-His last sign of life.
-Bookmark?
-Sign of life.
Ah.
But how are you going
to find the house?
Oh, I don't think it's
bad, looks like money.
I mean, how you
want to find the house.
How am I supposed to find a house?
It's easy,
they don't run away.
Don't worry,
I'll manage.
Otto, you are
Friesland's last hope.
[romantic music starts]
Oh!
[Kissing sounds]
Otto, you really
shouldn't have done that.
I have lost
control.
Oh, by the way, how does
one actually speak in America?
Well, American.
Aah!
My Name is Otto.
Take a car.
I'm hungry.
I am Hungarian.
I am thirsty.
I am Thursday.
Your American is perfect.
Thank you very much.
-We have to go.
-Oh yes.
-Do you want to go to Florida like that?
-Yes, it's supposed to be warm there.
And your luggage?
Toothpaste,
Toothbrush,
and
my Swiss pocket knife.
For shaving,
for manicuring,
and for massacring!
Otto, cut the jokes.
The last one turns off the light.
[Click.]
I'm so excited, I only
know America from video.
[Foot stomps]
Hey!
[Foot stomps on gravel]
[Finger snapping]
[rhythmic finger snapping]
[sings] You knock me
off my feet, now, baby.
Whoooo!
[Music starts]
Ha ha!
Uuh!
Woohoo.
Come on, girl!
Ah ah!
Juchhu!
[singt]
The way you make me feel.
[Chorus]
[Otto]
You really turn me on.
[Chorus]
[Otto]
You knock me off my feet, baby.
[Chorus]
You knock me off my feet.
[Otto]
My lonely days are gone.
[Otto imitates Tarzan yell]
[Turbine noises]
[Vacation music]
Peter, Paul and Mary,
are sitting in the kitchen.
(Peter, Paul und Maria
sit in prison)
Oh, the bell rings.
(Oh, der dog fights.)
Here is a letter
from America.
(here is a ladder from America)
America is a
terrible country.
So bad that I
don't leave the airport.
Why is that?
Miami has become so terribly
violent.
One murder every 21 seconds.
120 robberies per minute.
And the Black people,
they are all addicted.
And the drugs are
expensive, very expensive!
In order to be able to buy
them, they have to steal.
But I just want to
stay for a few hours.
But one second is enough
to be murdered!
And you only have one chance,
you have to be faster than the others.
That's why they are
all blocking over there.
You will see,
Florida is full of
big Black people,
with long
knives, who bring small, weak,
blonde, thin,
white people around the corner.
[Happy music]
[Traffic noises]
That, then, is America.
And here a murder is supposed
to happen every 20 seconds?
Then I'll have to
hurry.
[Traffic noise,
a lot of honking]
[Door slams shut]
Where do you want to go?
Voulez-vous coucher avec moi?
(Do you want to sleep with me?)
What?
Oh, uh, sorry,
wrong page.
You have a very beautiful body.
(You have a very nice bathroom.)
Come on man, I don't got all day,
Where do you want to go?
I'm looking for my brother
Benno, he's supposed to live here.
You sure?
Yes, I have shoes.
[Upbeat music]
Oh, there's music in the air.
(There is music in the eggs.)
[Upbeat music]
[singing]
For the first time in the new world,
I'm excited to see if I like it.
The streets are flat,
and the houses are tall,
that looks
just like Friesland!
[Police siren]
Even here the cops make noise,
that will wake up all the chickens.
The crab boats are in the harbor,
the fishermen are probably already asleep.
And when the fishermen
have rested for a while,
then their wives have work to do.
There they are,
in their traditional attire,
-Hey, baby! What do you want?
-Come on, honey, let's go!
How wonderful that you're
so diligent.
Excuse me, where is the Church?
(Where is George?)
Is this Arnold Schwarzenegger?
(Are those all illegal workers?)
[Brakes screech]
[Loud exhale]
Listen, man!
You don't talk about my people!
I do the driving,
And you shut up!
Shut up?
Wait.
[Paper rustling]
(Shadow off.)
[quietly]
What does that mean?
[Loud exhale]
[Engine starts, howls]
What the Hell?
(Was zum Teufel?)
Why are we stopping?
Goes it not weiter?
[Door closes]
Shit, fucking car!
Shit, fucking car?
Moment.
(Beautiful, sparkling car.)
[Upbeat music Music]
[Door slams shut]
Hey, Mister Black and Decker!
[Gunshots]
Stop, stop, uh,
sorry, uhm, Mr. Refugee,
I have a question, excuse me.
Do you know where that is?
Cut, Cut!
(Schnitt, Schnitt!)
Who the hell is that guy?!
We start again!
Get that fucking guy out of here!
Aah, hier wird gefilmt,
Miami Vice.
Wollte ich immer schon
kennen lernen.
-Tag Herr Miami, Tag Herr Vice.
-Hello.
In need information
I search this house.
Ah. that's the Graf’s Villa,
right over there. [shot]
Ah, thank you.
Miami Vice, huiuiui...
That guy is crazy.
I mix up reality and realness.
Let's shoot it again.
That won't happen a second time.
[leise] Next time, I will be better prepared.
That can't be true.
Have I been lucky!
I could really use a rubber band right now.
Ts ts ts...
[Music resumes]
[Clinking metal]
Ahem,
Ho ho ho!
Three sinister fellows are
blocking my way, Help, help.
But a Frisian heart
knows no fear.
Therefore I stand up
to the dark rabble.
[Police siren]
[Metal fence clatters]
Not so hard, I have it
with my back.
You see this Messer?
That's not a knife!
That is a knife.
[Snip]
[Snap]
Where's the Stuff?
The cloth?
I'm wearing it.
Here's the cloth.
Well, I'm gonna kill this son of a...
Hey!
Moment, Moment!
That's going too far now.
Or is this here
not a movie?
[sad sigh]
Mom, I had a
terrible dream.
Imagine,
I dreamt
that I was in
America, and I was mugged.
And the one holds
a knife to my throat.
No, my boy, I have
to disappoint you.
This is a dream, you are
still in America and
have a knife at your throat.
[Harpsichord music]
You are finish!
No, no, I'm not finnish.
I am Frisian.
I'm gonna kill you right now!
Oh yes, please.
Hey man, stop!
He's a friend of Steffi Graf!
Oh Lord, I almost killed a friend of Steffi
Graf! (Oh, Gott! Ich hätte ihn fast getötet.)
-Really?
-Yeah man!
-Graf Steffi? Nie gehört.
-Good Job, man!
Ähm, I must loose now.
I must go there.
Wait, you cannot go like this to Steffi Graf.
Give him a jacket.
(Gebt ihm eine Jacke.)
-I don't know who you mean, but...
-Friend of Steffi Graf is our Friend!
Nice guys!
First service, man, first service!
First serve, man, first serve!
[Otto chuckles] Nice! Yeah!
Graf Steffi,
and Prince Service.
Benno therefore moves
in the best circles, typical.
[Rattling of the gate]
[Tennis sounds...]
[Music starts]
[metallic sound]
Benno?
[Tennis sounds continue]
[Rattling of the fence]
[Whistle]
[Otto whistles etc.]
[Fence rattling]
[Otto screams]
[Loud crash]
Hey,
Hold on a minute!
Tell me, who
are you?
Yeah, who are you?
You're doing this
amazingly well, you.
if you practice diligently,
you'll go far.
-Do you think so?
-Yes, but be careful, you're holding that thing completely wrong.
I'll show you, this is
how you have to hold it.
[Scratching]
And afterwards
string change, right?
Exactly,
you have to be careful.
You mustn't hit those things
so hard.
Because they feel pain,
like us humans.
Be careful!
[Thumping]
[distorted voice]
Ouch!
-Crazy!
-Isn't it?
Oh, I'm looking for my brother,
Benno Groß, do you know him?
[Romantic music]
Actually, I find
him quite nice.
Actually, she is right.
I can't imagine that he could be
Benno's brother, that conceited guy.
Ah, she knows Benno!
Yes, I know him.
He once
worked for us.
Doesn't he live here anymore? That's annoying, he's
supposed to save our homeland, that's why I'm here.
- Hogwash.
- Speaking of Hogwash!
Do you know a sentence with
the words "malarkey" and "hogwash"?
Animals are key to a successful farm,
but the hog was missing.
The new coach talks too much.
Kick the guy out.
I'm from Friesland, by the way.
And I need to know, where Benno
lives, because I uh... Hey! What? Where?
You wanted to tell me
where Benno lives?
That he's supposed to be
Benno's brother, hogwash.
That's nice of you,
to carry me.
That reminds me of the following.
One said, "I was
very intelligent,
I walked already with one year old."
Says the other, "that's stupid, I
let myself carry until the 7th year."
Haha, great joke, right? Haha.
[Otto screams]
[harsh impact tones]
Now I will probably never
find out where Benno lives.
[Bouncing of a tennis ball]
Benno. 122nd Street Northeast.
[Happy music]
That's strong!
[Tennis noises]
She's still holding that thing the wrong way around,
she'll never learn it.
Thanks!
And don't forget the words of
the Chinese Ping Pong.
What did he say?
Uhm..
[unintelligible Chinese]
And what does that mean?
I don't know,
I can't speak Chinese.
So, goodbye!
Ciao!
[Otto screams]
[Fence rattling]
The address is right,
but no Benno Groß.
Detective Big Ben.
Hm...
Well, maybe he
can help me further.
[Phone rings]
- Detective Agency Big Ben?
- Hm?
- Am I speaking to Benno Groß?
- Hmhm!
- In person?
- Hm!
- We have a small problem!
- Hm?
- And an assignment for you!
- Hm!
- It's about adultery.
- Hmhmhmhm!
[Upbeat music]
[Footsteps]
Don't disturb, beauty sleep.
Do not disturb,
Mummy is sleeping.
[Otto giggles]
[Door creaks]
-I repeat.
-Hmhm!
-11:30 PM!
-Dirty Disco!
-Hmhm!
-White gloves!
-Hm!
Ah, sorry, excuse me, I'm
looking for a Benno Groß.
-Hm?
-End.
Benno Groß?
Interesting.
What does he look like?
Certainly not an average guy, right?
No, there are said to be
hundreds of such people.
Unfortunately, there are thousands of them.
Please describe the man.
Well, uhm, medium height,
-medium weight, -Aha.
-Average, side part,
-Huh?
[Suspenseful music]
Benno!
Otto!
[Creaking]
[Back patting]
You, in Florida, here?
Fresh from Friesland,
my God, the old homeland.
I have a thousand
questions for you.
First question, how do
you like my new haircut?
No idea, I'm just glad to have found
you, you have to go home immediately.
My home is here.
Your home maybe,
but not your homeland.
And that one is in danger, it needs you.
Beautiful homeland, that
rejects one like a mangy dog.
Just because one has paid
attention to their appearance.
Benno, you are the only one
who can save the homeland.
Can I?
The homeland can 'kiss my ass'!
You have to save the homeland!
[Clatter]
I have to?
Yes.
Remember.
You swore it.
Then, at the old lighthouse.
When we both smoked
the holy eel together.
[Harp sounds]
The Frisian oath knows no haste,
the Frisian oath has a thousand parts.
Therefore we swear in the old way,
by Störtebeker's red beard!
[Together]
What has been in
Friesland shall be healed by the
Frisian way of life, with the scrubber
and the broom, on the dyke and under the counter.
[Giggling]
[Together]
Whoever catches this eel once will never be
hated again in Kral,
to whom we will give a beautiful scarf.
Whoever wants to learn the Frisian oath in its entirety,
let him read in the book of the Frisians, page 3 to 321.
That’s why we swear, once and for all,
the Frisian oath by the holy eel’s call.
My God, were we young.
But you're right.
I have to go home.
Plant a tree.
Save the homeland.
-But when?
-Yes, immediately!
You must catch the evening
flight, here is your ticket.
Impossible, I have an
appointment this evening.
I just took
the order.
-Why, what is it about?
-Adultery.
I'll do that for you,
it's my specialty.
I break the marriages
of the proudest women.
You scoundrel adulterer,
what are you doing in my bed?
You shall not break
until you feel sick.
[Otto shoots
from a pistol]
Otto, stop the jokes.
I have to be at the
Dirty Disco by 11:30 pm.
Okay!
I have to shadow a man,
because I run a shadowy business.
-What does the man look like?
-Three things I know: He wears a white glove.
He will meet a woman at some point.
And he will break up a marriage.
-His or hers?
-That doesn't matter.
The photo is what counts!
[Camera hums]
Got it!
Do you even know how to
behave in an American disco?
How to communicate
with each other?
Because of the loud music
there's body language.
I'll show you, sit down.
[Pop music plays]
For example, the female signals
her willingness to dance like this.
That means,
I'd like a beer.
I'm really into you!
And that,
I gotta to... very urgently.
And so, too late.
Benno, I'll take care of
that for you.
But not in the elevator.
And don't forget, white
glove on the right hand!
And don't forget,
to save your homeland.
[Engine noises] And be
careful with my convertible!
I know my way around
such cars.
Ha ha!
[Music starts playing]
[Door slams shut]
[Bang]
[Tires screeching]
[Music plays - MIAMI VICE theme song]
[Bang]
[Honking]
You motherfucker, son of a bitch!
Ah, Hello!
[Bang]
Dirty Disco, 11:30 PM.
He has to be here,
the glovebreaker with the white geart.
Erm, the heartbreaker with the white glove.
[Loud disco music]
But how can one find a man
with a white glove in this noise?
One can't even understand one's
own thoughts in this hustle and bustle.
I have to proceed systematically.
But where should I start?
I know...
I'll start with the hands.
[Loud disco music...]
Down here
no one wears gloves either.
There's only the Frisian
primal scream method.
[Otto] Hey!
[All] Hey!
[Otto] Heyhey!
[All] Heyhey!
[Otto] Hey!
[All] Hey!
[Silence]
[Music slowly starts again]
[Music continues playing normally]
[Knock knock]
[Whistle]
Excuse me?
(Excuse me?)
Ah, can you,
erm, fire me?
[Pfeifton 'La Cucaracha']
[Ominous music]
[Camera whirs]
If they've read this
card, I'm already gone.
So, everything under control,
everything running according to plan.
Now I just have to catch him breast-handed.
Uh, crotch him red-handed.
Handle the breasts with my crotch.
Exactly.
I have to kill someone,
be right back.
-Okay.
[Door slams shut]
[Engine starts]
Now he's driving to his
love nest, this adulterer.
[Car door slams]
Well, who lives here?
[still exciting music]
[Tape is played]
[Sound: moaning women]
[Chair squeaks]
Such a pig!
In Benno's office.
[Camera clicks, whirs]
Mister Van Devil, please.
El Cucaracha.
Everything under control.
What?
That's supposed to be adultery?
Beginner.
Everything is going according to plan.
Tonight, he's dead.
[Paper shuffling]
[Incomprehensible muttering]
Tonight, he's dead.
(Tonight I will be a dad.)
Will I be a father?
Frauke!
That can't be right.
We only have sex
with our eyes.
Then I must have had
stalk eyes.
[Giggling]
Again.
Tonight, he's dead.
Tonight I am dead.
Aha.
[Exciting music builds up]
[Crash]
[Exciting music plays]
[Wild stomping]
[Gunshots]
[Boing!]
[Electronic melody]
Hallo Otto.
I'm sorry, but my sniffing sensors indicate
that you are about to soil yourself in fear.
May I therefore ask you to
please use the taxi over there?
Good luck with your escape.
Thank you.
[electrical buzzing]
[Door slams shut]
[suspenseful music continues]
Drive away!
Quick, quick, quick,
uh, hurry, hurry, hurry.
[loud sniffing]
Oh no! Not you again!
Out!
[Ominous music]
Nice to meet you.
(Nice to rent you)
[Whistling]
Do you want to lunch with me?
(Do you want to lynch me?)
I... professional.
Don't worry, over soon.
It doesn't hurt.
What you are doing will
have political consequences.
In Germany, we have many politicians.
(In Germany we have many policewomen.)
By the way, a policewoman goes to the doctor and
says, my foot has fallen asleep, will it be awake all night?
[Clattering] Or: A policewoman goes to the
pharmacy, do you have anything against headaches?
The pharmacist replies, why should I have
something against it? I live off of it.
[Click]
[Hissing]
Hasta la Vista!
(See you later!)
Don't worry, be happy!
What the hell is this?
[Whistling]
[Hissing]
Hey, Mr. Killer, you forgot something! Your tubes!
Or are they
for me?
Hey, the whole gift load is going to burn up here!
I can't guarantee anything, hello!
[Door slams shut]
[Hissing]
WATER
[Toy engine noise]
[Boing, boing...]
[Electrical hum]
[Rattling]
[Music becomes more suspenseful]
[Thud]
[Air escapes]
[Crash]
[Loud explosion]
[Sighing]
My God,
what do you look like?
Hopefully nothing happened to you?
Unfortunately, yes.
Man has me on the
airport toilet attacked.
A Black man?
A negro?
Bavarian.
[Mouth harp music]
In the book of the Frisians
it
is written, whether north,
south, west, east, home is
still "eastest"!
And "eastest of all" has it naturally the
rescuer when he finally returns home.
[Applause]
-Nothing has changed here!
-Have you ever been here before?
-Yes!
-Then be glad that
you can still recognize our beautiful
East Frisia.
-Why?
-That went through the world press.
It was in all the newspapers.
In Aurich, in Emden, in äh...
Empty. Give me a new bottle, old woman.
Old drunkard!
-Heh!
-It was in all the newspapers?
Yes, they wanted to make
everything here completely flat.
-Even flatter?
-Hmhm!
As on the moon, scorched earth,
this is how it should look.
-And who prevented that?
-Yes, guess who.
-I know!
-One of us.
A Frisian. Strong,
Young,
nice,
Yes, just like me.
Haha, that I don't laugh!
Be calm down there, I knew him.
- Ah, you know him?
- Heh!
He asks if I don't
know our savior.
Do I know him, or
don't I know him?
No, where from?
Now listen to this,
something so ungrateful.
Then you ask your wife something
and then she also
answers right away.
As if I don't know
my best friend.
Where they are standing now,
he always used to sit there.
Also, at home
with me on the sofa.
Then we always drank tea.
You haven't drunk any
tea in your whole life!
That's proof,
because he always drank everything.
-Oh, just stop it!
-I was like family to him.
So are we East Frisians,
three things are important to us.
Cleanliness, Honesty, [Hicks!]
Sobriety,
and family values.
-That were four!
-Be quiet!
Get to work!
What is that back there?
That? That's the horizon.
Ah, are we that far already?
I'll show you something,
hard to starboard!
[Folk music]
There's something exciting
and interesting to see there.
A beautiful picture
of Frisian justice.
So they all end
here, these criminals.
Also, if there's one thing
we can't stand in Friesland,
then that is pollution.
[Splashing]
And these guys wanted
to destroy our homeland.
[Metal clattering]
[Language in
Choir] Organic or normal!
choir] Organic or normal!
[Rustling]
- Organic?
- Or
- normal?
Or!
Homeland! Your savior is here!
You, the savior?
And who then is that?
[Fanfare music]
Is the homeland threatened?
Only one helps in need.
Benno the Great,
Savior of the Homeland.
[Rustling garbage]
[Oppressive music]
Homeland.
[Sigh] Beautiful home.
He receives some
like a mangy dog.
Just because one has once
done something outer-Frisian.
Home can kiss my ass.
Frauke! You
haven't forgotten me.
And you really
thought of everything.
Even fresh laundry!
Everything lovingly prepared!
[Sighing] Surely the
kettle is on inside.
The television stands
steaming on the stove
and then we'll play "Trick-Track".
Whoever gets the trick,
grabs their partner by the track!
[Giggling] [Door slams shut]
[Steps creak]
For Benno, from Fra...
[A woman's voice sings]
Frauke?
[same female voice]
Otto, I haven't seen
you in a long time.
I have a thousand questions for
you, what do you think of my hairstyle?
This is Brett, the new forward
hairstyle, from 'Glashart'.
Yes, Brett creates hairstyles,
that you can rely on.
As sun protection...
[click] [Harp tones]
As a roof against rain...
[klimpern] [Water splashing]
And essential
at every standing party.
Awesome Benno,
but, you live here now?
As an honorary citizen?
My honor!
Achse, you live
together with Fr...
Old love doesn't rust.
Have you got them...?
[Kissing sounds]
Hmhm!
And also...? [more
smooching noises]
And also...?
Ask her yourself! Darling?
There I am, Darling.
May I introduce you
to my little brother Otto?
Ah, Frieda, I'm so glad to
find you so fresh and cheerful.
My darling, hi Otto, your
styling product is ready.
It is an intense toning lotion.
from burdock root starch,
and Glycitin asbestos.
This gives your hair
fashionably strong hold
and brilliant shine,
all day long!
Thank you, darling!
[Spraying noises]
Wait, you're spraying, and
what about the ozone hole?
[Spray]
That's what I sprayed
this morning already.
Well, then have fun
firming up. Where is my hat?
Thanks, Schildi.
[Cheerful music]
You look good.
Lost a bit of weight.
Goodbye.
[Sprays]
[Spray]
[Door closes softly]
[Whistles 'La Cucaracha']
[Weapon loads]
-Now it's your turn!
-We're making out today, man!
[Romantic music]
[Sighing]
So?
[Children's laughter]
Our home,
our country,
our future,
our children.
Kids? Let's get
started right away!
-Otto please!
-Yes?
One thing you have to
promise me from now on.
And what would that be?
Please no more jokes.
I promise you that.
One more I have! A
man comes to the doctor,
says, every time I do
that it hurts awfully then,
says the doctor,
don't to that.
Then let's take a
look in our wallet,
there's a 500 Deutschmark
bill growing there.
He must be removed operatively.
Sister, tongs, Panties!
The doctor to the patient:
"I can't find anything.
It has to be the alcohol"
The patient: "Ok, then I come
back when you are sober."
Two young men who are
attaching the exterior plaster,
and suddenly the
scaffolding collapses.
Both fall down, one is
smashed on the ground,
the other was lucky, he was
stuck with his eye on the nail.
Give me a cigarette, my
pack is still in the machine.
Please, please,
you are wrong! she cried,
Her eyes were filled with fear.
Please, please don't!
But it was too late, he had
already put on the Heino record.
Aunt, I shot my arrow into
your garden, can I get it back?
But gladly, where is
he then? In your cat!
I'm constantly on the go, constantly
stressed, never at home, and everywhere
and privately there's nothing going
on anymore, when I'm at airports
if I wasn't constantly searched for weapons,
I would have no sex life anymore.
Mrs. Krueger, for 6 years
you have lived by the highway,
is there any	subsequent damage?
Noooo! Nooooo! Noooo! Noooo!
Now don't clap
that bad air in here.
At the drive-in theater recently
two best friends froze to death.
They wanted to see the film "Closed for the Winter".
Every Thursday, all members
of the Otto Fan Club meet
in the phone booth.
My aunt said my birth would be a
contribution to environmental pollution.
She caught me then, when
the doctor let me fall laughing.
I had big ears, I stayed
inside during rabbit hunts.
Liver to brain, where's the
alcohol, I have nothing to do here!
Holladihitti, Holladihitti!
Hello, Echo! Hello, Otto!
-You, Susi?
-Hey, who's that?
I, your hairdryer.
-You, Dad?
-Yeah, my child?
-What are you doing all day?
-Driving a tractor!
Okay, okay, okay,
I've got one more!
Hey, you're not
paying attention at all!
Of course I'll watch out!
-No, you are not watching over it!
-Yes, I am watching over it!
-How many children do you have?
-Six! -See, you can't keep up with them!
Hello, Mister Vegetable.
Good day, Mr. Kohl.
-Do you understand me?
-I understand you very well.
No, you cannot understand me.
-Yes, very good even.
-No, no one can understand me.
Cheers... Cheers...
Fascinating, how I have
the masses in my hand.
[Crowd laughs and applauds]