(Rooster screaming)
Ha! Holla-di-hitti!
Aha!
Can anyone see me?
Can anyone hear me?
I am in a state of distress at sea!
Yes! That means,
You can see me.
But I cannot see you.
Distress, SOS!
Eat, Ear, Eat!
But, dear brothers and sisters,this raises the
question, an Otti alone on the sea?How is that possible?
Well, it's a long story,I'll
tell you from the beginning.
From the beginning I
created Heaven and Earth...
(Thunderclaps)Excuse me, excuse me,
I know,that was another one, good enough, good enough.
The whole misfortune began with
my birthin my Frisian homeland.
That's my family home.
Isn't it nice, Isn't it
wonderful-wonderfully beautiful?
That's my grandfather, isn't he majestic?
Isn't he wonderful-wonderfully beautiful?
And that are my parents, They
loved me like their own son.
Isn't he adorable? And his little feet, Are
they not wonderful-wonderfully beautiful?
Look at this, Heinz!
Well, I suppose,
compared to his face...
(Flute music in the background)
My father. He always wanted my
best, And that was my allowance.
And that's grandfather, isn't
he... Oh, we've already had that.
(The rocking chair creaks)
Huh, Mutti's smallest one,
That's me.
And what's behind is my mother.
It was bound to us by the
strongest tie,—the mother's love.
Oh dear, Mother, I'm really
big enough, I can eat alone!
Oh little Ottili can eat
alone? Then try it anyway!
Uh! Uh! Uh! Uh! Uh! Uh!
Eating alone, yes yes...
One for Aunt Lisbeth!
One for Uncle Karl.
One for Aunt Anna.
-One for Grandpa!
-My mother...
She made it hard to let her go.
-One for Grandma.
But now was the right moment.
I had to leave immediately
from these conditions!
A man like me
belongs there, where
big money is made.
A man like me...
But have I already
imagined that?
My name is Otto. (Loud slurping)
(Jazz music...)
(Ship horn)
(Footsteps... traffic noise)
Let's get started from there!
(Jazz music...)
(Traffic noise... U-Bahn sounds)
That was it, the big city.
Wasn't it huge? Didn't
she look incredible?
Here you had everything.
But also problems.
I already had three of those.
I had no job. No money.
No idea how to go on.
No job? No money? No idea,
how it goes on? No problem!
(The Door creaks)
(Whispering) Hello.
Now, little one?
No job? No money?
No idea how to go on?
You're just right for me.
Here's your contract.
(Paper shredder)
Contract. By accepting this contract, I
confirm the receipt of a large amount of money.
In exchange, I am
committed to... (mumbles)
Ah, the fine print you
should not read, my friend.
-But why not?
-It's bad for the eyes.
-Ah, yes, that's
great. Yes, and now?
Now?
Now I get another beautiful,
Good readable
signature of yours.
Oh, that's fine,
I'd do it gladly.
(paper rustle, ominous creepy music)
(Foamy water splashing,
White whale film soundtrack)
Signature!
Young friend.
Ah, yes, of course, Otherwise
it would be a headline.
Otto? Otto...who?
Only Otto. My parents were so
poor, we couldn't afford a surname.
Oh, you see me crying.
But these times
are now really over.
Your money.
Wow, so much! Not quite.
Because they are going off:
Work processing fee,
Stamp money.
Yes, and then
another,<br /(laughs)
And then of course
my loyalty bonus.
-Yes but that's all for me.
-Yes.
For you, and your small business.
And if I might still
give you some good advice,
be successful!
That's a good tip,
I'll remember it.
Have you already thought of
a name for your firm?<
Yes, umm, OSSl.
Otti's Super Service international.
Oh.
(Amenaz-ing Music)
I will remember it.
So, with my new
start-up capital I felt it.
The world lay at my feet.
Hello, Taxi!
(Braking noises)
Three things are what make
the great entrepreneur stand out.
The use of mobile technology,
The unconditional will,to
come all the way up.
And the ambitious build-up
of a large customer base.
Just three months after founding my
company, I also met the last condition.
I was expecting my first customer.
I WAS EXPECTING MY FIRST CUSTOMER!
(Gasps)
(Glitches)
(Loud talking with full mouth)
Yes, come on in, I'll be right
there,I'll be right there, Holla-di-hitti!
(Smooth-Jazz)
(Toothbrush noise)
(Gargling noise)
You and your success...
...in life.
-Fräulein Sehräder, where were we?
-I was sitting on her lap, Mr. Director!
Ah yes.
-So, Fräulein Sehräder, I'm making the jokes.
-Now read on.
-Severe respect to Mr. Bumskanzler...
Is there such a thing as Bumskanzler?
That means Bundeskanzler.
\u003cbr />And besides, we should address each
other formally. Yes, but not in the office.
We aren't,
the Bundeskanzler and I.
-So write it down, Stuppsi...
-Really?
Yes, and all that go before my signature.
So these secretaries...
Voilà!
Holla-di-hitti! Ottis Super
Service international!
What's the order of things?
So I'm expecting a delivery tomorrow of 30
Springböcke, -That's good!-I don't really know where to put it.
-That's bad.-I do
have a garden...
-That's good.-But
my fence is too low.
-And those springböcke
jump so high.-That's bad.
Now and then, I
thought, that you perhaps,
Actually, my fence
until tomorrow so on
three to four meters high can be raised.
No, I can't do that.
Oh, that's bad.
That's good, I can make sawhorses from their springbucks.
Watch out carefully
Here is the bock.
(Flute music)
And here
are buckets.
This is bad with the buckets.
Because he jumps out, the springbuck.
Not with my secret recipe.
In the buckets comes...
...Cement!
Ah, that's good, very good.
-Are you even using cement?
-No yet.
(Bouncy music inspired by
the "Mission: Impossible" theme)
(Baustellenlärm)
-(Murmuring)
-Yes, that's okay, will be taken care of!
-(Murmur)
-Yes, just go with it, will be...
-Yes, that will be taken care of immediately.
-Hey, you there!
-What?
-(Nonsensical phrase)
-Please?
<br /(Nonsensical phrase, slowly spoken)
Can you please specify
the direction a bit better?
You, go ahead and figure it out.
This constant stream of foreigners.
<br /(Nonsensical phrase)
<br /(Groaning)
Yes, Silvia. And that
will be our small salon.
Here we will all be very,
very happy.
-Who else is coming? -You and I, -and your mother, my friends and...
-Stop talking, it's making me dizzy.
About happiness, about happiness...
Oh, how I understand you,
my little golden parakeet.
But Silvia, we want to talk
about something else now.
You have your money and, well, your yacht and...your properties, -and your factories?
-Yes, why not?
Yes, then I obviously
have something for you too.
I brought you something
from my last safari.
-Little surprise.
-(Exasperated groaning)
Ah!
(Exasperated groaning)
Don't turn around. Not yet.
Wait a moment!
Now!
(Astonished breathing)
Silvia!
My treasure.
(Building site noises)
He saved my life.
( Car door slams )
Hold on, wait for me!
(Car door slams shut,
Motor noises)
Stay there!
How can I repay him?
Eighty-two, eighty-two,
sixty-six.
(Alarms ring)
(Groaning)
Hello?
!
(Sarcastic groaning)
Always these disgusting calls.
( Loud yawning )
(Nail clipper sounds)
Record breaker,
This will be a great day.
(Phone rings)
Hello?
(PHONE RINGS AGAIN)
I'm an idiot.
Hello?
(PHONE RINGS AGAIN)
-I'm calling about the Springboks.
Oh, that's good!
The matter has been resolved.
-Oh, that's bad, are they not jumping?
-And how!
They're already
overboard in the harbor.
Oh, that's crap.
(Telephone hangs up)
Well, there they were
again, my three problems.
No Springboks, no job,
and too much concrete.
Why didn't I succeed,
what did I do wrong?
The answer only my book knew.
(Leafing through pages)
The successful entrepreneur starts
every day with a jubilant "Yes" to life.
The successful entrepreneur seizes
every opportunity that comes his way.
And what he once tried
to do, will never let go, ah!
The successful entrepreneur is, at
everything he does, highly
concentrated, bright awake, and always in control.
That suits me.
(Pants, then starts
coughing) (Phone rings)
Note: Remember, a boss who can be
reached anytime (Phone rings again) is no boss.
Ah...
(Blows into a happy
tune)(Phone rings further)
(Phone rings again)
Ossi's Ottis Super Service
international, what can I do for you?
I'm looking for one of your employees.
A one? We have hundreds here.
I'm looking for a specific one. The one
from the Alsterdamm construction site.
No, no, when there was
none. But then there was one.
I am quite sure.
Sure? Then I will connect you
with our security, immediately.
(Sound of a phone extension)
(Altered voice) Security,
Ossie, what can I do?
-I'm looking...
-Don't say anything, good woman, the
cement excavator was sent
by me especially into the desert.
Listen, the train is just about
to leave! (The kettle whistles)
Sahara Express! All aboard...
Step back from your ticket.
Listen, the man has
saved my daughter's life.
(Sharply piping, Sound
of a falling bucket)
It's like a stone has fallen off my heart.
I'll connect you with our rescue
department, in a small moment.
Rescue team, Ostsee,
am I personally?
Finally, one always
comes stumbling upon you.
(Turkish Knock)
Here, ah, here.
Yes, a man in my position, is not
always available to everyone to speak.
With whom am I speaking?
I am the consul of Kohlen & Reibach.
Ah, Kohlen & Reibach.
What can you
do for me?
We would like to
thank you personally.
And I would be delighted to see you today at
1  o'clock this afternoon, please come by us.
1 ? o'clock, small moment, I need
to first check my calendar schedule.
Oh, that looks bad, would it also
be possible in the afternoon at 5?
Mainly, you're punctual.
Yes, I'm
punctual, I'll come.
-Yes, but where?
-Street of Parks, 25 to 29.
Street of Parks,
twenty-five to ninety-nine...
Now, something else entirely.
You know which day today is?
I need to check my calendar
schedule first. (Sudden laughter)
Today is the deadline day.
The refund is due.
After one month, the total amount
of the refund, including interest,
interest, interest, compound interest and
compound interest compound interest rates.
96.6 mark and 50.
You can now have the 50 cents.
Metallic clicking
But where should
I pick up the rest?
From Kohlen & Reibach family.
Huh?
And tomorrow, young
friend, the money is
here on the table, otherwise...
(Snipping sound)
(Loud swallowing)
Be successful.
(Ominous music)
(The door slams)
They were back again,
my three problems.
I had an invitation,
nothing fitting to wear,
and not even 50 marks
for a fly.
The only thing that
could now save me was...
...a nigger.
(Loud music)
Hey!
-You, nigger?
-What?
-Erm... You, nigger?
-Black man, black head, black belly, black feet?
Black feet?
Yes, black feet,
watch out, I'll show you!
Aaah...
-Black feet!
-Yes!
-You, nigger!
-Oh no, but seriously, do you want, to earn 50 marks?
I have a plan, we're both an
excellent team, watch out...
(Whispering)
(Laughter)
(further whispering)
(Loud music from the Ghettoblaster)
(Turkish trumpet)
Oh, my Little One,
Is your mommy at home?
Mama, Mama!
Here's a man with an ugly
face standing at the door!
Tell him we already have one.
We already have one.
We've already had one.
Funny, come up!
(Loud staircase climbing)
(Turkish trumpet)
-Oh, dear lady...
-No, thank you, I don't read magazines.
-Are you not aware, that tomorrow is the deadline?
-What's that all about?
Yes, tomorrow is the deadline.
From then on, slavery is
prohibited in our country.
-Did you know that?
-No.
-So you also don't have slaves?
-No, where are they from?
-From the Erzeugerland,
Then there would also be transport
costs, plus customs, plus insurance...
No, thank you,
that's not on the table.
I'm busy at home, and my husband
is at the ministry during the day.
Well, there's still the middleman trade,
that would be much cheaper for you.
- Is that cheaper for me?
- Yes, I'll make you an offer.
(Click sounds)
Has the master been called?
That's him, Bimbo.
What does he cost?
Noble lady, we'll discuss that
later, I'll show you Bimbo here.
Bimbo, this is your new
mistress, don't make me ashamed.
- Goodbye!
- Goodbye, Master.
Please, if you want to
come closer, Herr...Herr Äh...
Bimbo.
-Thanks, Missis.
Do you want to quit?
Oh, that doesn't pay off.
Yes, then come Please go on.
What are we going to do now?
You need to know that
we've never had a slave.
A bit unusual it is, though.
Can I offer you a
coffee? Thank you, Missis.
How do you drink your coffee?
-I like it black.
Oh, of course.
I should have thought of
that. \u003ci>(Door is ringing)
The echoes of Turkish doorbells
Good day, are
you holding slaves?
Yes, ah, he's here.
But trade is stillallowed
until tomorrow.
Yes, that's right.Is he indeed
registered, the slave, or?
I don't know...
Are you registered, Mr. Bimbo?
I'm not registered, Miss.
(Softly) Oh my goodness.
What are we doing
now? No problem.
Then we will report him
here, To that I am present.
Pay the same amount:
1,000 Deutsche Marks.
What?
Also, I didn't have that much.
I haven't come to
the bank today yet.
I don't know how
much you have there.
-100 Marks.
-That's enough, I'll take it as a deposit.
I am just no monster.
Does that go with it?
And what about the rest?
You pay later. Bimbo comes with me, as a deposit.
Ah, that's very nice of you.
Mr. Bimbo, don't you want
to drink their coffee first?
I must go, missis, I must go.
Goodbye.
See you soon.
This is your share.
What do you actually
need the money for?
For some blackness.
-Not again!
Birdsong
(Happy, light
instrumental music)
(electric humming
of the opening gate)
Actually, she opened
all the doors, my new fly.
That was it, the
Kingdom of the Rich.
Now they should know
how strong an arm is.
I had saved my life with the luxury
cement sack now it was their turn.
My God, I was
again for sale today.
I would have even
sold my soul for money.
We're not buying anything, we have
everything. That's just fine, I'm invited.
Your card, please?
-Karte?
Mixed noise.
Come in, bring money in.
I will inform you of the
monarchies, Herr...Sir Seven.
Chattering
Cash laughs, unknown master.
-Since you're here, it's nice.
Harp music.
(Sighing)
Water gurgling You are young.
You are in love.
You need glasses.
My friend,
How I am eager to gaze into the open
and noble aspects of that man's character.
The thing most precious that has been
saved for me, what I possess on earth.
My Sylvia.
Give me your hand.
Are you giving me something? I
think I'm supposed to get something!
I thought of cash, a gift?
The consul has called me.
Where is my reward?
Speaks French.
Signed, Jean, from the best. And from
the most expensive, Château Reitbach 1899.
Just in time for the
rescuer! (Tinkling bell rings)
Oh, Christmas! Ottilie,
merry Christmas!
Why doesn't anyone sing along?
Ah yes, I'm the one who gets it.
Hello-ditty!
Coughing
We have been thinking
for a long time over.
how one can thank a savior,
The elevation of its
high position raises it.
Over selfish,
financial interests.
Money, as we had said,
Can't mean anything
for a man like that.
We have therefore
decided on a gift.
Yes?
My God, then take it already.
Yes, but where is it, though?
Scratching wailing noises.
Where did you
hide it?Where is it?
There!
Is that it?
The gift?
I can't accept this.
I can't assume this is all of it?
My dear Silvia.
Today shall not only be blessed
the Saviour, but also the Saved.
Rescued ones
For there is no savior
without those who are saved.
And as happily Rescued
ones,you will also do well to practice
Better watch out for them eight.
And so you will
live for all eternity,
This ringlet reminds me.
Toy music
But Ernesto.
It must have cost a fortune.
Not worth mentioning, $96.50.
There it was, the solution
to my three problems.
But I had already
gotten three new ones.
They stood there,
I had to let her go,
The dumb thing was that they
wanted me to get rid of them.
I'm looking forward to
your slideshow presentation.
-They want to go now safely.
-Ah, they're already leaving?
Can we also look at
the slides together?
Yes, yes, Diass,
Diass, Good days!
I want to show you with these
pictures a glimpse of my homeland.
You also will soon
be my, my love Silvia.
My private airplane.
My first Jaguar.
My second Jaguar.
My servant.
And lastly, my mother.
Clapping hands.
Bravo, Ernesto, bravo!
Wonderful days.
Ah, I brought a photo along,if
you ever want to take a look.
No, thank you. We don't
want to put up with you.
I would also like to
see that, it interests me.
Yes?
That which I have, love.
- What?
This is my bicycle. Look
at it, how it's jumping up.
Wiehern
I was the only one who could
hold the saddle for 40 seconds.
I came to myself
again in the hospital.
I was, of course, the
only one, who came to me,
when you don't do
everything yourself...
Look at that bicycle, here.
My father went to the lake,
to teach me how to swim.
He threw me into the water,
while the others skated.
Look at that bike!/that
you have to have seen.
Behind is our farm, which was
quite small; we were very poor.
We were so poor, we had only a
sheep, and that was 50% Synthetic.
Silvia, it's time to think about,
that we have to go to the opera.
My little singing thrush.
-Yes!
Then we want to go, all
of us, all of us, all of us go.
Yes, it only goes into your
opera,listen to the melodies,
Intoxicate yourselves with the
air, love yourselves in the loges.
-What are you doing there?
-Oh, um, I thought you were going.
You're right, why people listen in
other's houses, You have me too!
The guitar and the sea.
and the joy that you now
have the right to wish for.
I wish you would leave
my house immediately.
I don't know that song.
Don't you see that I'm utterly exhausted?
-I'll just sing my lullaby right away!
Oh God...
- You can tell Otto that I'm fine.
Don't fall asleep, first let's sing
the sheep song! (Guitar music...).
The first sheep was named
Friedrich; that was incredibly low.
The second sheep was named
Peach, because she used to screech.
The third sheep was called John,
stayed on Peach all day long.
The 306th sheep was named Eberhard;drank so much, his liver was hard.
The 307th sheep was called
Luke,he always had to puke...
Erm, that's 720. The sheep was called Gertrull,
because one hits its head on the skull.
The sheep was called Vin;
because one likes to pull it's chin...
The 990th sheep was called
Trump,the lightning hit his rump.
The 1000th sheep was named Harold,
and that was a hundred years old...
Guitar feedback
during recording.
Harold!
Snoring.
Xylophone music
Now let's go, attack!
Stop my friend, that's injustice!
-Ah, Nonsense!
Snap up the ringand
get out of here!
But not with the ring.
-What else?
With good conscience.
-Is that how he intends to pay off his debts?
It's better to have
debts than to be liable.
Slander, nothing but slander.
-Those are not slanders.
Are you kidding
me? No, not at all.
But! -No!
But! - No! (Loud clinking.)
Loud guitar noise Harald!
I was richer tonight.
Wealth in experience,
That has been done well.
and resist the
influences of evil.
Dear debts, have become guilty.
Those were not just
golden words, that was...
What the hell! It was
a massive shitshow.
If I had the ring, I'd get out of
everything, what an idiot, what a twit!
I'm a shit, now I have to
earn money with honest work.
Angry outbursts.
Happy music
startled summons
Joyful music.
(loud big band music) (Otto
makes suitable drum tones)
Louder scream
I would never have thought that
honest work could be so dangerous.
One must warn people, their lives at stake
by setting it on the line with honest work.
Was there no law that protects
people from honest work?
No! There was only one
place, where one could be safe.
The walls of my own home.
The door slams shut.
Ominous music
What's your success?
Success? Ahm...
Now, since I want to ask, what
do you understand by "success"?
I'll ask something simpler.
What do you see under a bridge?
Can you imagine
nothing under that?
No large white steamer,with
a big naked woman?
Also nice, something
lighter,ahm ah ah...
What do you mean by a bridge?
Nothing, because the big steamship is so
loud shouting,with the beautiful naked woman.
Do you know what I understand?
Loud coughing. I want my money!
98 shillings and fifty pence.
Yes, but you already have
50 cents.<br /(Phone rings)
Hello?
No.
Huh?
That's what I will tell him.
Tomorrow.
Auf Wiedersehen,Miss
von Kohlen and Reibach.
Good luck, little one.
I hear now, you forgot
something,in the park alley.
Your gift. My gift? Ah, my gift.
It's quite valuable, I hear.
Yes yes, valuable, it's extremely
valuable, I'm going right away and get it.
A heavier blow than the knife
blade into the doorframe hits
Tomorrow is the last day.
(Fateful Music)
(Hitting the door)
(The motor of the car makes
noise, runs on too few cylinders)
-Stop, I am innocent!
-But that is your problem!
Amusing. (Makes baby noises.)
Bottle, huh? \u003ci>Silvia,
aren't you leaving?
I'm sorry, but I
can't help with that.
Weidenmann's Healing, Ernesto.
Weidmann's thanks.
Yes, it only hunts your wild.
It kills with bare rifles, Shoots
at everything that moves.
We have been making
this bottle for so long, yes?
Is that a good suggestion?
That's an unmitigated nerve!
Silvia, you're coming with!
But Mum, you know,how sad
it is for me to mistreat animals.
-Sylvia! You're climbing now!
-And you, Your Ladyship?
Mr. Otto?
Yes? - I'll ride with you!
Yes, but where then?
To the hunt!
Is this for the hunt? That's
my world! Ships Ahoy!
Peter Heil! The mountain is calling,all
come up, neck and ankle break!
Aeolus sighing of
the Ferrari engine.
She ran off, the
beautiful daughter.
But the way to the daughter's
heart goes over her mother's ear!
And all mothers of this
worldunderstand the language of music!
Radio noises, then music
Song "My little green
cactus" (Otto sings along)
Hail, whorls, whirlpools!
I need red roses, I
need red poppies.
Hollari, Hollari, Hollaro!
And if a wicked one what
untoward words speaks,
Then I'll take my cactus,
and it pricks, pricks, pricks.
My little green cactusstands
outside on the balcony,
Hollar, hollar, Hollar!
Pik, pik, pik, pik, pik...
Today at four,
knock on the door.
What a surprise visit
so early in the day.
It was Mr. Krause
from next door.
He says: "Excuse me, if I ask:
She has a cactus
on her small balcony.
Hollar, hollar, Holaro!
I don't know what
to make of that.
Hail, hallo, hello!
It fell upon my face,
whether you believe it or not.
Now I know that your small
green cactus pricked me.
Please move your
cactus politely elsewhere.
Hollari, Hollari, Hollaro!
Dear woodland companions,
and woodland maidens,
We are here again this year,
I have come together
in my territory.
to make it thoroughly.
He is, Rudolf, the rammer.
of all the capital and most criminal,
of all the roughest and most cunning,
of all things, and
most detestable,
the strongest and
proudest of them all.
the greatest and most cruel,
the commonest and
most sought-after
the most feared and
dangerous rodent.
West of Wülferrode.
How can one shoot
at such poor animals?
And like every year,
who waits this year also on the,
This is a name. Please provide more context
or information about "Rudolf den Rammler".
dead, or undead.
This valuable trophy,
The value of 986.00 Mark,
and fifty pfennigs.
Otto! Where are you?
Ha ha, where is he?
-To him, our signal should apply,
He has died.
Hunting Horn Music
Stop!
I can also send a signal.
(whispering sound)
That means "Hold on a minute."
"He's not dead," and this means
"He is gone," and
this (Puppy noise).
But, forest chief! Ha, ha ha...!
Ha ha, where is he?
(Happy hunting music)
(Hunting dog noises)
Birdsong
What's that?!
(Repeated bird chirping)
Otto is whispering back.
Birdsong
Otto is talking again.
(repeated chattering)
Mockingbird
Chirping bird (Laughing)
Misfire.
Hands up!
So hare, your time is
up!pay your bill to heaven!
Come on, let's go!
Come on, now let's go.
Make it, go!push
down, shoot!
You are not; it is a
living being, just like you.
Oh dear, think of
the money and shoot!
Dear life in need,
as a life to kill!
Now he also rhymes too. And
badly. You and your sayings.
Are you bloody jealous.
Am I not?  Are you really?
Are you kidding me?
(Shot won't settle)
Hunting horns (Dog barks)
Silvia! I know, it's not the
most suitable moment for a man,
-he just saved a hare's life...
-Drive!
-Don't bother that young
girl -Shut up and go!
Let's see tonight?
- No, I have to go to the Crème de la Crème.
Loud engine noise.
Cron de la Cron?
Chrome de la Chrome
Krupp de la Krupp? What is that...
Loud, mechanical noise.
Oh my! (another,
loud mechanical noise)
Metallic hammering
Hey! Hey!
I had an infinitely delightful
experience this morning:
Dear a life in hardship,as
a life to act, yes.
A grateful lookfrom the
eyes of the rescued creature,
more was worth than some such
a trophy, in value of €1 million.
9876 marks and fifty.
Piece of trash.
Otto, breakfast just
like always? How's that.
Here!
Applause.
- They're my husband!
-What does your wife say about it?
You are artists. You
need an audience.
I have an audience,
I am an agent.
Mr. Agent, it's on fire.
A cutlet for the spy. Sir
Spy, answer the phone!
My Lord.
I lead the renowned artist
agency Floppman and Flau.
I'm sorry but the
artists have left.
They are namely too cowardly,for
this charming audience.
-Da you're stepping on!
-Hmm?
What's on Floppman
and Flau's program?
Floppman and Flau show proudly,
Big gala afternoon
in the senior home,
with their favourite
films, radio and television.
And what am I doing there?
-That's you.
All your favorites?
That's what I'm advising you on, I'm also paying for it.
Ah, ah, I can also do
good animal impressions.
Woof woof!
At exactly 4 pm, / the
curtain goes up for you.
Oh no, 4 o'clock is bad too.
Angry funny. An
absolute mood cannon.
Clicking
Ladies and gentlemen,
a so thrilling
audience,just like you.
It's had the least earned, any
longer on the torture stretched.
The mood will reach its
absolute highest point.
Applause! Rest now!
For an artist, whom you
are just now waiting for.
Exactly like me. Are
you gone crazy, you idiot?
He comes to you.
They all know him.His
name has a good sound.
So my boy. You have
no chance! Also use it!
Yes.
The first song I want to play,
is dedicated to my grandmother.
It fell off the curtain
hem while I was sewing.
She has broken her arm
and is now wearing a cast.
The doctor has
banned stair climbing.
and so she makes a ruckus,
when she climbs up the gutter.
Guitar music
Below in the valley,
yes, there sits little Ottili,
Hello, hello!
And then Otilia does
Holla-de-dee-dee,
Holla-de-dee-doo.
and le io le io le io
holleidi, holleidioids...
A song with depth!
One never knows where one
has to crawl, at that moment.
General laughter.
I also like that sort of thing.
But the First World War
has me already also fallen.
(louder laughter)
You'll laugh, I can
too without singing.
(Flute music and percussion)
Also wake me up when
it's all over. (Laughter)
Whistle music & Drumming
Gunshot rings out.
A full-blooded musician, as
he is described in the book.
In the penal code!
Tra-tra-trallala,
Tra-tra-trallala.
Jaaaaa...
Are you all here?
But not for much longer!
I am now standing,
with my three problems.
I was finished, I was
done, I was at the end.
I had let myself be
swindled out of money.
I had become a
Kasper of Zastrow.
That was now the end.
But how should it go on?
Was there anything on this earth< br
/> except greed, malice and brutality?
Something that makes life less
repulsive, disgusting and difficult.
There must be something.
Something that filled the
pockets rather than the hearts.
Something that did not separate
people, but brought them together.
Something that brought human
warmth into our cold, calculating world.
Something that lasted longer
than marble, stone and iron.
There was
something.  But what?
But what?
Harpsichord music
That's it!Silvia,
I'm coming to you,
In the Grimm's, in the Krom's.
No, at Krupp of the Krupp.
Krupp of the Krupps, no,
Crom of the Croms, yes.
Ah, that's it, Chrome of Chrome!
Yes, Silvia, I'm coming,
your rescuer is approaching!
Ha Chrome!
Rock music
loud rock music.
(The music stops abruptly)
Silvia?
otter.
Two things are we
here absolutely not:
People like you,
And people who look like you.
Ask him the question already.
(Whistling)
How does an Eskimo
go to the bathroom?
I don't know how
an Eskimo defecates.
(Ice cubes crunching)
( Otto laughs loudly )
Spitzenwitz! Shithole!
I can't translate that for you.
Werner, one more question.
Change is invisible and
smells of rabbit, what is that?
What is invisible
and smells of rabbit.
Is a rabbit's poop?
Loud applause
Rock music plays again.
Ah, that's it,the
Créme de la Créme.
Thank you, old man!Hot oven.
Hehehe!
Classical Baroque
music in the background.
Hickson
Apologies.
Do you know this?
What is it, it is
invisible,and smells of rabbit.
A rabbit's fart!
loud laughter
Silvia!
Silvia, Silvia, you!
Oh dear heaven.
Respected friends,
I have the
extraordinary pleasure,
Meet him with this very
ordinary, young man.
the had the unusual luck.
My daughter Silvia,
that's what it's all about.
Sir Otto?
Ja?
Mr. Obermayor, Mehlig.
Oh, a man of faith.
Wonderful,then you
are certainly the one,
Who can help me
during my faith crisis?
So it is possible for me, young friend.
-I believe namely,
I'm getting nothing
more to drink.
I'm getting
something, a wonder!
Moni, where are you?
I'll beat you at dominoes.
Lead singer,
Anneliese Grünentaler.
Mrs. Opera Singer,
Do you sing here?
I can shatter
glass,./Please be careful.
(Hashed, Dog Bells)
Not full yet, wait a moment.
(Screaming) (Glass clinking)
Do you see?
It works. And
here is a friend of Ernesto,
General Gustavo Raul Stussner
General Stossner!
(military salute)
Well?
This beauty, and so much lametta.
- What's this?
A Christmas tree,
that can speak.
At your doorstep still clings the blood,
the blood of your slaughtered enemies.
But since we're just talking about war
now, can I get something to drink, or what?
Thank you, You can leave now!
This gentleman
knows you already.
Bodo, Prince of Markwitz.
-I know you, but do you know this place?
If you recognize this animal,
Now I may have a head
of hair drink your champagne.
And?
- Pig!
- I'll just let that go.
No one understands me, but
Ernesto, you understand me.
What's wrong?
No one understands me.
No one.
Otto is mumbling.
I have to tell you, you...
-Enough, you've said enough!
Dear friends, let us
now come to dessert.
But I must tell her anyway!
Silvia, you...-Enough!
-The dessert, please.
-The dessert, where does it come from?
Oh, the dessert.
A small moment, I do that...
Apples of Bordell,
Potato Fritters.
We have, we had, He is gone
now, he is completely gone.
Where is he now?
Ah, there he is.
And with Red.
Oh, it's just too little.
We'll just take a
"Loni pot" instead.
Explosion.
God, stand by us!
(Singer cries out singing)
No panic! No panic!
Women and Otti first!
Excited cries from
the restaurant.
(The auto door slams)
(The car speeds off quickly)
Caution, sir!
My friend, no one
should sink so deep.
that he is the most
beautiful gift of nature
In his rage he throws himself.
and if you really want the wine,
and now and just,
I am willing to help.
This is rubbish wine, that
doesn't have a screw-top.
But but, here come.
We have indeed brought
everything,everything with us.
People say that Crème de la Crème
has left something behind lately.
How were you satisfied?
What did you have for supper?
-I'm annoyed, nothing but annoyance.
-I'm annoyed, yes, but not that much.
We are indeed cultivated people.
We wouldn't be here if not for that.
-Aah.
Thank you.
(Satisfied sigh)
I had at the time (wine brand)
And (another wine brand)
is highly appreciated.
I love you, I love you, the little French girls.
Both laugh.
-(French) To your health!
-Tea, I thought there was wine here.
And what a wine!
that is a Bordeaux.
Castle Reibach.
This is a year
Gurgling sounds
Hmm? Yes, or?
No idea.
1901.
No, that can't possibly be true.
It's 1899.
Ah, that my old tonguecan
still experience it.
That there is
still this wine left.
Do you know what this wine is?
At the last auction in
Bordeaux where was brought?
96.6 Mark, and if I'm not wrong,
Fifty cents.
(Pronounced)
In this night I had a dream,
I will be ashamed
for as long as I live.
A luck that will never
be known by anyone.
This went like this:
Cymbal crashes
The Line Fleet,
Carthage-Constantinople.
I'm hacking full throttle,and
behind me my brother Ernesto.
And what does he do?
That must be different.
The rubbing.
Who was it?
Whip cracks
That must be a poor
slave, who never had to row.
It has never fallen to rowing...
Groaning.
Never again Castle Reibach.
What! Is it 12:73?
There they were,
my three problems.
I had a hangover, a rabbit.
And I was totally weak.
And this, of all
days,the day of decision.
He or I. She or
none. How or what.
What was there, was just a
intensified fitness program.
One hundred and one...(Sighs)
Background music (Mood Music)
One hundred and two.
One hundred and three.
One hundred and four, one hundred
and five. One hundred six...
Three thousand sixteen, three thousand seventeen
(Cutting sounds)
(breaking bottles)
Only one strength breakfast, and I was
ready for the battle of love and happiness.
The world should now know me.
Joyful flute music.
Nothing should
now stand in my way.
Spray sounds.
(mysterious music)
Wailing sirens
Fire! Fire! (loud coughing)
(Soft coughing)
Drill sound.
Very good eye measurement.
Yes, for a marriage loan, you
need security, do you have security?
Security? Ah, well, if she
wants it, I'm unsure, but
That I want, am I
sure? No, heart by side.
What I mean are
material securities, stocks.
Real estate, bonds.
I have many deposit bottles, but...
-This is an attack!
First comes...
-Hands up!
Axis, this is an invasion!
-All down!
You're not, you idiot.
We have been spelling
it wrong for years.
For you alwaysstill
Mr. Haenlein,
Sir, Sir Haenlein.
- Also good, Sir Haenlein.
Now get moving with your 93
kilos and hand over the money.
I apologize but I can
not fulfil your request.
And secondly, it seems
to me, with your 1 meter 9?
exactly suitable for, to
overcome this obstacle.
Mr. Haenlein, even your
blue-grey eyes must have noticed,
that a war injury does not prevent someone
under the age of approximately 45 from
Such turn exercises
here to make.
Oh, don't be so dramatic,with
that 5cm long scar under your eye.
What am I supposed to say about my
good, but bothersome speech faults?
Also good.
The clever one gives in.
- Yes.
Ominous music
Bank employee
makes siren noises.
Foolish fog!
Exactly 98.65 DM!
Mr. Haenlein, you are bringing
this suitcase, into my social housing.
Thomas Ballermann Street 50.
And that was with
the stolen Mercedes.
with the fake number plates
they had forged, SF-FN 222,
Such a piece of
cruelty from you!
Get out of the way of this pair.
But not like that. Yes,
how else would it be?
Yes, put it on or
push or shove it.
Or do you believe,it
will sort itself out?
Look, it's going its own way.
Please, Mr. Sonnemann.
We'll meet tomorrow, punctually
at 9:15 am on the plane.
I wait in the one after Rio de Janeiro,
and not in the one after Southeast Asia.
You sadistic beast!
(Police sirens)
Ah, 9: 15 am, Rio de Janeiro,
and not Southeast Asia.
loud police sirens.
(Tires squeaking)
Hands up! No movement!
Peterson, you as an old
brush-tailed squirrel must see,
They are paper camels.
Man, who can't
even lift their hands.
But Chef, you can
see that they can.
Come on out already!
Comrade Inspector, I have
everything under control.
I will give you a complete
description of the perpetrator.
Write down, Petersen.
Now, get on with it.
The one,
That was a half chicken.
and had something
peculiar under his left eye.
A forged license plate, with
a scar on the number plate.
Should I really lie
down with you, boss?
The second was
Thomas Ballermann.
And had a language error, South-East
Asia, around 9:15 am, in Rio de Janeiro.
I have made a phantom drawing.
Paper bag wriggling;
doesn't it seem clear?
Now what are you going to say?
But Inspector,two
robbers came into the bank,
He is short, he is long.
FS-SF 222, false
registration plate.
Thomas Ballermann Street, 9:15, in Rio, Call the police now I have it.
Mr. Astrid, weren't you a witness
to this brutal bank robbery?
Do you have any
information for our viewers?
What did you observe?
Do you know, I as a barber?
can tell you something like that:
The robbers won't
have any joy at this heist.
Why?
-I saw them too,
with their nylon stockings.
That's poison for your hair.
Hair wants to breathe. Hair...
Mr. Astrid, I have a question, may
I call you simply over the phone?
-Behind left.
-Behind left, thank you.
Yes and what about
the getaway car?
I'll tell you one thing, Silvia,
this Mr. Otto you never see again.
But Mum, he saved my life.
That's bad enough.
You don't save your life with
people like that in our family.
Something in style I
had expected from you.
But Mother, she
is nice and friendly.
This mixture of Frankenstein and The
Hunchback of Notre Dame is quite nice.
You're unfair,he's not
a monster at all, in fact.
-He sometimes had something of a dancer.
-Dancer?
Dance of the Vampires
maybe.Believe me, the man is criminal.
This startled glance,
this common grin.
And have you seen his hands?
Thieves are that! The
hands of born murderer.
You're going too far!
I've seen his hands.
They are the hands of an artist.
Those of a conductor, a pianist.
One guitarist, a
counterfashionist.
I believe that he can
be infinitely gentle.
Believe what you
want,I know what I know.
Tomorrow at 9:15 amwe'll
be sitting on the plane to Rio.
And tomorrow you are
Ernest's wife, and also...
What are you
doing there, Master?
Yes, what's going on here?
Happy flute music...
There they were again,
my three problems.
(The door slammed) I loved that girl,
There are only a few
hours left, to win them.
And I didn't know how to do it.
Did my book know that?
The slow method,
winning a woman.
Ah, the quick method,
a woman to win.
Firstly, greet her with a gift,
Secondly, invite her to dine.
And thirdly, say that you
want to start a family with her.
Listen to me for a moment.
Firstly, greet her with a gift.
Secondly, invite them to dinner.
And thirdly, tell her that
you want to start a family.
Knocking on Turkish doors
Harpsichord music.
(whispers) Say, that you
want to start a family with her.
I want a child from you.
Isn't that a bit too rushed?
(whispering) -Damn it.
Invite them to dinner.
Can I invite you to dinner?
- With pleasure
- Will I then get a child from you?
-Let me get in first.
-No, you're getting it mixed up.
The gift comes, here.
That's lovely of you.
-So, and now it's time for dinner.
Who's Otto?
How's it going?
Acidic cucumbers
with potato salad?
No, no, /today is
the surprise menu.
He is walking into the kitchen.
As a small surprise, I have
Bullettencocktail
for my friend Otto
And his companion, please.
That's just dreamy,that
I've always wanted.
- delicious.
- I want to know more about you.
Now drink up first. Have
you ever had a girlfriend?
Friend, that can't be said like
that, that was more of a pen pal.
I don't know whether
one can say that.
But I'll say it like this,
That was thus:
She was called Ilse, and
I had written her a letter.
The window creaks.
But she never got him.
Ah, how sad.. Ah, do you
know, there are still others...
Main course! False hare.
That looks good.
Please. May I, please?
Good luck. And what about Ilse?
Have you ever tried it again?
But I've tried it.
I wrote her a long,
long, long letter.
Joyful flute music
It was the longest letter;
that I had ever written.
I had written down all the weight
of my great love from the heart.
There was already something together,and
everything was contained in this letter.
And this time I was smarter.
I stuck the letter to,and
had the window open.
Sounds of ducks Splashing sound
How dreadful! Ah, you know, there
is even more dreadful thing than that.
And now for dessert. My main
course, Hackfleischpudding.
Thank you very much.
That's also my main course.
Have you tried it by post?
But of course.
Joyful flute music.
But, alas, in some
godforsaken, Dutch post office,
The Tauber Valley
had to happen then.
The owl is silent.
Ah, Otto. Ah, Silvia.
Stavros, what's up?
Ah, menu is over.
Alright, let's get started.
Goodbye!<br /(Host
responds in a foreign language)
Otto responds in
a foreign language.
The history was so
sad. There is worse.
What?!
-It could rain.
RegergNoise
How nice that you
have a umbrella with you.
Yes.
Happy musicA raincoat
for you and me.
Step dance sounds
Why are you crying?
- Otto is raining and I have no umbrella.
Why isn't it raining anymore?
Come's, we're taking the shortcutover
the cemetery, to my place in the warm.
Do you not fear at all?
-No, not if you're at my place.
-Sounds nice. (loud eagle scream)
So, that's how it goes.
The tree creaks. You, I
have to tell you something.
I am different than
the others. I know that.
No no, I am quite different.
The scream of Eulenspiegel
(dramatic music)
Cry.
Dark organ music.
The bell is ringing.
The bell is tolling.
Scream
Pop music
Black-brown is the hazelnut,
Black-brown am I also.
Black-brown shall be
my girl, just like me.
Black-brown is the hazelnut,
Black-brown am I also.
Black-brown shall
be my girl,just like me.
Black-brown, Black-brown,
Schwarzbraun, Schwarzbraun,
Schwarzbraun, Yeah!
March music...
What's going on,it
doesn't rain anymore.
Let's quickly get away from
here. Yes, we're going to my place.
Happy flute music
Everything up until here has gone
exactly as it was written in my book,
But what was most important
came yet still,the night.
What do you actually do at
night? I am just so excited.
Do you have hunger?
- No, do you have a towel?
A moment.
Ah, the towel is
hanging in the bathroom.
"There's just one washcloth
hanging." "But that's definitely a towel."
-One can just put your hand in
it.-That's why it's also called a towel.
-What's all that noise?-I'm
making it cozy for us.
Spray sounds
Romantic music.
The bathroom is free.
(loud gulping)
...are you free? Who let him
out? I had it extra tightly bound.
The bathroom is free, yes,
it's a public bathhouse indeed.
Instrumental music.
Oh, you're so sweet.
Do you have soft hair?
You have but lovely eyes.
And how impertinent
your nose is.
And how long are your ears.
Good heavens tight buttocks.
Hollow knocking.
Oh, and this sweet,
small Stummel's tail.
Ahaha! By the way, now show
me where the hammer hangs.
You're not doing that, it's not your
style; taking an opportunity like this.
But it is indeed the opportunity,
Opportunity makes love.
Moment, I'm the one with the wide sayings,
I, and love is something entirely different.
The love, the love, is
heavenly power.
Oh, he's singing too now!
Otto, listen to me.
No, listen to me.
No, me! I'm not listening
to anyone anymore.
(The door swings
open) Now he does it.
No, no, he doesn't do it.
Do we not want to do
it? What do you mean?
-A round of pens.
-Okay.
(Loud yawning, Sleep music)
What's wrong with my axis?
Remember, show them never your feelings, and
they'll hang around you like a fish on a hook.
Don't ever show your feelings.
Loud explosion? Na, Baby?
Is it late? Good
Lord, how late is it?
-About eight, if you're interested.
-Actually, I should have left a long time ago.
Why are you still here?
Otto, you wanted to
say something more.
Something important. If you don't
tell me now, I really have to leave.
Travelers should not be stopped.
It's no trouble,
if I'm going now.
Do you know, Baby,
someday,we have to go, somehow,
Nowhere.
It's a shame, Otto.
Don't make a big
deal out of it, Baby.
It's the same for all after one night with me.
Here's looking at you, Kid!
The door slams shut.
What have you forgotten, baby?
Women...
The door slams shut.
I have to tell her.
Excuse me, I had never
had the courage to tell you,
But you're wonderful, one-of-a-kind,
you're the dearest person I know.
I love you, and I
will always love you.
I will be loved.
That
This is the most
beautiful day in my life.
That has never been
said by a human to me.
These words: I...I love you.
Don't worry, I'll be back soon.
I have to see Silvia.
You'll be fine here.
Hello, Stavros?
I'm going, do you mind
watching Rudi? Of course.
-Are you being kind to him, yes?
-Of course, I am.
I must go to Silvia.
The door slams shut.
It was just a joke.
Louder and louder
airplane noises...
Carnival horns.
The captain and his crew are
delighted,to be welcomed as guests.
The city is already in carnival fever,the
mood barometer is constantly rising.
Turbulences will come your way,but
hopefully first under the sugar hat.
We wish you a pleasant flight.
Our charming staff will greet you
with refreshments of your choice.
Loosened party noises.
(Passengers sing
a carnival song)
(exhausted, loud breathing)
Once and never again.
Or?
(Passengers sing Carnival songs)
It's so hot in
Hawaii, no cool spot.
and just Hula-Hula...
You must drink;
otherwise you will fall.
Since when have we
been using each other?
For you still Herr
Sonnemann, Herr Haenlein!
That's okay, then drink
up! You will have it.
You know exactly about my war
injury it forbids me from drinking alcohol.
Why? Are you drinking with
your 5cm long scar under the eye?
with the mouth?
Frivolity.
This is the last bank
robbery, I have done with you.
You're being quite
bold, Mr. Sonnemann.
Sir Captain, we must
overthrow,ahem, correct, ah, soften.
Why, what's going on? It's
two bank robbers on board.
I know them very well,they are
named Hanemann and Sonnilein.
What do you tell me about that?
Tell me what Interpol says in Rio.
Yes, but how then?Yes, you're
certainly the radio operator.
Axis, Aye-Aye, Sir.
Hello? Hello Rio?
Hello Interpol?
We have two bank
robbers on board.
Prepare everything
for, a fifth arrest.
And another tip, be careful,the
two may indeed be armed.
(Sinister music) Hello?
Hello Rio? Hello Interpol?
Have you understood me?
Yes? Yes, two robbers.Two
robbers came into the bank.
The one thick, /
The other thin, yes.
Hands up!
This is an airplane hijacking, and you
are going to fly us straight to Cuba now.
No, to Argentina.
Or Kuwait?
That's too much for me.
Then I prefer Ghana.
-That's too close to me.
- How about south east Asia?
- You sadistic beast!
Yes, are you crazy?
Now you've killed
the pilot. Why?
I did it anyway.
I have seen it
exactly, so you did it!
-Sorry! I didn't do that!
-He didn't do it, I saw it.
-Naturally he's done it that way!
-Yes, are you out of your mind, Sonnemann?
The man is our last hope.
-One must surely fly!
-But I cannot fly.
I can't handle any objection.
They are flying.
(tense music)
Splashing noise.
Yes, what are you doing
there? You can't even fly.
Can I really?
Groaning
Haha, technical knockout
before the first round!
Dark music.
That is an airplane hijacking.
They killed the
pilot, and the co-pilot.
Ernesto.
You must fly! You
do have an airplane.
No, I haven't.
Is Ernesto?
And what's with your hacienda?
I don't have any.
I have no jaguar.
I have no servants.
I have nothing.
Ernesto.
I'm also not Ernesto.
But?
Harold
Snoring sounds.
Ah, haha!
Parties are getting louder.
Madam and Gentlemen,here
speaks your Captain, Otto.
I have a very important announcement,
Silvia, I love you, holla-di-hitti!
Otto!
Romantic music.
It's Rio in front of you.
Sit down quickly.
That's supposed to be Rio.
That's much bigger
than I had imagined.
This is never in
life Rio de Janeiro!
(Dramatic music)
Hurray.
-No!- -Ja!
No,!
Oh no!
Yeah!
Loud crunching. Ah ha ha!
explosion
Yes, that was a long story.
And it's very educational.
We have learned
something. Rio is much bigger.
And interesting.
Will I ever see my Sylvia again?
(WhistlingFlight Song)
Otto.
Hurrah, we're in sight!
Hurray!
Ominous music.
...there will come loud gauchos.
one, two, it's enough.
Forest noises.
Rest now, gentlemen!
We will now, possibly.
as first representative,
of our Western culture,
This unmarried
island is entered.
We want to behave accordingly.
Well done! Gentlemen,
More dignity!
Carnival march music
(mouth trumpet)
(German saying:) There flies, the holes out of the cheese.
Here it goes,the
Polynesian Polonaise!
(Foreign native language)
Huh! Huh! Huh!
Here come the holes
out of the cheese.
Because now she's
off, our Polonäse
From Blankenese
to behind Wuppertal.
At Kamen's Cross right away
We're off, with very big steps
And he picks up Heidi
from behind at the shoulder.
That lifts the mood,
yes then comes joy on
Come on Grandma, let's go.
The orchestra on stage
is driving madness.
The pianist is pulling
all the keys out.
The tuba blows the beat
away from the drummer.
The Conductor cries
and shouts: "Light out!"
Ocean sounds
Are you going to make
me happy tonight?
Are you also making me happy twice?
- Yes.
Also three times?
There they were again,
my three problems...
Piano Suite with seagull Sounds