[Running and squeaking brakes]
[Trumpeting elephant]
[Rhythmic beat]
Where is the picture?
Sharper!
Now the men on stage!
And light!
[Loud stomping]
Men, where you stand now,
will stand in a few days
Amboss,  the Rabid one.
Men,
do you know what that means?
Oh no, you don't
know what that means.
Shall I tell you?
Here,
the premiere of our new film
will take place in a few days.
Amboss, the Rabiator.
[Drum jingle]
This man, men, needs
men like you!
Strong men.
Hard men.
Determined men.
Intelligent men.
I'm paying for no one to
touch my gold baby's diapers.
Bodyguards, dear
friends. I need bodyguards.
Now show me what you've got.
Zippers open
loudly. [Suspenseful music]
Come on now!
[Tennis balls fall
out on the floor]
Very funny!
What kind of bird is that?
Well a ugly duckling.
Get this wretched
heap off the stage!
Wait!
That's not how you talk to me.
In any case, not unpunished.
And I advise you,
remember this face!
Um, or this one.
[giggles]
Or, how about this?
Or this?
And remember my name,
Otto.
[Title music]
[Giggling]
[Strangle]
[Coin toss]
[Lots of bass]
[Louder bass]
[loud bass] / Chair is
pushed back and forth]
[lots of bass]
[Lots of bass]
[loud bass]
My family, father,
mother, grandfather and I.
My parents.
They wanted to deduct me from
their taxes, as an extraordinary expense.
I haven't brought much joy.
The first words of my
father, when I came to prison, were
"Welcome!"
Mother always said to me, \"Go
play outside, don't just sit here."
"With the other children,
Herbert for example!"
Mom, do you want me to play with
a boy who always lies and cheats?
"Good heavens, no!" Well,
Herbert wouldn't either.
I always had to wear light-colored
clothes on my way to school,
in order to be
better seen by cars.
So I then set off, white
hat, white scarf,
white jacket, white
pants, white shoes,
and was run over by a snow plow.
Grandfather, 95 years!
He had a secret to aging.
Every evening before going to
sleep, he bit into a clove of garlic.
And when at night  death
came to his bed and said:
"Dude, it's about
time!", he then said.
"Who's thereee?!" and
Death "Uagh!"
And now everyone is gone.
And here too everything is gone.
My closet is gone.
My bed is gone.
My chair is gone.
My bookshelf is gone.
My only book I had
to postpone, my address book.
Shitty plot, but animal cast.
Even my only trousers
they took from me...
Oh no, I'm wearing those.
My TV is gone,
I've never made it to TV
either, always looking for work.
I wanted to work, but
you didn't let me, you city!
You haven't given me anything!
But also nothing taken,
except my courage, my hope,
my will to live, and
my self-confidence.
I wished I was like I was,  when
I wanted to become what I am.
My seashell Walkman,
Play me again the song of home.
[sings]
My Chicken Island, only
a small island,
a deserted sand dune
in the Wadden Sea,
but how much traffic
there was, animal.
If I hadn't been,
Seagull screeching, pure chaos.
But I showed them the way.
[Accordion plays
in the background]
90% of the birds have
passed the swift exam with me.
Why? Well, it's obvious, so
they don't sail into the walls!
[Seagull laughter]
Only the bats don't make it.
As for navigational ability,
radar system and so on.
Why do they only fly at
night? They're ashamed!
They don't want anyone to see how
they're constantly slamming into the walls!
But I was there for all
of them, for everyone.
Yes, come in, my darlings.
over there waits the fox.
Homeland, I did
not surrender you.
but nobody wanted you either.
Chicken leg!  [loud stomping]
I'm coming!
Otto.
Otto, what are you up to?
Oh Anna, it's you, I
thought you were your father.
I have to disappoint you, he
went for a walk with Harras.
That's good, I wanted
to leave anyway.
-You're leaving? Forever?
-Yes.
Then I'd like to say
goodbye right away, hold on.
(quietly) Otto...
Goodbye, Anna.
Otto, is there nothing
that keeps you here?
-What's that?
-Is there no one to hold you?
Who then?
Me, for example.
I think highly of you, I
know there's a lot in you!
Where should I
start, first of all...
or secondly, or thirdly.
Otto, you can do anything.
Except perhaps...
Well, what is it?
Well,
your guitar playing
is not that great.
Hold on! [Door slams]
You shouldn't
have said that now.
[Electric guitar is being tuned]
Are you ready for me?
[Rock music sounds]
-Give me an 1!
-
-Give me an S!
-S!
-Give me an M!
-M!
-Give me an F! \"F!"
-What's the Word?
-LSMF!
LSMF?
[Rock music]
Alright!
Los!
Go Otti, go!
[Footsteps]
-Who is your best friend?
-Otto! Otto!
-Who always meant well?
-Who do you love until the last day?
-Otto! Otto!
To whom would you lend a hundred
marks right away? [Tape recorder clicks]
Aha.
The artist is giving his farewell
concert, that was music, wasn't it?
[Approving sigh]
We used to call that assault,
but one is tolerant these days.
Well. Oh, madam, to
Professor Edelson, yes?
Sixth floor, you know
Yes, okay, thank you!
Moment, Maestro, haven't
we forgotten something?
Back then there was a custom,
one didn't leave without a farewell gift.
That's a lovely custom.
No, no.
[Groaning]
Here I have something for
you, something quite personal.
Hm, shame, unfortunately
unsuitable as wanted posters.
Well then, let's go.
In here!
Stop!
[Door slams shut]
I want to read you
something nice."
Oh oh oh, what do we have here?
Can I trust my eyes, is
a month's rent missing?
Or two? Or in the end even...
Three months' rent, Yes indeed.
Three months' rent you owe, and
without it you won't get away.
Then I'll just leave them
here!  [Laughs mischievously]
You are funny. But whether
the judge will also find that funny.
They're supposed to be cracking
down hard again lately, on malicious,
intentional rental fraud!
[Suspenseful music]
Defendant, I sentence you to 2,000
Deutsche Marks or 5 years imprisonment!
-Then I'll take the money.
-Huh?
Anna. Anna!
Call the "bulls."
[Loud banging] I can't, Father.
I guess I'll have to do it myself, no
one else wants to do this dirty work.
No no, you shouldn't, you
are right and need help.
If you had a young man who
took care of everything for you...
-A kind of slave?
-Yes, then it does everything for you!
-Him?
I'm taking everything down, even
the receiver, should I call the police?
Hold on, you're not getting
away from me that easily.
I have something for you,
something completely new.
You've never experienced anything
like this in your whole life, Work!
-Good job!
-Work?
Right dirty work, that
nobody does? I'll do it!
[Kissing sounds]
Formerly slaves had heavy chains, with
thick iron balls attached to them.
That was very enjoyable.
But what do I do if he takes off, before
everything is done, in 10 months?
He won't do
that, I guarantee it.
For whom?
Look at him,  fleeing
forehead, fleeing eyes,
fleeing nose, fleeing
mouth, fleeing chin.
If you don't watch out,
the rest will also leave.
No, there's only one language
that these guys understand.
[Loud, metallic banging]
If you hear this sound,
be here immediately!
Otherwise, he'll get
you. Grab Harras!
Hold it!
Hold on, Harras!
Quiet! [Dog howling]
It's unbelievable, he
doesn't get it again.
You shall bite him!
-Should I bite him?
-Idiot!
To the Labor Front,
you bring that down there, Anna.
And you bring Harras
up, to Professor Edelson.
He should take on that mutt,
so he can bite properly again!
Grrr!
Don't be afraid, I'll take you to the professor, and
in the meantime I'll tell you a story.
Then a dog came towards me,
and lifted its leg, I was afraid.
But the owner said, "Don't
worry, he doesn't bite!"
Bite, I thought
he'd kick! [giggles]
Not so funny?
[Parrot squawks]
Stop animal testing!
Shut up!
-Stop animal testing!
-Shut up, I said!
Stop animal testing!
[Doorbell]
That's nonsense, animal testing, we
don't want anyone to experiment on us.
There he is, our
little failure.
[Dog howls]
Don't want to be evil anymore?
There I'll probably have
to be mean first, won't I?
[Dog howls]
[Door slams shut]
[Otto whistles]
(whispering) Stop
animal testing!
[Wretched dog howling]
[Door slams shut]
[Loud knocking on the door]
Harras, hold out, your savior is coming!
Harras, patience, your
savior is pressing!
Harras, wait, your savior
can't get the door open!
[Loud howling from the doctor]
I'm just growling here so that
the dog thinks it's big and mean
and bite down hard, good
boy, Harras, hold fast!
Grab! Grab! Come on, grab!
Out! Out! Out!
-Out! Out!
-Excellent, congratulations, young man!
Never has anyone grasped and
implemented the method so quickly.
-My only pants!
-That's good, the only pants.
Have you heard,
Harras, the only pants.
Young man, He
sends you heaven.
A friend of animals like you, I
could really use right now. Come.
-I can't!
-Okay, Harras, make way!
Come, I will show you
something very precious.
[whispers] She's
probably sleeping,
our princess, from
the Orient,
Mizuleika is
the last of her kind.
The Sultan of Bahrain
entrusted them to me.
She suffers from a
mysterious ailment.
Every disruption could
be their last, you see?
Why, it looks quite
lively. [Cat meows loudly]
She's so lively! [Cat
meows loudly again]
You really have a way
with animals, young man.
That's excellent timing.
I have to go to the Edelson
Congress for Applied Animal Psychology.
But you are my savior, I
entrust Mizuleika to you!
-Should I take her right away?
-No no, for God's sake.
The noble animal must on
no account leave this room.
And she needs her
Edelson diet every evening.
Huh?
[Harp sounds]
Everything for the cat?
Oh, so yummy
things does she get?
Every evening, at 6 pm
sharp, hit that gong over there.
Oh, that's  Yes, simple.
Stop! Not right now.
6 p.m. Otherwise Mizuleika
will get up to something.
-Ah, she's doing suicide...?
-Psst!
But not in her presence.
Yes, exactly.
I will call every evening to
see if everything is alright.
-Everything understood?
-Yes sir, every evening at 6 pm, otherwise she'll...
Psst!
-...hmm.
-Yes.
Here is my apartment key.
And if you could drive
my car into the garage.
I'll do it right away.
[Door slams shut]
[Birdsong]
What are you doing out
there? Come here immediately!
I'm supposed to drive the
professor's car into the garage.
Harras, ass!
[Dog barking]
[Sounds of fighting]
Out, Harras, out!
It's a good thing that it's
only trained on humans.
Beautiful things you have here.
I don't want her
here, go on, get rid of her!
But first I have to
drive the car away.
I'll take care of the heavy
stuff, come on, let's get to work.
[Loud groaning]
[Groaning, clattering]
[Knocking]
[loud creaking]
What?
That was quick.
I'm also so fed up.
When you are
finished, I decide here.
Fifth floor, apartment
A, someone is moving in right now.
Apartment A, that's
my apartment, isn't it?
That was your apartment, but
now basement apartment,
with an unflinching gaze
on the laundry room, hehe.
forced) Hehe...
Of course I could accommodate
three guest workers there,
but we Germans
should stick together.
Yes, my caretaker.
[happy music]
[Happy music]
Master Otti cleans so cleanly,  that
you can see yourself reflected in it.
Now the hallway
cleaners can come!
Over there, comes a corner!
Understood!
[loud banging]
[Rumbling]
Full speed ahead!
[Loud rumbling and clattering]
-Now just the door!
-Get ready to ram!
Careful set down, Caution!
We don't want to do anything
to the freshly painted wall, right?
Clean! Yes, that's
professional experience!
Congratulations, Colleague!
[Loud bang] Quitting time!
"Goodbye!"
[The door creaks softly]
[Pop music starts to play]
[Door creaks]
Hello, is the janitor there?
I need a strong man.
Yes, my closet
door is sticking.
Yes, the new one,
fifth floor, apartment A.
[Door slams] [Otto
exhales loudly]
Be silent, my heart.
What a woman, Woah!
If only I knew what her name is.
Freshly painted.
What a name! \"Freshly painted"
As married people greet,
Otto, and freshly ironed.
-Will that ever come out again?
-Will she go out with me?
Do you think they are so great?
Great, what means great?
She looks good, but
what does that even mean?
She has beautiful
long legs, and?
Your figure is
unique, regardless.
Your hair, is like angel's hair.
And her breasts, are
like well-shaped fruits.
Like fawns grazing
amongst roses.
Your loins, like made
by the master's hand.
Say "Otto, are you sure that we're
talking about the same woman?"
Her name is like the evening
wind, that lets the fisherman sail.
"Out, out..." [Otto
sighs softly]
-What's her name again?
-Freshly painted.
It's a strange name, that's
true, but that's what was on her door.
You should have looked
at their doorbell better.
-Why, what's that there?
-Gaby Drösel.
[Reverently] Gaby Drösel.
A name, like Silverklang,
like the evening wind, which
lets the fisherman sail,
"Out, out..."
Now please stop
whining, like a horny tomcat.
Tomcat? Oh God, what time is it?
Five past six.
[Suspenseful music]
[Excited clattering]
[Door slams shut]
[Suspenseful
Music] [Loud Stomping]
Is something wrong? Oh!
Dear brothers and sisters, all
good things come from above!
Up there is hope
for each of you.
If he likes it, he will make
you, sister, head nurse too.
and you little scoundrel promote
to master crook.
The undershirt becomes the overshirt,
I am left under-tongend and overwhelmingly speechless.
Good evening.
[Keys jingle]
[Door slams shut]
Ah, the salmon for the
kitty, she'll be delighted.
[Lots of gongs]
[shocked] Kitty?
Kitty? Kitty, kitty!
[Cat's racket]
[renewed racket]
[Shocked inhale] Mizu!
[Horror music]
Oh Mizu, what are you doing
in there? You'll catch a cold!
[Fire crackles]
Professor, allow me
to raise an objection?
Do you consider it justifiable to
entrust such a sensitive cat to a human?
who has no academic
qualifications whatsoever?
If I can rely on anything as an animal
psychologist, it's human knowledge.
And I say, this man
is a natural talent!
He is reliable,
punctual, trustworthy...
[The phone rings]
-Hello?
-Ah, Professor.
Yes, on time to the minute.
The reception was a little frosty,
but she's slowly warming up to it.
The appetite? Excellent!
All eaten, Yes Yes!
Oh, salmon rolls,
very delicious!
See you tomorrow!
[Doorbell rings]
[Romantic violin music]
Good day, Professor.
-I'm afraid I have to disturb you.
-I'm not the...
Yes, yes!
I believe that you
are responsible here.
I've been living here since today,
and it's dripping through the ceiling.
Is it dripping? No,
it's not dripping!
Not here with you, with me!
-Then let's go to you!
-No!
- Shouldn't we have a look here?
- Under my duvet?
[Ginger Cats] Oh, wait!
Stay inside, come
out, go in...
Hahaha, there we have the
solution, these oriental cats, like camels.
You drink and drink, and then
you have to constantly, haha.
-But, just wipe it off, Miss Drösel.
-You know my name?
Well, as a homeowner I know,
who owns my home, uh apartment.
My name is Gaby, by the
way, oh what nonsense am I talking.
Speaking of nonsense,
let's have a drink.
Something alcoholic,
or something extra strong?
Something that makes it blue,
or something that makes it green?
Or would you
prefer an espresso?
Otto makes the sound of
an espresso machine.
I think I'd like a Manhattan.
Manhattan or Manhattan
not, I haven't got it anyway.
But, Professor,
Manhattan is a cocktail.
Haven't you seen the film
"Amboss, the Liquidator"?
How is Amboss going to drink this
cocktail right at the beginning?
-That was a Manhattan!
-Aah.
And you don't know him?
You ask me, if I don't
know a Manhattan?
Haha, hahaha!
No, I don't know it.
But I know something better,
the so-called "Professor Flop"!
We always drink this at the
Nobel Prize, that is, afterwards.
We don't want to see King Nobel
twice, one is enough, I always say!
[Swallow, hiccup]
[Loud exhalation]
Have you read them all?
Mostly I let others read, but
this is my favorite novel.
"The little
Brockhaus"""", great guy.
I liked it, how the little one
ventures out into the world.
He starts out as...
[Page Turning]
Eel angler in
Aachen, and ends as
Lemon squeezer
in a cyst on Cyprus.
Great you have it here, you are
certainly happy beyond measure.
You shouldn't have said that.
for now I sing you the song,
from the poor, rich professors.
[Piano unfolds]
[Piano playing]
[Otto sings] We
serve professors,
are also not free of desires,
because there's always
something going on in Hamburg
then we have to go to Munich.
We supply professors,
are lonely, and alone.
Yes, yes my child, so
it is probably true,
So get in tune:
We turn to professors,
with our problems,
The heart hangs in Heidelberg, the
pants hang in Bremen.
We reach professors, are
lonely and alone.
yes my child, that's just how it is,
So get in tune.
Hummingbird, Hummingbird!
Human girl, don't cry!
Uff Tata, Uff Tata!
Well, Miss Gaby?
I’m feeling terribly special,
do you feel especially terrible?
[Loud, metallic hammering]
-What is that hammering?
-What kind of hammering?
[more metallic
hammering] There you go!
So, you hear hammering, that
sounds dangerous.
Little joke, we'll
have that right away.
That's way too slow.
So, now it's right again, are
you listening to anything else?
-No. -There you
go, I told you so.
Great car, how fast does it go?
Ah, the car, you'd better
ask how far we can go.
We can drive afterwards,
You have to see me driving.
[Otto makes car noises]
Right around, left around...
Afterwards I'm always
completely hoarse.
[Doorbell rings]
Someone's at the door!
Wedding bells, those will probably
already be the best man and maid of honor.
[Otto stomps loudly to the door]
Father rests, you should come down,
coal is lying in the garden for the cellar.
Here are your pants.
-How do you even look?
-Huh?
-And what is that stupid hag doing there?
-What? What? Stupid goose?
Oh, ah, AH! An emergency!
The hag has gone idiotic!
Is she completely
or just partly idiotic?
Are you totally crazy?
Ah, it's missing up there, that
comes from a lot of heads in the water.
We'll change that right
away, Sister Anna, see to it.
Sister, wrench, panties! I'm coming
right away! [Door slams loudly shut]
Miss Gaby, I have some
difficult news.
There is in the life of a doctor
a fork in the road, save lives or
Speaking up, even with a demi-god
in white, the money has to be right.
-I'm inviting you on a tour
tomorrow!-Tomorrow? That won't work!
-I have to go to the airport.
-To the airport on Sunday?
Yes, here comes
Amboss, I have to see this!
-I'll drive you there, and afterwards?
-Afterwards? Afterwards...
Could you invite me for dinner?
Then I'll take the
whole day off for you!
[Water splashing]
[Cheerful music]
[loud creaking]
[Otto whistles]
So, Harras, want to see,
what you have learned.
It's 'Turk'! [Loud
smacking noises]
Harras,
a German dog, takes
nothing from Turks, hm?
Harras, again!
"Türk!"   [Slurping sounds]
Damn it!
A German dog, only
takes from Germans!
Harass! [Door opens]
Here, it's from the
German. [Slurping sounds]
-Stupid dog.
-Strong dog.
-Where are you from?
-Uh,
I'm back from the coal front!
And in that state
you want to babysit?
-No.
-Then wash yourself, but hurry up!
Mustermanns finally
don't have a nigger baby!
And be nice to the
child, behave yourself!
[Door slams shut]
And if they didn't
die, they still shave today!
[Mobillee plays]
Floor creaks [Child
starts crying]
[Crying gets
louder] [Loud slap]
[Otto moans]
[Contented sigh]
On TV The city is gearing
up for the new Amboss movie.
This is a rerun, the socks
seem so familiar to me.
Amboss, Superstar!
[Switching sound] Yes!
Become beautiful and
strong, in five weeks!
Through Amboss-fit, Power feed!
Nerve!
[Loud banging, gunfire]
Get on your knees!
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
See now an excerpt,
from the latest Amboss film,
Amboss - The Rabid One.
Now they're repeating all that
nonsense, what am I paying TV fees for?
-The Sandman is coming!
-I wouldn't pay anything for that.
[soft music from the television]
[Sound of a harp]
Professor Otto please,
to children's ward 5!
Professor Otto, please,
to Children's Ward 5!
[Exciting music]
[Children's screams]
[Loud banging]
I come from the future, to
prevent the worst.
The roots of evil lie here.
Where are the children of
Mrs. Modern and Mrs. Talking?
There, and there!
[Gunfire] [Popping
as the cribs vanish]
[exciting music]
Mission accomplished!
[Modern Talking is playing]
Oh my God, what have I done?
They're lying there, oh God!
Hopefully it was just a dream!
[Sounds of shuffling papers]
[The phone rings]
Watch out for the baby!
[Intriguing violin music]
[The phone rings again]
Look after the
baby! [Ugly laugh]
[Suspenseful violin music...]
[Same voice as on the
phone] Look after the baby!
[Child laughs] [Otto groans]
Oh, no!
[Washing machine noises]
[Otto sings: "Weekend
and sunshine..."]
Knock knock The stain
is out, can I come in?
No, I'm not wearing pants!
I know, do you want her?
But don't look!
[Door slams shut]
[Merry advertising
music from the radio]
Tight, it should be!
[Loud screaming]
[Otto moans]
[Metallic screeching]
[Hissing] [Satisfied sigh]
Weekend, sunshine,
and then with Gaby all alone.
And all the professors
scream, Weekend and sunshine.
[Otto whistles]
You Anna, I need your
advice as a woman.
Which jacket suits
me better, this one here,
or this here?
Or this? Right? I think so too!
(Singing again)
Weekend and sunshine,
and with Gaby all
alone... [Door slams shut]
And all because
of the stupid goose.
[Suspenseful music]
Ah, the key to happiness!
-What are you doing here?
-Um, um...
-I've forgotten something.
-What is it?
-What I'm doing here.   -How?
I know again, I would
like a large advance.
-What? Or a small advance?
Oh, the money, why didn't
you say that right away.
But one question
I have for you:
In winter '71 during the Ardennes Offensive
the horse of Field Marshal von Ranzau was
literally shot dead
under his ass.
What was the horse's name?
I don't know that.
Do 5,000 push-ups, but
quick, quick!
Five thousand? That can't I do.
You can't do that.
Then at least make
this grenade live.
I'm not doing that!
So, you don't do that.
So
you admit it yourself:
You know nothing, you
can do nothing,
and you're doing nothing.
And you also want
money for that?
I know something
much better for you!
-Work!   -What?
Today? On Sunday? Right now?
But no. Immediately!
Axis, that's something else.
[Speaks softly, slams
the door] Asshole.
[creaking]
Who has been working
hard all week for others,
He honestly earned
himself the weekend.
Or Harras?
We even make them work for
us on weekends, always on call.
Yes sir.
Already done, that was quick. The
whole yard was full of rubbish anyway!
Ah, the little farm…
The courtyard also seems
smaller and smaller to me,
-I have to check that out.
-Why bother, it's on TV!
Everything looks so much
smaller there, look at the announcer!
Be quiet, she wants
to say something.
Ladies and gentlemen, in
our series with Amboss films,
Now watch \"Amboss
- The Controller".
In this 1984 film, Amboss
portrays a subway controller!
Well Harras, this is a
film for the family, isn't it?
[Screams from the television]
Harras barks] What
do you say?
You want to go for a
walk again? Alright then!
Come on, loser! Once
around the whole block!
Come on!
[Shooting on TV]
[Harras barks]
Once around
the block, but fast!
[Traffic noise]
Man!
Come on,  that
takes too long!
That's enough!
Let go of the leash Dog barking
Phew! Man, finally!
At last!
There you are, stupid
dog, you missed half the movie.
Look there.
Now he's giving
it to him full blast!
That's the fare dodger line!
There they all sit, all
the punks and rockers,
and gamblers, and thieves,
and fixer, and stoners, and
drunkards, and mixers,
and overalls and slit
eyes, the whole damn lot!
Right now Amboss will
finish them all off!
Look! [Gunshots and
screams on the television]
Otto makes driving
noises [laughs]
[Knocking]
[Loud knocking] Come in!
Just a moment, Professor, Amboss
will be ready soon, just one more car!
[Gunshots, screams on TV]
Ah, that is, that is the,
with the punks and rockers,
with the dealers and gamblers,
to the kippers and
fixers, the sows and mixers,
the dungarees and slit
eyes, and all that crap.
Yes yes,
otherwise they Yes
cut everything out.
All the action scenes.
Typical Television.
Do you really
want to look at that?
Shouldn't we go outside, into
nature, into nature?
Right away, Professor, just
the ending, it's totally awesome!
(quietly) Strong!
[Gunshots and
screams on television]
Order executed!
This train is guaranteed
free of fare dodgers!
-And who are you?
-The stationmaster.
Ha ha ha! That's what they all
say! Get down on your knees!
[Clacking shoes
on concrete] Well?
Great car!
Exactly like the one Amboss
had in the movie "The Eliminator"!
Amboss, Amboss, Amboss...
Can you think of
nothing else, Miss Gaby?
Yes, I have to think of
an airplane right now,
in that sits Amboss, and
right away it lands with us.
-Do you really want to go to the airport?
-Where else then?
Then let's try it!
[Engine noises]
Fabulous quiet, the
car, purrs like a mustache,
you don't notice the speed.
Um, shall we go now?
Brilliant idea! [Honk]
Great sound, right? A
special commission
from England's last honk-smith!
I could listen for hours!
Otto honks a lot
Come on, please…
If we don't leave now, we
won't make it to the airport at all!
Then everything is locked
up, and I see nothing of Amboss.
"Here's a traffic update,"
[Otto mimics the car radio]
The access roads to
the airport are blocked.
Please bypass the area.
We'll supply you with
music, to forget Amboss.
Otto starts singing] There was
just something about an Amboss,
Turn it up! [Otto sings louder]
Can we finally
go to the airport?
To the airport? Haven't
you heard the radio?
What do we want there, it's
much nicer here, just the two of us.
I'm just quickly locking
the car... [Engine roars]
Engine sputtering
Tires screeching
-Can you not drive faster?
-Faster still?
Going full throttle then?
But at your own risk!
Engine roars Bicycle bell
[Police siren]
[Brakes screech]
You know,  why
I'm stopping you?
Let me guess.
You are responsible for the removal or disposal
of spoiled goods in closed institutions.
busy, or, you scoundrel you?
You have run a stop sign.
Oh God, I'm so sorry, will it
ever be able to stop again?
And, you were driving too fast.
Oh, you flashed me? Did
the photos turn out sharp?
I'll take three deductions, one for me, one
for my companion, and one for the stop sign.
Would you like one
too?  Then we'll take four.
Show me your driver's license.
Oh, driver's license? That gray booklet? My
mother has that, she's reading it right now.
Now that's enough,
your name, please.
May I introduce, Miss Drösel.
Why won't it continue?
What are you waiting for?
Tell him that you are
Professor Edelson.
I don't think this
upright, lawkeeper will be impressed.
that I am Professor Edelson, and
a friend of the police chief, or?
I, uh,
excuse me,
Professor, and, uh,
-Have a good trip!
-Wait!
Do you know the law
protecting raging professors?
-What?
-Paragraph 1, Section W:
"Who stops racing professors, or
holds them back, or prevents them,"
or hits on, or copies, or
harasses made-up professors,
will be punished with a fine of
not less than 100 Marks! Please!"
Well... uh...
[The policeman groans]
I'm sorry, I only
have 10 marks.
Well, then, let's
turn a blind eye.
The rest you give to the president,
we have to go to the airport now.
[Engine noises]
The crowd screams]
Amboss! Amboss! Amboss!
[Cheers]
There he is, I see him!
He's even more
handsome than in the movie!
Amboss!
[The crowd continues to cheer]
-Amboss!
-I see nothing!
-Over there!
-Can't it be any smaller?
Make yourselves smaller!
-On your knees!
-Amboss!
[The crowd falls silent]
Thank you, that's enough.
Get up, I've seen enough.
[Title music from
the Amboss Film plays]
[Bird chirping] That
was hot, wasn't it?
-To which restaurant are we going now?
-To the greatest of all time.
-And that's us there.
-But, this isn't a restaurant.
But the best cook of all.
And I'll show you, how
Mother Nature takes care of us.
and how abundantly
she sets our table.
May I seat you?
Yes, Mother Nature
has already provided.
Do you mean this
garbage dump here?
Oh, uh, nature's already
got us covered here.
For here the forest
spirits have celebrated.
Dwarf Edeka, and Elf Aldi.
I want to eat something.
Why don't you just say that?
The purest land of milk and
honey, we just have to reach for it.
Yuck!
Trout, totally blue!
Don't you like fish at all?
Do you prefer game?
We have that right away.
[Nature sounds]
What now?
You will experience
a majestic spectacle.
I can deceptively imitate
the mating call of a stag.
It's teeming with delicious
venison here, watch out.
[Otto imitates a deer]
Hello girls, it's me,
your stag, come here.
You are beautiful, beautiful!
[Imitation deer call]
Yes, look there!
The Twelve-Year-Old!
Buster, now you belong to me!
[Shot] [Gaby screams]
Phew, I guess I was
a bit too real, huh?
We deserve a boost for that.
The last harvest of the
banana tree, the forest banana.
[Chews and spits]
A bit woody, but unspritzed.
And without Bananarama!
I want to go to a really
great restaurant right now!
Now?
-Where are we at the crispbread tree?
-Crispbread tree?
Yes!
You are right, Miss Gaby.
It's no breadstick
tree, hold on to me tight,
it is the Fuchsberger beech tree of love!
She has seen all her lovers,
who have loved her there.
Caesar and Cleopatra,
Romeo and Juliet,
Bert and Ernie, Laurel and Hardy,
Thelma and Louise, Batman and Robin
She will also watch over
us, and our children's children,
as we swing and
sing on your branches,
and sway and juggle,
just like me!
[Wood splinters]
[painfully] I think I have
something to eat at home.
Believe me, Miss Gaby,
-Home cooking tastes best!
-Oh, man!
And you really have
something good to eat?
You ask me, if I
have anything good?
Have I, have I!
[Elevator door
closes] [Sad music]
[Door is unlocked]
Hmm, that already smells good!
Yes, what actually?
[Cats meow]
Ah...-
Make yourselves comfortable
already, out on the terrace.
I am meanwhile in the kitchen.
Meow Wait a
moment, first the gong.
[loud gong stroke]
[Crackling and sizzling]
[Piercing howl]
[Water evaporates]
Professor Edelson, I'm
certainly no prophet of doom,
but the fact that he has
only proven himself once,
is still a long way off...
[The phone rings]
-Hello?
-Yes, hello?
Ah, Professor.
Yes, yes, right on
time like clockwork.
The reception was
much warmer this time.
Feverish, indeed.
Do you like it? Sure!
See you tomorrow.
[Phone is hung up]
[Harp music] Do you like it?
I'm sure she'll like
it! [Otto chuckles]
Voilà!
You haven't promised
too much, Professor!
Let the stupid professor
say doctor to me.
What are these formalities
anyway, these titles, these differences
among men, through
education, property,
Privileges and positions?
Why? That's the most
important thing in life.
Miss Gaby, I must
be frank with you.
Huh? Oh, I see.
That's a '64, Rüpelsheimer
kidney buster,
A superior drop of wine.
Oh man, what a coward I
am, but now it has to come out.
Miss Gaby, I must
confess something to you!
You dropped a
knucklebone, and, uh,
the banana trees
are long extinct here.
Now I'm telling you!
Gaby?  My name is,
also I'm not called, I
am... [Metallic knocking]
[Metallic knocking]
Look, Harras, a bone!
Fine! [Dog barking]
And bark loudly!
[Harras barks loudly]
That's lovely! [Harras
continues to bark]
You see? And now
master gets curious,
[Harras keeps ringing]
And gets his ladderwife,
to look over the fence.
And when he sees
Otto's junkyard there,
Bring that hothead
cat back down to earth.
Straight from the
seventh heaven of love.
Yes, a shooting star, quickly,
we have to wish for something.
Just wait.
-Did we wish for the same thing?
-I doubt it.
What did you wish for? I
want, no, I need to know.
I wanted a ticket for
the Amboss premiere.
Ugh, why that?
There they all go, the
whole celebrity crowd.
Whoever comes in
there really calls the shots.
And Amboss is
personally present.
-Stupid dog!
-Excuse me?
Uh, I mean, there, the
constellation of the stupid dog.
And where is the big car?
That can't be true!
The car? My
car is not locked.
I'll be right back!
[Suspenseful Music]
Have you seen Professor Edelson?
Edelson? He's
been away for days.
Oh, traveling? And with whom
was I in the apartment all this time?
Ah, there he is.
That's Otto, our trash
guzzler, he's in the backyard.
[dramatic music]
That can't be right.
[Loud stomping]
Gaby, I lied to you.
Dwarf Edeka and Pixie
Aldi don't exist at all.
[Otto groans loudly]
Gaby...Amboss...
[gentle]Amboss...Amboss...
[Sounds of a harp]
Ladies and gentlemen, I welcome
you here at Madison Square Garden,
to the greatest boxing
event, of the twentieth century.
Here, the heavyweight champion
of all classes from America,
Amboss! [Crowd cheers]
And here, the
challenger, from, uh,
[Crowd falls silent]
Hühneroog, East Frisia, Otto!
[Sporadic clapping]
As a sign that you want a
fair fight, clasp your hands now.
[Loud growling]
[Gong strike]
[Merry music]
[The crowd cries
out in astonishment]
[Fight noises] [Loud bang]
One...
Two...
Three...
Inspiration) You have
to get up at nine!   Four...
What time is it now?
[quietly] Six...
Gaby? You've forgiven me?
But of course, we
belong together.
Oh, nice.
[Sounds of a harp]
You must get up, Otto.
Good morning.
[Guitar music]
[Otto sings] You
are the morning,
I am the dew.
You are heaven,
I am the blue.
You are the vine,
I am the wine.
You are the sun,
I am the illusion.
You are the wheat,
I am the bread.
You are the evening,
I am the Red.
[Chorus starts]
We belong together,
as the day,  and the night.
Us above,
made for each other,
made for each other.
[Music sounds]
-Beautiful.
-Really?
Do you think
they'll like it too?
-You have to figure that out yourself.
-I will!
[Otto starts, stops listening]
[The door opens,
Otto sings] You are...
[Guitar falls down] Gaby!
Wait for me, I'll do
anything for you!
One minute?
That I even spent a
minute with a guy like you.
the one who has no money, looks
like that, and walks around like that?
I could really slap
myself for that.
-Not yet, I'll do everything for you!
-Ouch!
Gaby, we belong together, I
could sing a song about it.
[Guitar playing, Otto
sings] You are hunger,
I am thirst.
You are the liver,
I am the sausage.
How was that, you are the fire, I am
the stuff, you the cough, I the wheeze.
Oh, uh,
you are the morning, I am the
dew, you are the sky, and I am so blue.
No, wait, I'm dead sober.
You are the
beetle,  I am May.
mirror, I am the egg.
Not quite right either.
You are the wad, I am the sea, you
are the rubber, I am the bear.
You are the thunder, I am the
lightning, you are the fries, I am Fritz.
Fritz? Ah, I am the Otti.
[Door opens]
You are spring, I
am the cleaning.
You are the tally, I am the wacker.
Tallywacker?
You are the dragon, I am the fly,
you are the good, I am the bye.
You are the ketchup, I am the stain,
you are the head, I am the pain.
You are the star, I am the fish,
you are the floor, I am the polish...
[Loud banging]
[Guitar strumming]
We belong together.
Gaby...
You are...
[Sad music]
[Rumbling]
Guaranteed beautiful and
strong, through Amboss-Fit power feed.
[Fanfare music]
Beautiful and strong in five
weeks, I don't have that much time.
Maybe they'll be beautiful
and strong, in five minutes!
[Hopeful music]
You know what's
really going on? Mozart!
Under Karajan it sounds etching, how
he drags out the tempi in the Requiem.
Which Mozart are we talking about, the
chamber musician inspired by Haydn?
or from the Mozart
of Opera Senosa?
You can't separate that, Divertimenti,
Neoclassic, that's totally annoying!
Out of the way, I'm
in a hurry! Ha ha!
[Clapping] [Crashing]
Hurry, our bus!
Yes, flee, run for your lives!
Your luck that I have
something better planned!
[Cool music]
Ah! It's a man's world!
[WOMEN]
Ha!
Gaby, Baby, I'm coming!
Where is she then?
Gaby? No, that's not her.
That's not her either.
And that? No, that can't be her.
Where is she?
[strained groaning]
Gaby! [loud inhalation]
Dude, Gaby, you got something?
-No!
-Why are you then like that?
-Because I have nothing!
-What do you want then?
An ice cream?
No. One ticket for the
Amboss premiere tonight.
-That would be so cool!
-There aren't any left anymore.
But an ice cream, Gaby, that
we have. Do you want one?
-Suit yourself.
-And what's in it for me?
You? Just wait and see.
[merry violin music]
Do you have ice cream?
Yes! I have melon,
chestnut, lemon, strawberries,
Cherries, Blueberries, Mocha,
Banana, Vanilla, Caramel, Stracciatella?
Then I'll, uh, uh...
What was that again?
Well, I have melon,
maron, lemon, strawberries,
Cherries, Blueberries, Mocha,
Banana, Vanilla, Caramel, Stracciatella?
One mortadella, please!
[Groaning]
Can I get 4 marks 50!
Cash only?
That's right! Thank you!
[rhythmic thumping]
-May I please?
-Hey!
-Do you think that's yours?
-Quiet please, advantage Becker!
(Clattering of metal)
Who was that?
Get off, Little one, Go!
Hold on a second!
[Ice skating sounds]
[Song starts:
"Like Ice in the Sunshine"]
[Squeaking] [Crashing]
[shocked intake of
breath] Good heavens!
A glass of water, a
glass of water!
-She needs mouth-to-mouth resuscitation!
-Do you mean that?
[That damn laugh]
[Loud banging]
[Rumble]
[Whistle]
[Rumbling]
[Saxophone playing]
Ha ha!
[Bang, then clatter] Oof!
Thanks, for holding.
Look, Kitty, this is what a ugly
man looks like when he's dead!
Kitty? The cat!
[Door opens]
[Door slams shut] [Loud gong]
[Gasping intake of breath]
[Plate clatters on the floor]
(softly sobbing) Miezi! Miezi!
You can't do that to me!
Miezi! [excited breathing]
He's crazy, he needs a
doctor, a psychologist!
P..p...p...Here!
[Paper rustling]
Ps...Psy...Psychologist!
[Screaming in the background]
Edelson, Professor Doctor!
Animal psychologist?
[animalistic roaring from Amboss]
[Loud banging] Why not?
Miezi, now say
something! [Katzenrotauen]
Bitch! [Phone rings]
Yes, Professor?
No, the Pro... I
am the professor?
I am the Professor, yes
indeed, Mr. Schmieriak!
We have a small
problem, with our big star.
Amboss, who else.
[Screams in the background] I
can't explain that over the phone.
You must come here, immediately!
Zoo Palace! But please hurry!
He has to in uh, in uh, [loud
screams in the background]
53 minutes, halfway
normal and top fit on stage!
Uh, you're the
psychologist, right?
Please, Professor, no fuss, you
come to the back entrance.
The password is, um,
um,"The Magnificent Seven".
"'The Magnificent Seven,'
yessir, I'm coming right away!"
(Phone slams
down) But not alone.
"The Magnificent Seven",
Gaby, we're coming!
[happy music]
[Meow] Excuse me!
Is of course just a
purely routine call.
[The phone rings]
When is the next flight?
[upbeat music]
[Footsteps down the stairs]
*Knock knock* Gaby, I
have something for you!
I can take you to
the premiere, Gaby!
"The Magnificent Seven",
Gaby! [Knocking on the door]
Let me in, or I'll come
out! [Paper ripping]
"Hi Bobby, Pit and Benny, I'm at the Dance-Center.
-Gaby!"
Gaby, I'm coming!
[Merry music]
That was quick.
I haven't even hammered yet.
-Why not?
-Because I have a surprise for you!
Good idea!
Such a bastard!
The backyard could
still use some work.
Good idea! [quietly]Such shit!
For this thorough cleaning I
brought you an extra special broom.
What shit! [quietly]Good idea.
What did you say?
-Such shit!
-If I catch you, you!
[Knock on wood]
[Metallic knocking]
[Metallic knocking] [Music
sets in with a rhythm]
Now everything will be alright,
Gaby, \"The Magnificent Seven"!
Ah, she will kiss me.
Uh, I have to get off here.
Chinese restaurant 'Lotus Blossom',
uh, speak English?
Ahem, ah.
You must have an ungeheuer Kohldampf, right?
ungeheuer, monstrous,
uh, [Makes monster noises]
Kohldampf, Kohl,
uh, Helmut Kohl, uh,
[imitating Helmut Kohl]
Ladies and gentlemen,
Dampf, steam,
steam! [Gasping out]
Take care, you go, ah, you go,
you go to the high-voltage
pole, high voltage,
High voltage, uh,
High, high, ah, high, high.
Hi? Hi! High, and
tension, tension,
uh, Schimanski!
[Makes movie noises]
[Upbeat Music] And tempo!
Stop!
One! Two!
Three! Four!
Stop!
Hey!
Gaby!
Stop it!
[Metallic clattering]
-Gaby!
-Beat it!
-Well, Gaby, I can...
-You can kiss my ass!
Now, at least listen to me!
Now you listen, you're annoying!
The way you walk around! The way you hit on people!
The way you talk! Everything about you is annoying!
-Get lost!
-But Gaby, I, uhm,
I can get you in, to
the Amboss premiere.
[Door slams shut]
Really?
Otto...
[Fanfare music]
Something like this I have never
experienced yet, dear guests, dear viewers,
Festival atmosphere here, among the
countless fans in front of the Zoo Palace,
and an incredible turnout of
celebrities in the premiere theater,
where the world premiere of the
new Amboss film will soon take place.
Let me through just once!
"The Magnificent Seven".
They're not getting
in here either.
I knew it, that we
wouldn't get in here!
I'll take care of it.
Yes, this premiere shouldn't
be missed by anyone.
prominent guests of honor
from all over the world.
And here, directly from the Milanese Scala,
Schluckiano Mampferotti,
Mr. Mampferotti, please a
sentence before the premiere!
[Loud burping]
Thank you, for the conversation.
And who am I greeting now?
"The Magnificent Seven."
Then come back again sometime
when the other six dwarfs are here too.
Yes, fun has to be.
I knew it all along, that
we wouldn't get in here.
Wait, we have our
extra entrance, ha ha!
[Knocking]
[More knocking]
We're not getting in here.
Just wait!
[Suspenseful music]
[Window tilting]
Let me in!
-Words?   -Uh, uh,
[Masonry crumbles]
The pipe is tending to bend!
What did he say?
"The ear points south."
'One goal is enough to win.'
The choir screams lying down.
"The bog bodies are flying."
-'The Magnificent Seven'.
-Get the man in here, quick!
I did say, that we
couldn't get in here.
Come in!
[Door slams shut]
Hey, where do I
know your face from?
Which face, do
you mean this one?
Or this?
-Wait a minute!
-You've never seen anything like this before.
- Professor Edelson?
- Exactly!
Wonderful, excuse me, madam,
you are not allowed in.
If you please, row 1, seat
14, for the lady, thank you.
[Excited
squealing] [Clears throat]
Yes, as you can see, Professor,
we have a little problem here.
What do you say about
that? [exciting music plays]
What is...that...?
These are all knots!
-Yes.
-Who would even do such a thing?
Your patient, Professor.
And he has to hit it exactly.
seven minutes on stage.
I don't want him to tie up
my guests of honor anymore.
I think he hasn't found his way
back to reality from his last role.
He IS the Rabid one, now he's
probably going to ruin my premiere too.
Ah, don't worry, that will
be taken care of right away.
Yes wonderful,
you are the expert.
And you have
exactly five minutes.
Here is your patient.
I have to go on stage.
[Ominous music]
[Door closes]
[Excited murmuring]
[Otto whistles]
[metallic clinking]
[loud bang]
[Clink] Stop!
I warn you! I am the wearer of
the black sock. Don't be afraid,
only in dire straits
do I take off my shoes!
On your knees!
But not on mine! On yours!
Speaking of knees, do you
know the story of little Ottili,
as he walked into the
woods, and his mother said to him:
"You Otti, there once
was a little Knackdich!"
[The crowd calls
out and whistles]
Shit!
Curtain!
[Crowd cheers and claps]
Ladies,  and Gentlemen,
Schmieriak Enterprises,
proudly presents,
Live, and in person,
Amboss!
[Drum roll, audience claps]
We all know him,
he was the terror
of the Stone Age,
he was the torch
of the Middle Ages,
Amboss, the Illuminator.
He was the avenger
of modern times,
Amboss, the Controllator.
And now, he is here.
Amboss!
The Rabid One!
[Drum roll, fanfare]
[Crowd applauds loudly]
[Clapping ends abruptly]
The crowd is talking
confusedly [Gaby starts to scream]
Mission accomplished, he's
good to go again!
Aha!
[Loud scream] [Crowd
is outraged]
Hello Mom! [Booing]
Well, my child?
[Crashing]
Holladihitti!
Boos Loud Whistling
Well, how was I?
[loud boos] [loud whistling]
I hate you, I hate
you, I hate you!
I hate you!
Extra sheet, Extra sheet!
Premiere flop due to the
lead actor's utter stupidity!
Extra, extra!
There's no trace of the
perpetrator, Extra sheet!
[sad violin music]
[ominous music]
[Metallic knocking]
Get in!
[Door slams shut]
[general chatter]
[Door opens]
[Door slams] My savior!
[Harp music] Where have
you been all this time?
You have made me the
happiest person in the world.
And not just me, here!
Look, who else
you've made happy!
And we professors always thought,
that this Edie cat had to die out.
But,
what science could not achieve,
that a man with reason did.
and true love to
the animal achieved.
-I always knew that.
-And my rent arrears?
-Ah, forgotten!
-And I can go wherever I want?
Hereby I raise my glass,
and would like to raise
a toast to Mr. Otto, who...
Yes, where is he then?
Anna, I was so stupid.
But I've learned something, there
are people who are truly beautiful.
They are
beautiful, beautifully stupid!
Let the beauties stay,
where pepper grows!
Your pants.
Anna, we belong together,
we don't care about beauty!
Please put your pants on now.
We belong together.
[Harp sounds]
[Otto sings] We are both ugly,
like the darkest night,
he up there told us
made for each other
made for each other...
[Merry violin music]
Shall we go now, Otto?
(very quietly) Anna.
Anna.
You are really no...
You are so beautif...
I thought we belonged
together, because we both ha...
Well then, this time
I'll make an exception.
-Superintendent Rettich is here.
-Please take the luggage to the station.
Right away, sir.
And how do you actually
look? Let your hair grow!
-Holladihitti!
-Stand aside!
Yes, you have to have it
not only here, but also here.
[End credits music]
[Screeching braking noise]
[Cough]
[Frog croaks]
[loud banging of
the toilet house]
[Elephant trumpets]
[Toilet flush]
[Screeching braking sound]
[Choking sound]