(Gentle Music)
(Warlike Fanfare)
Where is my thingy,
uh, that, uh, that, uh...
- (Mrs. Lohse) What?
- The thingy! The black one!
The one with the addresses
and phone numbers.
(Mrs.
Lohse) No idea.
The dog is really lying in
a very inconvenient spot.
No, here it is. Oh, and the business
sections of the FAZ, are they in here?
- If you put them in.
- In here? No.
I got those for myself
yesterday...
They were up here.
Someone always throws
the newspapers around here.
I don't want anyone to take
anything away without asking me.
In 3 weeks, Mother will
have her 80th birthday.
- Do you hear me? We have to go there.
- I'm not deaf!
- And how old will your mother be?
- 80.
Friday, Saturday and Tuesday
are here. Monday of course not!
Here. Monday.
(Marching music)
And when is her birthday?
In 3 weeks.
Do we have to go there?
Yes. You also have a family,
besides.
The man goes hunting
with his club during the day,
and the family
sits in the cave and waits.
Your club.
What? Oh, right.
(Marching music)
(Marching music fades
into quiet, light music)
(Door opens)
- Is Dad gone?
- Yes.
(Whistles happily to himself)
(Telephone
is dialed)
- Good morning!
- Good morning, Mr. Klein
- Good morning, Mr. Lohse.
- Good morning, Mr. Moll.
- Good morning, Mr. Jeckel.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Sir, uh...
- Good morning, Mr. Lohse.
- Good morning.
Hello, Mrs. Pfeiffer!
How is the shipping department doing?
My God, how time flies!
And is the work fun?
- Yes, yes.
- What became of
the little Mr. Dingaling?
What was his name,
this pale one? Hmmm...
You have it on your
tongue and can't think of it.
- Mr. Wiese?
- No.
It's much easier to
remember things from the past.
I know, for example, the
telephone number of my
parents, so before they
moved to Wiesbaden, 1950.
Uhm, I know that.
Uhm... 875586. No, 83.
- Good morning, Mr. Lohse.
- Good morning, Mr. Schambach.
Uhm, and the one of
my oldest sister. 341928.
- Have a nice day!
- Thank you very much.
- Good morning.
- Morning, Mrs. Lamprecht.
- Are the gentlemen from Osaka coming?
- Tomorrow at 11.
- Mail?
- On your desk.
Hello? This is Heinrich Lohse
from The Deutsche Röhren AG.
Yes, äh. Now we deliver the boiler
pipes, compression pipes, rain pipes,
extension pipes, pipes for heater and water...
Pardon?
Ah. Come again?
Oh, Sorry. I am... Then I have...
(Another phone rings)
Yes, I see.
I beg your pardon!
Herr Lohse? Here's a delivery - it arrived for you.
- I am coming.
Yes, that is the typewriter paper.
(Fanfare)
I'm just checking through again.
I still have a hundred-pack.
You don't have an overview there.
The sheet-by-sheet purchase of typewriter
paper is commercially irresponsible.
If we buy in bulk,
falls the price at 500,000
sheets by 35% and so on.
What is that?
Those are the erasers.
Would you please sign?
The General
Director expects you.
- Why?
- I don't know.
Oh, and make sure
that this is cleared away.
(Baroque brass music)
My dear Mr. Lohse.
(Continues baroque brass music)
Please have a seat.
Cigar?
Oh, thank you very much.
You have purchased
paper for our secretariats?
Writing paper.
Yes. With a saving
of over 50%.
Also, well, a bit in advance?
Yes. For about 40 years
with an average...
And, uh, is everything alright health-wise?
Oh yes, thank you.
You married rather late - and have a small child.
- Well, small...
- Can it sit and speak yet?
- My son is 16. He sits and speaks.
- What does he say then?
- Like what he says?
Well, how...
How does he call you?
- Papa.
- Charming, quite charming.
You should have more time
for the boy.
- Yes, yes.
- Mr., uh, Lohse,
I consider it my duty,
on the private life of
my closest employees
- To be considerate.
- That's new to me.
Dear Mr. Lohse, the Deutsche
Röhren AG owes you thanks.
I mean, it's time, that we think
together about,
uh... how you, uh...
can enjoy the well-deserved...
the fruits of your
well-deserved retirement.
- Do you want to imply...?
- We understand each other.
Keep your seat,
Mr. General Director.
For 37 years I've worked here.
We've turned a small, lousy
Mickey Mouse operation
into a big... a... what we are today.
And not you have anything to do with it...
- I don't want you to...-
I'm allowed to say that.
Please.
One moment!
I'm listening.
I'll get it right away.
You already mentioned the
Mickey Mouse operation.
Ahh... yes! That's what I wanted to say!
I ALONE decide when I'm fed up
with your tubes.
I already know when!
Now!
(Virtuoso violin playing)
(Exciting music)
(Sneaking footsteps, floorboards creak)
(Floorboards still creaking)
Ugh! My God, you scared me!
I live here.
But not now, at this time.
And I have
a surprise for you.
Good day, my boy.
(Loud music from headphones)
Where are you coming from?
Dieter!
Well, I'm eating now.
So! Excuse me.
I only have...
Well, I want to...
You put the book down now.
Dieter!
Well, I actually have
good news for you.
- From today...
- Aren't you having any Brussels sprouts?
Thank you, yes.
I actually have
a surprise.
It's no fun,
cooking for you.
- I have a surprise.
- A surprise?
From tomorrow on I will be
there completely for my family.
That's why you can
just keep eating.
My company, so Managing
Director Blume and I,
have us, uh, are we,
uh... are, uh, agreed,
that I will offer my working capacity
in the future less,
also rather not at all,
concentrate on the company
and for that use my experience
more for...for my...
my home... and, ähm, the well-being...well, the
well-being of my family... dedicate...dedicate to dedicate.
Now eat,
so it doesn't get cold.
What are you saying there?
It is a new, more private activity.
What does that mean?
I am retired.
Then I'll get dessert.
I just threw in the towel!
(The doorbell rings)
So you are always at home
all morning?
Yes. And in the afternoon too.
And where, what, what did you...
how do you think...
I think I'll make my experience
available to the household
- and the family.
- Ach...
What is that?
Pear Helene.
That's an apple though.
With chocolate sauce.
Then it's not a Pear Helene,
but Apple Helene.
That doesn't exist at all.
An apple is an apple
and a pear is a pear.
Leave it, if you don't like it.
- I do like it.
- Then eat it.
I am eating it. But not
under the wrong name.
- That's Elisabeth.
- What's wrong?
That's Elisabeth.
(Electrical buzzing)
Do you know what I've
been thinking about?
Well, what is it?
It's not so easy these days for a
woman to run a modern private household.
- Are you listening to me?
- Yeaaah.
And I've decided, that in
order to relieve you, Chairman.
..well, Head of the, uh, uh,
that I will now take responsibility
for the household.
Yes, my darling.
Did you want to say anything else?
- No.
- Well, then good night.
So!
Renate?
Renate!
(Phone rings)
(Mrs.
Lohse) Lohse.
Hello, Rita!
You, uh, is something wrong?
No, no, it's time.
You, it...it's alright.
But I have to talk to you then.
Yes.
No, you tell me first.
Yes. No, right now
it's not so...
Don't let me bother you. You
can talk on the phone in peace.
You know...you, uh, I...
Um, I wanted to...
But it's not so...
It, uh, it also has
time until tomorrow.
Yes, then...
then I'll call you, uh...
Yes.
You, I'll call you
back later.
What is that?
These are the things
for the clothes collection.
My winter coat?! Come on!
You already had it when we
met.
The coat is still in perfect
condition! I'll give it to Dieter!
He's looking forward to it,
when he inherits Dad's coat.
- Renate!
- He's over the moon with joy.
Why do you always
throw away all my things?
The dog needs to go out.
Darling, that's not an
answer to my question.
And the dog has to go
out, when I think it's right.
Wutz!
Wutz, you come here
now to your master!
- (Dog growls)
- Wutz, here's your master!
- Good morning, Mr. Lohse.
- Good morning.
Wutz! Here's your master!
- (Growling)
- Stupid dog.
Well? Did he do something?
He, uh, well, you can't
really see that well.
- I'm going shopping then.
- No. Give it here.
- I find that really nice...
- We discussed that.
That falls within my
area of responsibility.
You don't know anything about what I...
Your husband was 17 years
Head of the purchasing department.
I put the cans over here.
- What would you like? What kind of cans?
- I would like...
2 fish dumplings
and 1 gravy.
You don't have those
put out. Yes, please?
- 1 caraway cheese.
- They would have to be there then.
My name is Lohse.
I shop here.
But I put them next to
the potato salad.
- Then they were picked up. Right?
- 1 caraway cheese and tomatoes.
- If they are gone.
- I want to shop here.
Who was supposed to
pick them up? Yes, please?
- I would like to buy here...
- But I was here!
- Then you stand somewhere else.
- 1 caraway cheese, please.
- Otherwise you would be there.
- Where then? Yes?
Well, where you put them.
1 caraway cheese, please,
and 2 pounds of tomatoes.
I always put them
here. What is it now?
My name is Lohse, I
would like to shop here.
Tell me also, what it should be?
We are not going to get
anywhere with this tone.
So, we have 2 options.
Either I read you the whole list
of what I need, or we go through
everything
individually one by one.
Please?
So then, 1 jar of mustard.
1.29.
1.29. Will it be cheaper,
if I take several at once?
At 10 glasses you
save... 60 Pfennig.
That sounds better. And at 50?
- Mr. Lohse!
- Oh, Mrs. Mielke!
- Aren't you going to the office today?
- I, uh, yes, uh, no.
Not directly.
My activity currently relates
more to the domestic area.
You're retired!
That's one way to put
it...that could be said, yes.
Could you hold the bag for me?
Yes, gladly, but then I
must also immediately...
Thank you.
So. Then I'll just...
I would also have
a cup of beef broth.
I could heat that up for you.
- Mrs. Mielke...
- It would be very quick.
- Maybe another time.
- But this stays between us.
My sister is in such
things always a bit...
Although...that with her husband
was just gossip back then.
He died in a
perfectly natural way.
But one doesn't have to necessarily...
No, no. So then...
Ha! That is...
Mr. Lohse wanted
to ask you something.
I said that you weren't here.
- I must leave right away...
What did you want
to ask me, Mr. Lohse?
Oh, that can wait. I
have to figure out my
life, the means, my
means of sustenance first...
Goodbye.
Brigitte, will you come here for a moment?
Renate!
Renate?
Stop!
Put that back where it was!
How did you get in here?
Through the front door.
- What's your name?
- Kleinert. I clean here.
Well, look at that.
My name is Lohse.
We'll be working
together in the future...
No, uh, scratch that.
Housework requires  strict
organization if it is to be effective.
- Do you have that?
- Yes sir, Mr. Lohse.
The top principle is:
"First think, then act."
That's Mrs. Kleinert, our cleaning lady. My wife.
Mrs. Kleinert, we can
then go to the curtains.
I don't want to
be interrupted now.
I'm in a meeting with Mrs. Kleinert.
It would be very kind if you could schedule
an appointment for me afterwards.
- Uh ... what was that last?
- What?
What I said last.
- "Act. Then act".
- Yes.
- By the way, ma'am, uh...
- Kleinert.
I will lend a hand,
until you are trained.
I want to set a good example.
What principle has
guided your work so far?
Yeah...I would have made
the beds now.
Completely wrong. You finish your task in the
stairwell, I'll make the beds and you join me later.
- So then!
- Yes sir.
(Birds chirping)
- Where are the beds?
- I took them out to air...
Ma'am, uh, Kleinert, our work
schedule is undergoing a change.
We will continue in the garden first.
In unforeseen events one
must adapt to the circumstances.
Uh...best if you remove
the top sheet now
from the thingamajig,
the, uh, climbing rose.
Yes, Mr.
Lohse.
And please stay calm.
We had a very important
message for you. (Mr. Lohse) Oh?
(Muffled harmonium sounds)
No, Rita, you have no idea!
Sorry, the doorbell
rang. I'll call you back.
These are our beds. I was
just quickly with Mrs. Kleinert...
And those are the Glöckners. They
have an important message.
We don't subscribe to any magazines.
- Is this about magazines?
- No.
- No. Will you take that from me?
I'll take care of it.
(Still muffled harmonium sounds)
Please, sit down.
Excuse me.
My wife is a bit suspicious.
This is not meant personally.
May I offer you something?
According to calculations by the
internationally renowned Professor
Pirkheimer, the Venus moon Tetra has
left its orbit and is now racing towards Earth.
Its impact
is imminent.
This means
the end of our planet.
You know, that's very
inconvenient here at the moment.
I thought you had...
Only people who are clean
inside and out have nothing to fear.
This handcrafted brush made from pure
natural bristles, I could let you have for 28.50 DM.
That's very kind,
but I think...
For 32 DM we recommend
this bath additive.
- No, no.
- Even without cash.
If you please want to sign?
No, no...
You will receive our
delivery then monthly - on
invoice with 2% discount.
- Or the amounts will
be debited from your
account, with 5% discount.
If you don't decide
immediately, that's fine.
We would then always
come every Thursday.
Ah? Where do I have to sign?
The delivery for Lohse.
That's getting a bit much for me now.
- But it's your order.
- What? Ah yes, yes.
(Mr. Lohse) You
can put it right here.
- Here?
- Yes, please.
- Goodbye, boss.
- Goodbye.
What was that message?
That was a message
from Professor
Pirkheimer about the impending impact.
It might be the end, the
upcoming end of our civilization.
You haven't signed anything, have you?
I, uhm, no. It will all be charged.
What will be charged?
Uh...brushes.
Root brushes and, uh,
natural bath additive.
1 ton of bath additive?!
No. That's mustard. 150 jars.
Mustard! Well, thank God! The world is going under,
but we have mustard, root brushes and bath additive.
What's going on?
Your father wants to give you something.
What?
Ah, yes.
This is my... this was my best coat.
In this coat I met your mother.
Try it on.
(Romantic violin music)
Perfect.
You can sew on the button.
Great! Turn around once.
It fits perfectly.
If my father had given me
such a coat!
Are you happy? Say something!
And the color looks so good on you!
You can wear this
to Grandma's birthday.
- Say something!
- Great...
- Look, a squirrel.
- Look, a squirrel!
A squirrel!
I unpack my marital problems
and what does my girlfriend say?
Look, a squirrel!
I have been married very
comfortably for 17 years.
(Funny noise)
I had the household, then came Dieter, and Heinrich
was well looked after in his company all day long.
Never bothered either.
- But you did whine.
- Whine?!
That he never has time.
I didn't know what it's
like, when he has time.
Then find yourself a job.
Couples are only happy
when one never has time.
I made us something warm.
What is that?
Königsberger Klopse from a can.
Königsberg was the capital of...
I know.
- How's school going?
- It's okay.
You are almost just barely born and
we are already sitting together for dinner.
At your age I was very
interested in sports.
- For top athletes.
- Hm-hm.
Sit up straight, boy.
Who is...
whom do you admire so much?
- Who do you think is great?
- Michael Jackson.
Michael Jackson.
He was world boxing champion
in the light heavyweight division.
But then Eddie Alersmeier beat him. 1952.
That's something I have a memory for.
What does a boxer live
on when he gets old?
Michael Jackson is giving a concert in
the exhibition hall the day after tomorrow.
That's the chance!
You, uh, the young lady,
the one you met recently, uh...
is that yours, is that, uh...
is she from your class?
Hm-hm.
And, uh, if you... so, if you're together,
how, uh, is it, when you're like, uh...
Look, your mother and I...
we weren't, born
old, so to speak.
Uh... the most important
thing is that one, uh...
Especially when you are young,
there is the body, uh...
that's quite natural, uhm...
so, the physical, I mean.
Men are... and women
too... Think about it!
Precisely, because I mean well. Did we understand each other?
Hm-hm.
Nice that you talked
openly about everything.
Women have their good sides too.
My mother went to school back there.
My brother-in-law used to
live here. But in the back.
27., 28., 29., 30., 1., 2.
Where is the 3rd?
(Sounds of voices approaching)
(All the ladies talk at the same time)
Go ahead to the living
room then. I'll make tea.
Ah, Mr. Lohse!
Nice that we finally see you too.
I'm just getting an overview of the
available newspaper material.
- Heinrich!
Did it have to be today of all days?
No, with timely information, I would have
reserved the use of the living space for you today.
(Mrs. Lohse) Take a seat.
Let's not be disturbed. If it
gets mixed up, I can start again!
- That's chewing gum.
- That was the FRANKFURTER!
What a strong man you
have there, Mrs. Lohse!
Aren't you feeling well, Brigitte?
Heinrich, didn't you want to
go for a walk with the dog?
No. That wasn't mentioned.
Mrs.
Bredenbek, I must ask you to stand up.
You are sitting on the culture
section of the WELT. (Clattering)
No, that's not
the culture section.
But I had it
put here somewhere.
Please look under you.
Maybe someone is sitting on it.
- Please stay...
- I must insist!
Will you help me, Heinrich?
I knew it!
It doesn't matter! I have time!
Why don't you throw away
these newspapers?
I didn't know that you were
into your cultural vultures...
No one ever looks in there again.
How am I supposed to
get the housework going...
I want to see you when I
throw away the newspapers...
I want to know, who drinks
coffee when and where!
What kind of impression does that make!
You are also interested in
having order...
What's gotten into you anyway?
That's Püppi.
(Muffled noise)
Waiter?
They don't like us here.
Waiter, may we perhaps
bring them SOMETHING?
Waiter?
Have the gentlemen ordered?
Yes, for some time now. We
would like two calves' livers.
- I wouldn't recommend that.
- Oh, and anything else?
Homemade chicken soup, but I
would advise against that as well.
And fish?
- Then I'll take the hunter's steak.
- As you wish.
- Do you have pear Helene?
- Heinrich!
That is our specialty.
We serve natural pear
puree with vanilla sauce.
Pear Helene is a poached pear with
vanilla ice cream and chocolate sauce.
Ours is with vanilla sauce
and is always very popular.
Your pear is simply not
a pear Helene.
- How about the apple pie?
- No, thank you.
So 1 hunter's steak.
If I hear
pear Helene one more time,
I throw myself down
and bite into the carpet!
Ach was!
I have imagined your
retirement differently.
This is my first retirement!
I am still practicing!
I just thought... My God,
what are men insensitive!
Everyone here can understand you.
Unfortunately I don't
understand you at all.
- 1 Jägerspieß.
- Thank you very much.
If you should eat right
now, it is not very hot.
- And mine?
- You didn't order anything.
- Then I'll have the chicken soup.
- Chicken soup.
Give it here, I'll do it.
Maybe you'll let me do
something alone sometime!
Here you go, here you go!
I didn't say anything.
Order yourself a
hunter's skewer.
That's mine.
That's right here with me.
Have you ever seen what it
looks like when you do that?
What am I supposed to do?
- When am I supposed to do that?
- Always.
You've already done it 3 times here.
Then that's
a lovable peculiarity.
Do you know what you're doing?
- What?
- That.
May I clear the table?
No, we're not finished yet.
Should I dissolve myself then?
- It would have
been quite fabulous if Mr. Director Lohse had
left the director
in the company - and only Mr.
Lohse would have remained.
- Only Mr. Lohse? "Only"?
I am Heinrich Lohse, happily married, ha-ha!, with one
child and a regular income. What does "only" mean here?
I just want us to be at home now instead of
sitting in your company. Quiet and peaceful.
- Old and fat!
- That wouldn't be the worst thing.
I will try my best.
Excuse me,
my name is Drögel.
I became an unwilling
witness of your conversation.
- I am in a hurry.
- I liked how you...
There are ladies missing
everywhere who sometimes...
Excuse me, but...
We are a well-known confectionery company, the
company Riegel and Klotz, formerly Seidenmann, Bielefeld.
Well, uhm, yes, yes.
We need ladies with joy in the matter.
May I offer you my card...? Excuse me.
I had it in my hand all along.
Thank you very much.
I would be delighted to hear from you.
One chicken soup.
(Door opens and slams shut)
- Heinrich?
- Don't worry. Everything is fine.
I don't make beds, buy groceries,
and only go up and down the stairs.
- If I may! - Come closer.
Excuse me, Heinrich.
That wasn't what I meant.
I know, it's not easy for you either.
Maybe I should have helped you more.
- What's wrong?
- You could have your own kingdom here with us, with your family.
- Aha?
- Just for you.
Where no one... where no one bothers
you, where you can be loud sometimes.
Loud?
Where you can be the way you want to be.
If we tidy up a bit here...
That could be very...
It could be quite cozy.
Something like crafts or something.
And all this is going away.
Then you have space for models.
- Hm...
- Model building...or something like that.
Are there gentlemen retired
everywhere here in the cellars?
Here you also have light...
and water...
Well, what do you think?
Can't I just stay up there?
(Mrs.
Lohse) The Mielke sisters are coming now.
They'll pick me up. (In a
shrill voice) Oh, Mrs. Lohse!
I didn't know your husband was home!
Do you want to say hello?
No. I'll stay lying here.
Very still and peaceful.
Coffee is in the thermos flask,
sausage rolls are in the fridge.
Did you hear?
I heard it!
(The doorbell rings)
(The door opens)
- Good day, Mrs. Mielke.
- Good day, Mrs. Lohse!
(The ladies talk all at once)
(A blackbird sings)
Ach, Mrs. Lohse! I didn't
know your husband was home!
(In a falsetto voice)
Good day, Mrs. Mielke!
(Clears throat, then normal
voice) Nice that you're here again...
- Are you sick?
- My husband just lay down for a bit.
We took some time off.
Very sensible.
That's not quite right,
Mrs.
Mielke.
I am retired.
Mr. Lohse is retired!
We didn't know that at all.
- Why don't you come along?
- Yes, why not?
No, no...
We need more men for our cultural events.
That's really very kind, but
my wife thought I should...
My husband doesn't like poetry readings.
- That's something completely new!
- We did discuss,
that you wanted to stay
home comfortably sometime.
Well, he can still do that!
Mr. Lohse!
Well then I'll just put
something on quickly.
(Heavy string music, Coughing)
(Unintelligible)
(Clears throat and coughs again)
My most esteemed ladies
and gentlemen.
For the 2nd time this year
we have gathered today
to an event of our
cultural circle gathered.
(Clears throat)
This afternoon is dedicated
to contemporary literature.
It is a great pleasure,
that the most important
representative, living representative,
the most
important, livingest, so still alive representative
of
modern poetry could be found, here with us
to read from his work.
A man,
who has made literary
history, a name that has become
a
term worldwide: - Lothar Frohlein.
- Frohwein.
Frohwein.
(Silence, only Frohwein's
leather jacket squeaks)
(Silence, only the creaking
of the leather can be heard)
(Expectant silence)
At the beginning I will read 22
poems from the cycle "Farewell".
- Then...
- A little louder, please!
Then 8 ballads from my early creative period,
followed by the sonnet collection "The 12 Months".
Hereupon 3 chapters
from the novel
"Pedokles" and finally
a tragedy in 3
acts with the title:
"Goethe in Halberstadt”".
Then we will have the
opportunity, to speak to each other.
Melosine...
(Hiccup)
(Hiccup again)
Is that part of the recital?
A piece of sugar always helps me.
- He should hold his breath.
- What do you mean?
One would have to startle him.
Or ask something that distracts him.
Psst!
(Still hiccuping)
Excuse me,
if I interrupt you.
Heinrich!
(Hiccup)
What did you have
for dinner last night?
Uhm...Kohlrabi.
Steamed kohlrabi with fish
sticks and... tartar sauce.
Melosine...
Krawehl, Krawehl!
Dew-hazy glim by the Muses' grove!
Haze groved dew by the Muses' glim!
Krawehl, Krawehl!
(Hiccup)
(Romantic piano music)
(Music overlays
the various conversations)
I always thought before, that
we were living past each other.
You've told me that 3 times already.
I told him what I meant, and
I thought, he had understood!
He doesn't throw beds out
the window anymore, no!
Now he's discussing
with Lothar Frohlein!
- One sausage, for the lady.
- Thank you very much.
Maybe there's also
something else besides men.
What do you mean by that?
One shouldn't
drive oneself crazy.
Let them do
whatever they want.
There are such beautiful
men..., uh, possi-bilities.
Compared to women,
men are really uninteresting.
Pretend he isn't even there.
Ha!
Caught you,
my darling! Haha!
- That was brilliant.
- Thank you very much! Goodbye, Rita.
I thought - I knew you were in town - it
would be nice if we met somewhere. By chance.
I won't bother either.
Pretend I'm not even here.
- Do you have a wish?
- One pot of coffee.
- 1 Coffee.
- Do you know who's sitting there?
Where?
There! The lady with the
light bonnet. That's Lisbeth!
- Lisbeth Prenzler!
- Heinrich!
Well, my fatty?
Come on, put your glasses
on! It's me! Heinrich Lohse!
How are you? You've gained a
bit of weight. It suits you though.
- Is your husband here too?
- I'm not married.
We visited you in Hamburg!
I live in Würzburg.
For 36 years.
No. Your son studied in
Hamburg and lived with you.
- I don't have a son.
- But, Lisbeth!
My name is Käthe.
Oh...
Käthe...
You know what, I'm going now.
I'll call you.
So, I wouldn't have recognized
Lisbeth again. How is she doing?
Uh...okay. She lives now
in Würzburg. Where is Rita?
She had to go.
I have to hurry too.
You certainly still have
something planned.
Yes. But if you ask me,
I would accompany you.
As a dutiful husband.
As a little mouse.
So! So...
what do you want to buy?
Oh, I want to
look around first.
Look around... And where do
we want to look around first?
Ah, that's interesting. Look!
These are these pipe systems.
We sold a lot of those
to Mexico. And to Cuba.
I didn't even know, that
we were exhibiting here.
The whole system works
without backflow preventers.
Interesting, isn't it?
The opening for the
overflow must be at the back.
It is hard to see.
Yes! You can see it from here.
Very interesting shopping route.
Renate?
When are we going home?
I need another pair of
shoes for Mom's birthday.
We already bought shoes.
The brown ones with the studs.
- That was 6 years ago.
- Yes, exactly.
Why don't you ever wear
black underwear?
- Say...
- Yes?
Do you want to keep
looking for a long time?
I'm not rushing you.
Take your time.
How long...how long
do you think it will take...
until you have seen everything?
At your leisure.
- Oh, you know...
- I'm not rushing you at all.
I just wanted to know how
much longer this will take.
- About.
- Just a moment longer.
- What are you actually looking for?
- I don't know yet.
You don't know what you're looking for?
So, I have now seen
everything and now know,
that it is here, also, that i
here really wouldn't know,
- what i still have here...
- Why are you so impatient?
Come on!
I have in 45 minutes,
well, let's say, 2,000
blouses, little shirts
and panties inspected.
That is more than in
the 59 years before.
I thought I would have to set
myself up there for the night.
- What is it?
- Absolutely nothing.
- Wanna drive?
- Nah, nah, you go ahead.
It was nice that we went
shopping together once.
Too nice.
Did you see him?
He came from the right!
No, I don't see anything.
I can't see anything at all!
I'm closing my eyes, because
traffic makes me nervous.
Drive a bit slower
and stay in your lane.
I'm driving exactly 50.
See? I knew it!
No, no, no!
(Brakes squeal)
- What is it?
- You're driving!
Then we'll get home safe, harmoniously
and without a nervous breakdown.
(Multi-voiced horn honking)
My name is Lohse. My wife
and I are just switching places.
There were some disagreements
about the driving style.
(Still honking)
I thought it would be
better if my husband drove.
You wouldn't have decided
differently in my place.
Now we can go on right away.
(Engine stutters and whines)
Here it is!
(Reads with exaggerated accent)
\"The Mini
Piffi 4 was manufactured
with all new gear
and thoroughly tested
before leaving the factory.
The Mini Piffi 4
mixes fast and easily..."
Isn't there a Japanese
explanation for this?
Wait...oh, I see.
(Laughs exaggeratedly)
Now give me that, sit in the living
room and please don't do anything.
Oh, excuse me!
I didn't even see you.
Well...
- Please, sit down!
- Mr. Lohse!
Well, a little sip
now and then..."?
You're welcome.
Do you actually clean up at home
yourself, or do you...
have you got a
clean...a clean...helper?
(Laughs embarrassedly)
My wife unfortunately won't let me help.
I do help her.
You see, and I'm not allowed to.
She has something against my help.
That's probably more of a
communication breakdown.
I think it has something
to do with gender.
That's the old
hatred between the sexes.
That's it. If I see my husband
sitting at home like that...
(Rhythmic squeaking)
A certain aversion
between women and men
- it is quite natural.
- That's right.
Apart from procreation.
- That's it.
- That's a different topic.
My husband always has something
too. Men always have something.
He always has something.
Women and men are opponents,
who only agree in one point...
- One shouldn't get married at all.
- One should rather try to balance the opposites of the sexes.
Men don't listen at all!
We should have talked to
each other much more often!
- Am I interrupting?
- No.
Would you please come over here?
They'll excuse me, I think.
(Mrs. Lohse) Whenever I need
you, you're drunk with Mrs. Kleinert!
Please let me know before you marry
her, and if you want to live here afterwards!
- Should be a surprise.
- This thing doesn't work.
Why not?
Am I the graduate engineer
or are you?
It's a very simple
mechanism.
(Loud bang,
clattering and rattling)
- Hello, Mrs. Kleinert!
- I'm making the beds now.
We're supposed to let them know if we want to live
- here after the wedding
- Goodbye.
That's Uli.
Good morning, I am
registered with Mr. Drögel.
- With whom?
- With Mr. Drögel.
Drögel... Drögel, Drögel,
Drögel, Drögel, Drögel...
- Don't know him.
- He is director here.
Ah, you mean
Mr. Director Drögel.
He is in the fabrication, straight
ahead through the sliding door.
Hello, Heinrich, this is Renate!
Nonsense, Kurt...Heinrich.
Heinrich, I meant.
Where is Kurt anyway? Is he at home?
We haven't had anything for a
long time... How are you doing?
You lose touch completely...
Tell me, where...where
is Kurt anyway?
Yes. Here is Heinrich.
Duuu... Gerti, I'm standing
here in the phone booth
and would have liked to speak to him.
Do you think I can
quickly stop by yours...
Yes? Right now? Yes.
Well then see
you...see you later. Yes.
Hello?
Ah! Madam!
That's really nice!
My name is Lohse.
You kindly gave me -
your business card.
- I know, I know.
I'm glad you're here.
Mr. Drögel, before you
get the wrong impression...
We have been leading
in the production and
distribution of chocolate
bars for 27 years.
- Mr. Drögel...
- If I may still say so, I
took over the company
from my uncle Erich
Klotz, my mother is a Klotz, and run the
company further under
the name Riegel Klotz,
because the block bolt has
established itself as a brand name
and, uhm, because the
term \"Riegel-Drögel" - or
"Drögel-Riegel" isn't...
- Mr. Riegel, uh, Mr.
Drögel, I actually didn't
intend to become employed.
But for private reasons I don't
want to stay at home all day...
Ms. Lohse, I know,
what you're trying to say.
We offer you free collaboration as a
counterweight
to your domestic
partner, to whom you probably
need some distance.
- So that not, uh...
- Uh, yes, yes.
But how do you know if
I'm suitable for this work?
I feel it.
How am I supposed to know,
why Renate has changed?
What about a zeppelin?
We write on it
"Renate, I love you".
Renate doesn't look up.
Or I'll get you the
chancellor for breakfast.
- That too!
- I could arrange that.
- No.
- Then buy yourself a new suit.
- Women are through with such things...
- How is Renate?
Fine. Uh, thank you,
tha-thank you. Very...very good.
But there must be
something, that impresses you.
I'm telling you, Renate
wants to admire you.
That's your whole problem.
Women love about us the
extraordinary, what they themselves don't...
Heinrich, you smoke too
much. Kurt, I quit completely.
Oh, that's just the way it is.
That has nothing to do with...
Say...you watch television.
If there's nothing on at the cinema.
"The Schnakenburg Family". 20
million people watch it every week.
They're shooting the finale now.
They're still looking for a villa for that.
- One like yours.
- So what?
Then Renate sees you
on TV!
- Me?!
- Well, your house,
and we'll get you in there too. I know them all.
Then you're on TV. That
will blow Renate away!
- How do you know that so exactly?
- I'm an advertising professional.
- I know what's going on!
- Oh, come on!
For me your personal opinion about our new
chocolate bar's fall offer would be very important.
My opinion?
The opinion of a woman
of education and taste.
If you'd like to try
this offer for example.
That's a coconut filling with
pistachio foam as a carrier mass.
(Wet Squeaking)
For older people we have developed
the woodruff- soft cream variant.
(Squeaks even louder)
The taste particles unfold best by
alternating sucking and chewing.
- I don't know if you're there...
- Yes, yes...
- Renate?
- Wrong!
- Ah, Mrs. Mielke!
- No one opened at the front.
I think it refers to. You
should be on time...
I'm coming in. But only briefly.
If my sister finds
out, she'll kill me.
(Mrs. Mielke giggles foolishly)
(Mr. Lohse giggles
embarrassedly)
Well...
- Do you have a dog?
- No.
Renate, uh, my wife
and I, we are going to my
mother-in-law's 80th birthday
the day after tomorrow.
Oh?
Yes.
In our autumn offer we have
2 Krokant compositions...
Are there still... I
mean, how many...
at the moment I don't feel very...
Oh! May I...
You have very beautiful hands.
Ach?
How are your impressions
of the collection so far?
Yes, well, with that
one, I liked it less...
I felt better about it afterwards.
- That was Kirsch nougat...
- Yes.
But this one here, the brown one...
Chestnut cream...
Yes, I'm quite...well...
I understand.
And the double nut in a cream coat?
Also. That also.
Are you serious with me?
Do you have something against...
Something not right?
What is supposed to be
not right?
Ah...what is supposed to be
not right?!
I'm sitting here and
drinking a... what is that?
Bitters.
Bitters and I have a job
too. Everything is fine!
- When will you retire?
- Excuse me?
When you retire.
I speak quite clearly, don't
I? Another one, please.
Sometime I'll close up shop.
And then we'll stay on Mallorca.
And there you will then get
on your wife's nerves for the
rest of your life. Have a good
trip! When are you leaving?
When are we taking off? Well…
When we don't feel
like it anymore here.
Who is that ghost
in the knitted dress?
That's my wife.
Charming! With very short hair.
And the fat one
with the mustache?
That was in Bad
Harzburg. I was pretty...
I had a mustache then.
Are there any butter cookies
left outside? I'll take care of that.
They're on the table.
(The doorbell rings)
(Mr. Lohse) Ah, Mrs.
Mielke! That is very nice!
I'm not disturbing, am I?
Your wife wanted to go into town.
No, I'm always happy when
I'm alone, that someone stops by.
I'm looking for my sister. She's usually at home
around this time and I thought that she might...
- Ah! You have visitors?
- Yes. Uh, no, not directly.
I just looked at the old photos
and then I made myself a cup of tea.
2 cups.
Yes.
One was dirty. So I
quickly got a clean one.
And right away another glass
because the other one was also.
..used.
- I'll clear this up quickly.
- Let me help you.
Not yet. I'll just
leave it like that.
We are now going into the kitchen.
Through the hallway into the kitchen!
At home I have to do
everything myself anyway.
Brigitte is no
great help for me.
I'm afraid I have
to tell you this.
She is indeed... I don't
know if you know this...
but that stays between us,
my sister also has a
certain amount of damage.
Oh? I didn't even... um...
- May I make myself comfortable?
- Oh yes, of course.
Brigitte is, as far as
men are concerned,
somewhat haphazardly,
if I may put it cautiously.
- Do you understand what I mean?
- Certainly.
You should have
actually noticed it already.
No, nothing. I have
absolutely nothing.
Really. I think, I haven't
noticed anything.
Men are blind. What
are you doing there?
Mr. Lohse, you want
to steal my shoe!
God, how sweet!
(Piercing scream)
Brigitte! Brigitte!!
Where is this measly weasel?
Where has this sausage stuffed
in casing hidden itself?
- Do you mean your sister...?
- Ha!
We have visitors.
Renate?
(Ominous music, Police
siren in the background)
(Music becomes
increasingly menacing)
(Police siren Now very close by)
"I deny, the break-in at
the house Mozartstraße 4"
to be involved and assure
I don't know the people
involved in the break-in.
Um... Yes.
Oh, could I maybe
make a phone call?
You're welcome.
Heinrich?
(Phone rings)
Lohse.
Here is Heinrich.
Where were you then?
If someone asks
questions here...
- (Dog howls)
- ... then it's me
Do you have an explanation
for this retiree orgy?
You, uh, no.
They dragged me into it.
Yes. There lay that shoe and
I had her bag in my hand
and then she screamed.
The doorbell rings, Gertrud
and Brigitte Mielke enter.
to fight in our living
room! That can...
No, that's not how it was!
At first, we were only two.
I don't know that, I
ran off, you know.
Now be a dear and pick me up.
Excuse me? I'm here
with business partners.
Address?
Günzelstraße 6.
What? Oh, so at, uh…
- What is your name?
- Meisenbach.
Uhm, at Consul
Meisenbach. Don't ring,
I stand outside. And I'm not
standing directly in front of the door.
So please, what should we do?
I, uh, I'm going to forbid
all female neighbors,
- to visit me.
- I am serious!
It's raining now too and
I don't have an umbrella!
Moment.
(Romantic Music)
Oh, Heinrich!
You have something of your
own now with your candy factory.
And I've also come
up with something.
Everything will be
completely different.
(Din of voices)
Kurt?
Yes, my boy? You look good!
So, I am the former tutor
of the Schnakenburgs?
- I think so.
- But I don't have to say anything?
No, you were given a miss.
You will only be carried out.
Also, please no word!
And at 5, half past 5 are
everyone outside again?
But yes indeed!
It wouldn't be a surprise
for Renate otherwise.
Also, Mr. Lohse assumes,
that by 5, half past 5,
the place is free again.
- We're turning the 28th?
- And the 29th.
Then we need Father
and Mother Schnakenburg.
- We're tacking on the finale.
- Shall we continue?
It was agreed upon, 1 shooting day,
Wrap at 5:30 PM.
- Who approved this?
- Nobody tells me anything.
We are open until 7
today and from 9 tomorrow.
- No, no, no!
- Teach that to Mr. Lohse.
(Din of voices)
Heinrich, I have great news.
We're going crazy and
doing the whole finale tomorrow.
The Schnakenburg
finale in your house.
And you did it!
Renate can be proud of you.
- Too bad, Mrs. Lohse.
- Yes, it's too bad.
I am interested in, namely,
not just chocolate bars.
My husband had
great difficulty tonight,
but we then spoke out.
I understand.
I now know where my place is.
Renate, I love you.
You have your bars, Mr. Drögel,
I need my home. My...my nest.
I understand.
(Sentimental music)
(Music fades out)
(Ominous sounds)
Heinrich!
- You cannot go through here.
- Where is my husband?
- Heinrich! What happened?
- Renate!
My God, he should
probably lie down!
- The whole surprise...
- Don't talk.
- I am the tutor...
- That's enough, Heinrich.
- I am here, you know.
- Oh my God!
- Kurt!
- Hello, Renate!
That's great! Isn't
it...? That's just... Well?
What on earth has happened here?
Schnak-Schnakenburg's End
in the house of Lohse.
On Easter on Channel One.
Your husband set all of this up.
Everyone who has nothing to do her,
leaves the set now!
- Is that a new trapdoor?
- What do you want?
Nothing! I'm just Mrs.
Lohse and used to live here!
I can't work like this. KURT!
You... somehow
I feel that Renate
- is not particularly happy.
- But yes!
She is not thrilled.
Women can't show that.
Ah?
(Din of voices)
Heinrich, can I talk
to you for a minute?
- Wait a moment, wait a moment!
- I would like now please
- Speak to my husband immediately!
- Certainly.
Have you noticed that this is
the only place in our house where
- What's left for us?
- Oh.
Am I wrong about that?
- What does retirement mean?
- (Flush toilet)
Please tell me now,
if this is the room, where
we will live in the future!
- Renate...
- It also has its good sides!
We've gotten closer again!
I want to know it now!
Then I'll prepare for it!
I'm sure I'll come up with my
own idea sometime in our house...
Now listen to me carefully!
You're now putting this
whole bunch out there.
or you can live out your
retirement wherever you want!
But not with me!
And for my birthday I'm
driving alone tomorrow!
Who has a birthday tomorrow?
My mother!
Shattering glass
Mr. Lohse is here.
My wife just said,
You should make your
recordings elsewhere.
- Quiet, please!
- Turn it down!
- We're rolling!
- Camera rolling!
- Rolling!.
- Cut!
- 28.4, take 2.
- Action!
- Goodbye.
- Thank you, that's it for today.
Renate? Renate!
(Sad music)
Man, Wutzack, just do something.
(Belts)
Why can't you just
lie on your own spot
like other dogs too?
(Whining)
- Dad?
This is Emiko.
Your father should
take the thin coat.
You should take the thin coat.
Oh, Mrs. Kleinert, you're putting
everything right again, aren't you?
Start from the top.
- Yes sir.
Ask your mother,
when the train leaves.
- When does the train leave?
- At 9:18.
At 9:18.
- Thank you.
- Welcome.
I am your aunt.
Because I am
your mother's sister.
Hm-hm.
Therefore, your
grandmother is my mother.
And my mother-in-law and
your mother's mother.
Hm-hm.
Also your father's
mother-in-law.
Therefore, your father
is my brother-in-law.
- Your brother-in-law.
- No, honey.
- That would be Renata's brother.
- Your uncle is right.
Hellmuth always knows
these things so well.
No, we complement
each other very well.
I always rejoice when
Hedwig knows better.
You are such a good man.
Hmm! Do you know the story
about the community nurse
and the cow?
Tell your father, we don't
want to hear this story.
We don't want
to hear this story.
Yes, yes. Perhaps...
that is perhaps also,
maybe that's not... Uhm, yes.
Aren't you feeling well, Renate?
- Yes, indeed. Thank you.
- I'm actually always well.
Only when you are not
well, am I also not well.
(Coughs)
We were not separated for
a single day in our marriage.
For 21 years.
But we like to travel.
And how are you doing, Heinrich?
Uhm, I'm fine, yes.
I'm...fine.
- So, gentlemen.
- I'll get the ice.
The cake, please.
(Mr. Lohse) For
me, that's.. )Yes.
For whom was the cake?
- We share her.
- We share everything.
Then I can cash in right away.
(Train screeches on the tracks)
This is the turn at Holzhausen.
I'll take care of
that right away.
(Dieter laughs)
One does not mock the
misfortune of another human being.
But if there is an
occasion for joking,
I like to chuckle sometimes.
Your Aunt Hedwig too.
Real joy comes from the heart.
We are cheerful people
and enjoy ourselves together.
I am happy about
your pretty pendant.
Yes, Mother wore
that for a long time.
Too bad. He makes
you look so pale.
(Orchestral music)
(Girls' choir sings cheekily)
We congratulate you,
Mrs. Jensen is turning 80 today.
Long live she,
Now and forevermore.
We wish you a long time
A cheerful heart and
contentment,
Among your acquaintances
and many relatives.
We congratulate,
Mrs. Jensen turns 80 today,
Long live she.
Now and forevermore!
There are still 2 verses.
I think, that's enough now. I
have to eat something now.
Stay calm and sit still!
Madam, You are
light as a feather.
Are you sitting
comfortably, Mother?
That's the 80th now. The
75th was just recently.
No, not with your back outwards.
I always say, Food keeps
body and bowl together.
Soul! Body and soul!
Interesting, that
women can't conduct.
Why can't I conduct?
- I am Pastor Hummel.
- Never mind, never mind!
Here, here, right
here in the middle.
Or no! To the head end!
Mother, we carry you,
wherever you want.
Light... like a feather.
May we sit next to you, Mother?
Sit where you want.
Dieter, for you the ladies
of the choir have set a place.
This is my place. I always
sit next to my husband.
(Mimics)" "I always
sit next to my husband!
(Grandma Jensen) Now we eat.
otherwise I can become
very uncomfortable.
(Giggles foolishly)
- Do you belong to the family?
- No.
Lucky pig.
What's that?
- Herb cream soup.
- Ugh!
That's herb cream with tarragon.
Food is for sustenance. One
does not speak about it.
Hellmuth and I eat
sufficiently, but simply.
Now the mayor is talking!
Lütje, what is it now?
I thought, after the... after
the main course, I thought.
(Incomprehensible mumbling)
(Snickered)
(Glass clinking)
Hellmuth wants to say something.
My dear God.
Esteemed Mrs. Mama,
my highly esteemed
ladies and gentlemen,
Dear family! 80
years! 80 lived years,
of which 47 were marriage
years, the most beautiful.
That's new to me.
Anyway...so...Hedwig and I,
we have been in our
6-year engagement period
mutually exclusive
and are now already rewarded
daily for so many years
through our harmonious coexistence,
for each other and...
Uh, yeah. Man and woman
are they... Or something like that:
Man and woman
complement each other.
If I may just say this freely.
I wouldn't be what I am
without Hedwig, and Hedwig...
Even if we mistakenly
differ in opinion,
have we become particularly fond of
each other. I believe it will be clear ...
Listen here! Hedwig!
- ...what I'm trying to say.
We may be proud of each other.
Our sympathy goes
out to all couples,
to those this is
obviously not granted.
Maybe they'll finally
toast to my health. Cheers!
- (All) Long live she...
- It won't be sung anymore!
(All fall silent abruptly)
Now my bag has fallen down!
I'll be screwed.
My husband prepared
for Mother's birthday.
You and your
husband, this milk roll,
You are so wonderful,
that it chokes me up!
- No, how ordinary!
- Can I help you, darling?
Maybe they will reappear.
Mom asks when you'll
be back upstairs for dinner.
Renate has expressed
herself very badly about us.
When it comes to the relationship
between man and woman, we
won't be trifled with.
And if Renate is so ill-mannered,
she has a problem.
- Esteemed guests...
- We have always noticed,
- that your marriage lacks warmth.
- Inner warmth.
Well! We're missing her.
And unfortunately, we are also lacking
your deep affection for each other.
This wonderful and yet
so humble happiness.
And the cheerfulness
coming from within.
The cheerful basis for
harmonious coexistence.
- Hedwig...listen up! Hedwig!
- Did you hear that, Mother?
Hedwig, the mayor
is speaking with you!
(Slurring) Hedwig,
you are the sharpest,
what I have ever encountered
between Heringsdorf and Borkum.
Mr. Lütje, you just said
something very vulgar!
The mayor certainly
wanted to do me a favor.
I am not of that opinion.
And we are never of
different opinion.
Then please join my opinion.
- Do you belong to the family?
- No.
I apologize for the
lewdness of my wife!
(Dieter) "She spoke to him,
she sang to him,
And he was lost to her spell.
Half she pulled him,
half he sank down,
And he was never seen again."
And then?
Nothing more.
(Everyone is talking at once)
Something is broken between us!
You have taken the innocence
from our togetherness!
What? I didn't
understand the last part.
Did you actually
speak with me just now?
No, I was just
talking to myself.
But now you've said something.
- I wouldn't know what.
- You said,
that you were
talking to yourself.
- Yes.
- Like I said.
Pastor! Say something,
for heaven's sake.
My dear friends...
What a wonderful party!
- No one is listening anyway.
- ...no idea about women!
How do you want to know
if I can conduct or not?
I don't care whether
you can conduct or not.
(Laughs exaggeratedly)
I'm missing something about
you. I don't know exactly what.
Hedwig, you are the
hottest, who ever...
Should I serve the Pear Helene?
- What's that?
- Heinrich!
This is an apple
compote with cream.
2 times.
(Conducting a march
with a chicken bone)
Could it be that
I... that I have been
- Not always quite...
- Yes.
If I now try even harder...
No, Heinrich,
please! Only not that.
But there must be something
provided for these cases!
Rules of thumb or
something like that.
And what if we now
do something together?
What should we do together?
(Mrs. Lohse) It should
be something sensible.
(Mr. Lohse) Meaningful!
Meaningful it must be!
(Extremely discordant
recorder playing)
(Cheerful marching music
overlays the false flute)