(Speaker) As Adalbert Amen
on that memorable autumn evening
closed the church door, he had no idea
how soon he would be a witness...
to a mysterious mystery.
Crucifix!
(Drum roll, applause)
Thank you. Thank you!
(Speaker) He would see what no human eye had looked upon before.
Hear what no human ear had ever heard. He still didn't know
that one day he would reveal his secret to save a great...
artist from greatest need. But let us see and hear for ourselves.
(Music)
Today I bake, tomorrow I brew,
and the day after tomorrow I'll fetch Werner!
Yes!
(Wood cracks)
Ah, how good that nobody knows,
that I am called Rumpelstiltskin!
Hard as a rocker,
hard as a chopper,
hard as a bottle of beer,
it's going hard from here.
We don't go chic to restaurants
and nibble delicately on lobster tails.
We don't smell like Eau de Toilette,
we sniff chain grease.
We ride easy over hill and dale,
only a guardrail can stop us!
Dengel, dengel, dengel, dengel.
Hard as a rocker,
hard as a chopper,
hard as a bottle of beer,
that's how hard it goes here.
Don't put the camper there
or you'll have a tunnel in it!
Don't close them, leave
them open, the gate!
Let us through there,
otherwise it will give Zanke!
We ride easy over hill and dale,
only a delimitation post can stop us!
Dengel, dengel, dengel,
dengel. Hard as a rocker,
hard as a chopper,
hard
as a bottle of beer,
bone-hard it goes from here.
Past the cow and past the
bull, we overtake the police too.
We are the wild ones and uncontrollable,
when we iron over all the slopes.
We ride easy over hill and dale,
only a barrier post can stop us!
Dengel, dengel, dengel,
dengel. Bone-hard like a rocker,
bone hard like a chopper,
bone hard like a bottle of beer,
it's going down bone hard from here.
Bone hard like a rocker,
bone hard like a chopper,
bone hard like a bottle of beer,
it's going down bone hard from here.
Bone hard like a rocker,
bone hard like a chopper...
tell someone!
- understood.
(bird chirping)
(Music)
(humming to himself)
Good morning, good morning dear sports fans!
Welcome
to Werner's sports studio, live and direct
from Kiel's Zwietracht Stadium.
In today's top match
of the Northern Oberliga...
With excellent football weather
the 1st FC Süderbrarup and the hosts
Wooden leg Kiel.
There's a bombastic atmosphere! Around 63,664 spectators
don't want to miss this spectacle. Both teams are in top form.
And there I see the referees!
Helmut! According to § 35 para. ll of the official ordinance,
we have to report before entering large gatherings of people
the proper function of
our service pipes to check!
(Werner) Here the dreaded Helmut Hochbein among the
players, who hardly
hesitates to issue a red card.
In the last cup final he drew
the card without warning when a
goalkeeper bricked up his
goal with 400er Ytong stones.
In professional circles he
is also called "Red Helmut".
The referees check
the correct fit of their
clothes one last time. It
can't be long until kick-off.
I'll take another look in the bottle,
what time it is. Yes... Now it's so far!
Referee Helmut Hochbein sets to kick off. There
seem to be problems. I can't quite make out what it is. Aha,
The referee has a clogged pipe.
We are using this delay
and checking the air pressure of the ball again.
Second attempt: Bruno Koslowski,
Kick-off!
Yes, my dear viewers, the ball is released!
Kick-off from Süderbrarup with
a
powerful shot by Jens Jensen!
Header by Petersen. Parried!
H
eading duel in midfield.
Who jumps higher? Of course
Langmann.
Cross to Bernie Blindman.
The man with the foresight.
The
dribbling king of the Holstein team.
Here you see again: The Kiel team
manager
proved to have a good nose.
For a crate of sprats from
I
nter Milan away! Look at it:
No sprat too many, I would say. The
defense of Süderbrarup is on point!
She rolls from behind across the
field, and attention... Goal! Goal!
Unstoppable! Goal! 1:0 for Süderbrarup.
Unstoppable for Kiel goalkeeper
Würger. But he complains about offside.
Should this beautiful
goal perhaps be invalid?
No, the referees remain strict.
- What is the ball doing in my plants?
(Werner) Kick-off
Kruse. A strong kick!
But there... Hand! Hand! Handball in
the penalty area of 1st FC Süderbrarup!
Who's making such nonsense
here? (Werner) Quite clear: The referee
awards a penalty kick!
- Eckat, come on! We have to go to Hansen's
the heating off... (Werner)
Shot and... Toä! Toä!
Toä. It's unbelievable. Yessir.
Ice cold transformed. This is
the equalizer for the Kielers. 1 : 1.
The goal scorer from
Süderbrarup is obviously angry.
Ouch! Oh! Ouch, ouch.
This will be a hot game.
Corner!
(Koslowski) The ball is caught!
(Werner) Nasty foul by Karl Greif.
- He was just here.
(Werner) What's the referee doing?
He can't decide on the right ball.
There's great
restlessness in the stadium.
It's like hell broke loose here. That's trouble!
- Damn, where is the ball?
Seems there are inconsistencies.
- Ah, there it is!
Hands off! (Werner) The
referee is arguing with
the Kiel groundskeeper.
Protests in the West Stand.
I think I have everything, Mrs. Hansen.
- I'm still looking for nice melons.
Here. Beautiful watermelons!
- With black spots? Strange!
(Werner) The expert is getting
upset about the condition of the ball.
What? Scrap? You
better tell him that.
Here you go, ma'am. (Werner)
Kick-off Süderbrarup, deflected by timber.
Van der Huub gets
tunneled, but strong counter,
Süderbrarup in possession.
Solid, how this team acts in front
of the opponent's penalty area.
And there: a classic Bogencatcher!
What are the Kielers doing?
Are they sleeping? Great save!
The support in the defense of
Holzbein Kiel: Goalkeeper Klaus Würger!
Great! But the danger is not
over yet. Follow-up shot... Post!
Lucky escape. But the ball
remains dangerous. Still Zittermann.
Now he wants to know it! Overhead
kick! Dreamlike! And... Goal! Goal!
Goal! Is that even possible?
Klaus Würger can't believe it!
2:1 for Süderbrarup! That's
football, the way we love it.
The referee tries to
bring calm into the game.
But it doesn't seem to be working.
The Kiel players seem annoyed.
Are we on a soccer field or what?
(Werner) Kick-off for Kiel. Kruse again.
Long. Long!
Brettschneider nails the pill
mercilessly to the crossbar!
Header from Karl Tüffelmeier. But
there: the Kielers are back on top!
Thrilling final minutes!
Blindmann. Grenade!
Goal! Goal for Kiel in the
last minute! A deserved draw!
Some players are obviously not happy with the referee's decision.
- There he is, the chicken scarer!
I'll stamp you into the ground!
- Referee Koslowski tries to calm down the agitated players. But it doesn't seem to be working.
The stadium turns into a cauldron.
More and more players try their hand at freestyle
wrestling. Nobody can stay in their seats anymore.
Kruse smashes the ball once more
furiously across the field. Watch out...
The ball has landed in an
uncontrolled danger zone.
The ball has fallen onto the hot pan at the
snack bar. It's getting bigger and bigger! It explodes.
What the hell is that? Come on, runner!
(Werner) The whole market is devastated.
Policeman Bruno whistles hanging from a lamppost, the poultry man
hammers against it and wants to get at him. The referee whistles off the game.
Well folks, it doesn't
look good for the 2nd half.
The locker rooms are on fire,
the goal is wrecked, the Kiel
players are after the referee...
Overall though, a nice game.
Not quite fair, but fine.
I'm already looking forward to
Saturday when I can present you with the 2nd half
. See you then!
We switch back
to the broadcasting center.
(Laughter)
(Speaker) That's Griesgram the Gruff.
Dreadful ruler over the county
of Geiergrab, located in the Debacle Mountains. Vapors of melancholy
hover about the tyrant's brow,
for he suffers from a nasty ailment.
He has chronic laughter muscle cramp.
- Chancellor!
Chancellor. Was that a funny movie?
Your Majesty, I am
somewhat... I am somewhat...
How shall I say? Overwhelmed.
So, the one scene...
Chancellor.
Did we laugh?
Yes, do... No. Your Majesty
did not care for laughter.
Has anyone amused themselves in this round?
The film, my king, the
film was eye-gouging!
I felt quite ill!
I had to ko...
That went below the belt!
- All devil's muck! Cheese!
So, at one image I already felt
somewhat queasy, Your Majesty.
There you have it!
- Your Majesty, I...
How dare he?!
- I am not to blame! He gave me a guarantee!
- Who is "he"? And what kind of guarantee are you rambling about? - The creator of this art...
work. The draftsman.
A certain Crumb.
He gave me a guarantee on the film!
Yes! Your Majesty, you heard correctly.
A laugh guarantee!
With a mischievous afterthought. I beg to believe,
Your Grace: This crumb is quite the big shot at home! A blast...
I have had something prepared
with your kind permission.
A cinematic portrait, so to
speak. Is Your Majesty agreeable?
Yes.
Water march!
A film document without equal,
Highness! Shot millions of years ago.
And an equally worthy witness
of a momentous historical event.
Our ancestors from the tribe
of Australopithecus will in...
a few seconds cross the threshold from
animal to human-verbal communication!
(Music: ALSO SPRACH ZARATHUSTRA)
Ah!
(Chancellor) Right away, Your Majesty,
the time
is ripe for the first human word.
Gleich is it so far. Gleich
vernehmt Ye the first human word!
(Burp)
(Chancellor) The primeval
sound of civilization!
Transported into our time,
laid in the mouth of an inconspicuous
comic figure named Werner.
That was the starting shot for a
boom, like the world had never experienced before!
Werner began, life
to turn humanity upside down.
No one was able,
to escape Werner.
He was THE sensation!
Read aloud.
- Always remember:
Don't be stingy with the oil!
Okay.
(Chancellor) Even in the hottest regions
he won over the hearts of the population.
Hold on, hold on!
(African)
(Chancellor) Even in the coldest environment
Werner played an important role.
Werner assure you that you are telling the truth
and nothing but the truth.
Then lick your hand and repeat after me:
Yes, I Werner.
(Burp)
Hereby I baptize you
in the name of Werner.
(Chancellor)
A name long thought extinct
celebrated a legendary comeback.
- Werner? Stand up!
(Chancellor) Even the composers of contemporary
choral music could no longer bypass Werner.
(Everyone burps)
Enough! That's it, stop it now!
When Brösel, the creator of
this Werner, heard about you,
He made his way from distant Hedwig-Holstein,
especially to cheer up Your Majesty.
And here he is!
Welcome, Mr. Brösel!
Moin, moin.
- Oh, he looks good!
(Incomprehensible muttering)
(Brösel) Good morning.
He looked at me.
- He looked at me!
Hi Chief!
- No, Mr. Brösel!
He's standing in front of the king!
- There he is,
in full size.
That snob.
Brösel, Your Majesty. Brösel.
- Chancellor! Does he want to lecture us?
This knucklehead then
wanted to teach Us how to laugh!
And?
Did We laugh?
(Incomprehensible muttering)
God forbid, Your Majesty!
No.
Dumb and Dumber are dead.
Balduin, the holiday scare: dead.
Heinz Erhardt: also
dead. Karl Valentin: dead.
Buster Keaton: dead. So?
Does he notice anything?
Or does he think, the
plague wiped them out?
Well then! Show
him, what happens to
jokers who are
unable to cheer us up.
(Suspenseful music)
But that's the...
- Him too!
(Otto) Don't tickle!
- Yes, yes! That's him!
(Otto laughs)
He was always my favorite comedian.
Well? Has he noticed properly?
So. We give him...
three days. Should it however
not succeed for him by the
deadline, to make us even
the smallest chuckle, then…
(King) Wilhelm Busch is
dead. Heinz Erhardt: also dead.
Karl Valentin: dead. (Brösel)
Woody Allen... also dead?
His glasses!
Helicopter!
(Speaker) He knows: The conditions are bad for
drawing masterpieces. Yes, does he even have a chance?
(Suspenseful music)
If my pot breaks in two,
it doesn't matter to me.
Whether happiness or
glass shatters, what do I care?
But if a pencil is
broken, I will crawl over.
To help the breaker, and
what does the speaker say?
So, for humanitarian reasons
this person is certainly not here.
Brösel, be careful!
- You don't have to stand on the block of the bloody woodpecker, you have Brösel, you
the magic pen.
In its middle lies concentrated power! Use it, and
I swear to you: The king will piss himself laughing!
But you will be free. So take it.
Hey, hey. Not so greedy, my friend.
Nothing is for free not even Death
himself. You have to promise me something.
I have one wish free, otherwise nothing.
- I'll do it! When I get out of here, I'll grant you any wish! - One, my best.
One is enough. But on the sly.
So, what is it? Attention, recording.
Ok, when I get out, I
will grant you one wish.
And this thing works?
- Absolutely, my best!
He has already served Albrecht Dürer! Do you know the hare
with the praying ears? Well! It was drawn with that.
Good.
- Watch out, my best. Little tip: Draw a joke from your youth. It always goes down well. The king curls up.
Then!
Good laugh and ... see you soon!
Hey, Zatopek, get excited!
What luck, the master overslept!
Tell me, Werner, does it have to be
that the moped is so loud?
Morning, master. The
muffler fell off. Sorry.
Ah, here comes Eckat.
Eckat. Well? Are you already here too?
Good morning, Mr. Röhrich, half past eight.
- So?
Eckat, my wife isn't
here! I think it's time.
Can you runner go have a look in the
cellar? I think the Russians are there.
I'll do it, boss.
And you don't have to tinker with the
moped. You can do that at home too.
Yes, master!
Werner? Can you come and take a look
here? Behind you, there's a piece of coal.
Pick that up. And then you can
put it with the others in the cellar.
Yes, master. Well, Eckat?
Have you found the Russians yet?
Since the explosion the other day on the
construction site the old man has a different weapon.
(Telephone)
Sanitary installations, heating construction,
climate and swimming pool technology, Röhrich.
This is Mrs. Hansen speaking.
My heating system is rumbling.
Especially at night when I want to
sleep. And it's leaking too. It's unbearable!
Yes, Mrs. Hansen, I understand the problem. I ask you:
Has a sniff piece already been installed with you?
A what?
- A self-acting vent.
In specialist circles
also called a sniff piece.
What?
- Yes, I believe, Mrs.
Hansen, I'll stop by with my men. Yes, Eckat! Remember last week?
When he wanted to explain the function of the bolt gun to the masons?
Or: Giv me mol her. Not
everyone can keep up with that!
Let me do it.
And he is so stupid and
shoots his fins off with the thing!
Ah! My hand! Eckat! Werner!
Eckat! Get a bandage, I'm bleeding to death!
- Ouch! Ouch!
What's going on here? Do
you want to make a fool of me?
Eh... Hello, Mr. Röhrich.
There aren't any Russians in the cellar.
- What's this circus here?
Why are you eating my coal?
- Ouch!
Men, you have to go, at
Hansen's in Südergraben.
Put a sniffer in. And
install the washbasin.
And the radiator is
still leaking. Werner!
The IDEAL-Standard basin is upstairs
in the warehouse, you get it now.
Be careful not to break it. Eckat,
get the truck out of the garage.
Yes, master.
Huh? Look here, Eckat.
There's a valve here. You Eckat?
Where does this come from?
- We took that out recently.
It still looks good. Is it
not working anymore?
He's still good! Does it have to be
that he rusts around here like that?
Werner! Take the wire brush
and make the slider shiny.
Then you put him in storage.
- Yes, master. Great chief.
Did you bring everything?
Then let's go! Werner!
Where are you staying?
- Coming, master, I'm hurrying.
Eckat and Werner. Now listen
to me. When you're with Mrs.
Hansen, please take a look at
the furniture. I know Mrs. Hansen.
She always gets so angry!
(Eckat) Yes, yes, boss.
So, Werner. We'll go up to
Mrs. Hansen. It's on the 4th floor.
You carry the things up.
Hello, Mrs. Gloer.
- Get your feet off!
Yes... should I do
that, Mrs. Gloer?
Come on, Eckat, the day is short!
We're supposed to lay a piece of
pipe here at Mrs. Hüpenbecker's.
Hey, you rascals!
Please take your feet off!
Leave me alone, old spinach owl.
Stop! I just mopped!
Just mopped!
Yes, yes, yes!
- Werner!
Are we at a bachelor party here?
Just mopped fresh! Everything dirty!
The beautiful IDEAL standard basin!
- Can't do anything about it, master.
Werner, you're ruining me!
- She's to blame with her scrubbing brush!
Dirt! Dirt! I just mopped!
Is that too much to ask?
Want to get your feet moving for a bit? But no!
- Now just shut your beak!
We are in a completely
different predicament, Ms. Gloer!
I'll give you something to worry
about! You clean up this mess here!
Ugh! Now be reasonable
for once. Calm down!
Just lie down,
we'll take care of it.
Eckat! You fix the leak
on the radiator at Mrs.
Hansen's. I'll get a new
IDEAL-Standard. And Werner,
you clean everything up here again.
- Yes, master.
But properly! First
sweep together, then
mop and then polish
everything sparkling clean!
Yes?
- Good day, Mrs. Hansen. Company Röhrich.
Gas, water, shit.
- The craftsmen! Are you here already too?
Well! Isn't the boss here at all?
Well, come in. But
take off your shoes!
It's leaking here. I've tried
everything, but it just won't stop.
You hear what your boss said.
Everything has to be sparkling clean again!
And I'll check that! It's always
the same with the craftsmen.
Be careful with the carpet! I
put plastic bags down extra.
And if you want to
smoke: There's the ashtray.
But be careful with the
curtains. I just washed them.
And the heating is freshly
painted. What about the sink?
Shouldn't that have
been done today?
- Mr. Röhrich is on his
way and bringing one.
Here I am! Here are
the other things, Eckat.
Good that you're here, Werner. You
have to hold up here for a moment.
My carpet! Shoes off!
- Good day, Mrs. Hansen.
I bring your sink.
- How nice, Mr. Röhrich.
Come with me to the bathroom right away.
That I am Röhrich,
every child knows that.
Now we two will first have
a liqueur before we start!
No, I won't!
- Oh, come on, you can have one!
Yes, but...
- Well then. Cheers, Mr. Röhrich.
Cheers!
- And another small one?
Well, okay. Cheers.
We can still have one.
- Well, alright. Okay then.
Cheers. That's enough now.
One more, because that's it!
- Yes, if there has to be one more...
But then it's over. Cheers!
No point. After the party comes the
hangover. The screw connection...
is all messed up, you. We
have to drain some water.
Fit a new valve, Werner.
- Well, if you think so, Eckat.
One more!
Were you at the hairdresser's,
Mrs. Hansen? You look so good!
You too, you scoundrel!
Ah! Nanu! How do I look?
I'm embarrassing myself! Hick!
Man, I'm so stupid. (Werner)
You can say that again, Eckat.
Hick!
Eckat, Werner! What's wrong
with you? What are you doing?
Are you ready? Are you drinking?
- No!
We can't do anything. The connection
is gone. We need a new valve.
What? That's impossible!
Let me try it!
No, no, no!
Give me the pliers!
It'll still work, Eckat.
Come on, help me.
Röhrich, I would leave that alone.
- Werner! There's a complete pipe lying there.
We'll use it as an extension.
- Yes, Master.
Come on, Werner!
- If this works out at all.
Röhrich!
- Don't talk nonsense! It will work!
That's tearing off!
- Let's see how this
starts. One, two...
Ah! Eckat!
Help me!
Eckat, what's going
on? Call Mrs. Wagknecht!
Eckat! What are you doing?
Pull me out of here!
Werner! Help me!
Pull now!
- Eckat! I can't hold on anymore!
Call my wife!
Eckat? Eckat! I think,
we tore off the valve.
Why us?
- I think it was you, master.
Men! Do something! If
Mrs. Hansen sees this!
How unpleasant! This is
embarrassing for me. The nice carpet!
The handwheel is stuck! Quickly,
quickly, where's the wrench, men!
We can't find it.
The water is so dirty.
Werner! Run runner to the cellar
and let the water out of the boiler!
Who, me?
- And get a few rags!
And some stoppers! And don't
forget my rubber boots! Hurry up!
Now the salad is hammered.
Everything is wet now.
- Eckat! Old man, get out of here!
I'm bailing here!
- Hi! Mr. Röhrich!
For God's sake, my apartment!
Maybe the old lady has a key!
Come on, come on! Open up now!
What are you ringing for at noon?
- I need the key
to the boiler room.
- What does the hallway look like?
Up and down! Should I mop again?
- Yes... No!
But the key…
- That's enough!
The purest Sodom and Gomorrah!
- Hurry up, you nagging goat.
Clean up! But suddenly, you good-for-nothing!
- I need a basement heating key!
There's a burst pipe up there
and we have to drain the water!
You have to ask for
Biernot on the 1st floor.
Good heavens!
- And who's cleaning the hallway?
What's going on?
- I need the key!
Which key?
- Heating cellar.
Why?
- Burst pipe, upstairs at Mrs. Hansen's!
Werner! What are you doing?
Why is this taking so long?
He won't give me the key!
- The key, man!
We have a mess up there!
Stop! Come here! My toilet is overflowing!
- My wallpaper!
Out of the question, you're staying here!
- Leave us alone!
We have quite other
problems! Ouch! Let go!
You should let me go!
- First you fix my toilet!
Werner! Don't go in the cellar! Help
Eckat! And calm down Mrs. Hansen.
Yes, Master.
- Come here.
I flushed my dentures down the toilet.
- We'll take care of that right away.
Mrs. Gloer, well? There are still
all sorts of other things in there.
Oh, no?
- Oh! I think I got him.
How nice, Mr. Röhrich.
- Well! I'm stuck!
That's terrible!
- My arm! I can't get loose anymore!
I'm helping you. What are you doing
then? You're doing everything completely!
Eckat!
- Mr. Röhrich!
Eckat! Werner!
- My toilet!
Werner! I'm stuck.
Eckat, Werner! Where am I?
- My toilet!
Eckat! Where are you?
Eckat, Werner! Report!
Do you guys no longer want to talk to me?
Eckat! Can you take a look? I
have something on my head.
I also have dirt on my mouth,
and nobody tells me anything!
(Eckat) He's coming up again.
- Great pumpkin! 5.8 points, I would say.
Who hasn't had one yet, who wants to
go again? A small donation for the master!
Yes sir, ladies and gentlemen!
Pay attention, here he comes again!
What will he show us this time?
Yes! A brilliantly executed mud
wrestler in reverse! Applause!
- Is everything alright with Mrs. Hansen?
Have you had lunch yet?
Unbelievable. Him too?
Oh!
Well, what day is
it today, people?
Friday, Your Majesty.
- Ramadan, Your Highness.
Ah, what! Father's Day!
- No! Carnival Monday!
Because today is
All Saints' Day, you.
.. carp, the delinquent
has the last word.
Hey! The last word.
We trample through grain,
we trample through the seed.
Hooray, we are becoming
stupid, the state pays for us.
(Speaker) Calm down, Crumbs. No panic.
You were sleeping, you had a bad dream.
Now you're awake, boy.
Now face reality.
(Exciting music)
You have visitors, Crumbs.
(Speaker) How could Crumbs
possibly get into that one?
Film producer Gerd Geldhai, also
known as "Kraken" in his circles.
Rich and notorious for films
like "Rumble at the Maternity
Clinic",
\"Unwilling Gynecologist" and "Phone Book Trucchio".
This man walks over corpses.
Oh, Crumbs. What have
you gotten yourself into?
May I ask what this is supposed to be?
- That's the point.
Schulz!
There, take a look.
Well? Can you laugh about it?
- No.
That's a damn fine strip.
Great story. Drawn excellently.
Or what?
But under this pressure I
cannot work. Deadline allergy.
Brain block. Creep already
nightmares.
- You signed a contract.
Can't we cancel that? Let's just
forget about the whole thing, okay?
Good! So let's forget about it.
I'll give you the contract back.
And you, joker, refund me the money I've
buttered into our dwarf-nose project so far.
Too much.
Too much
for a man like you.
to make it so easy to
cut it out of your ribs.
I'm turning off the tap for you, my dear.
You'll unfortunately have to move out here.
No more own car.
Your motorcycle? You will no longer have even
the money for a decent pair of shoes in the future.
And now... Tear it up.
Smart boy.
And now give it your all.
Come up with something!
I'm also getting some ideas, for example,
that you have a premiere in 4 weeks.
(Speaker) Did Crumbs
hear that correctly?
Premiere in 4 weeks? Only
a miracle can help him now.
(Rumpelstiltskin)
Watch out, my best man.
Little tip: Draw a comedy from your
youth. That always goes down well!
(Röhrich) Mason, carpenter...
Joiners... And not one
for the sanitary area!
Am I supposed to handle the work alone?
No, no! How is this supposed to go on?
I don't know...
Good morning, master!
- Werner!
Do you actually know how late it is?
- Sorry, master.
My moped wouldn't start. The carburetor.
- It's always something with this crappy moped.
Buy yourself a bike! I
couldn't afford that back then!
Eckat is already gone with the
truck, to the construction site.
I'll ride there on my moped.
- Yes, get on with it!
(Phone)
Well! So early?
Sanitary facilities, heating installations,
climate and swimming pool technology, Röhrich.
This is Eckat.
We still need a radiator.
10 on 160 on 90. And
the gas canister is empty.
Why? It's brand new! You
must have not turned it off!
Ui, ui!
Werner! Wait!
Damn cable! What crap!
Get that thing out!
- Yes, master.
Eckat called. You're supposed to bring
something else along. A gas canister.
And a 160 radiator. Get going!
- Yes, Master.
Gas canister.
(Groans)
That's heavy!
Ah!
Master?
How am I supposed to get all this?
There's a trailer in the shed.
You put it on there! So, then.
No, no, Werner,
he's not with it at all.
He's not exactly new anymore either.
How am I supposed to hook that up? Great! I
asked the boss, and I'm getting a new towbar!
Master?
- What else?
I have to go to Bicycle
Meier first! I need a towbar!
Man, are you stupid! Come
on, I'll get it for you! Werner!
Use your brain for
once. You take it like this.
Now look! A piece of welding rod.
And then you wiggle this around like this.
That's good then!
- Yes, master.
Load the stuff up. You're late.
- Ready, master!
Quick, Werner! Now go!
You know, I kiss hot. You
know, I burn right away.
You know that I always achieve
everything, everything. I am a man.
Hey-ey-ey! I am a man!
Oh yeah, remember: I am a man!
Why are you treating me like a big child? My kisses
burn hotter than the desert wind. I am a man. Hey-ey-ey!
I am a man!
Oh yeah, remember...
Awesome! Now it's downhill all
the way to the construction site!
My brakes are giving out. Ah!
Just a bit more. Just a bit more. Careful!
A lunatic! Oh, help!
Shit! Ah!
(Evil laughter)
He's giving Toppy some competition!
- Really strong, you! Nice thing!
5.
8 in the B-note, I'd say.
Did you bring beer? - Nope.
Then run to the store and get 5 beers and make sure they come up here. The
radiator has to go on the 4th floor. Don't forget to hook up the gas bottle.
Yeah. Nope.
- Hurry up, the foreman is coming soon!
Alright, Eckat.
Stuck too deep in the mud. I'll never get this out!
That's going to get me yelled at by the foreman!
And I have to get beer, too, otherwise
there will be nagging from Eckat.
Damn! Where is that boy?
(Sings to himself)
Well, well! Eckat!
Yes, what's wrong, boss?
- So, are you guys sleeping up there?
Make sure the stuff
comes up. (Puffs)
Oh right. I actually still
had something planned.
Just hurry up! Eckat is thirsty!
Here Eckat, your beer.
- Did you connect the gas canister?
Gas canister? No, not quite.
- The old man is here! Nothing is done!
How am I supposed to stand now?
- How am I supposed to get this junk
into the 4th floor anyway? Somehow
I have to pull the cart out of the mud.
Of course! With the crane!
I always wanted to try that.
Push me three crowns over.
- Yeah!
How often do I have to tell you, you
drunkards? Don't you understand anything?
A thousand times I've told you, you should
wear helmets on the construction site!
That's mandatory! Everyone
has to stick to that, clear?
Not so easy. Everything
looks easier from below.
If a stone falls on your head, what then? For the last time: Helmets on at work!
- Boss?
Yes, what else?
- Up there...
(Unintelligible)
Well, not bad, such a helmet.
- Lonely peak.
But original.
- Oh, but that's swinging!
Cheers, guys, to the helmets!
Chug this shit!
Oh, wrong way.
Now there's a burst pipe.
I'll have that right away.
I'm going crazy! What is
this kid doing in my crane?
Okay, up with it.
Oh, that's too hard.
Warsaw!
Oh dear!
Hey guys, look! Old Röhrich!
I haven't even wiped yet.
Werner!
You're a troublemaker!
- Great performance!
I'm embarrassing myself!
- Oh! I've exposed my master.
That's going to cause trouble!
- Werner! How are you putting me here?
You can't do that!
- Werner! Come over here!
I'm embarrassed! In
front of all these people!
"Werner! You're a troublemaker!"
Want a sip?
- What's so funny here?
Eckat! I didn't expect that
from you! What a disgrace!
That wasn't on purpose!
- Why is your apprentice drinking beer?
I'll help you out! What
about the main line?
Are the holes drilled? And the
connections? What am I paying you for?
You can do fancy stuff at
home! I need this finished today!
I have to go to the construction
management. I'm counting on you!
Yes, yes.
- What does "yes, yes" mean here?
\"Yes, yes" means: Suck my dick!
You stay here until it's done!
Man, he's in a good mood today!
I'm gonna laugh about this. I'll
continue on my own. I'll get us some beer.
Yeah, Eckat.
Eckat is gone. Finally,
can I make my bomb.
There! This plastic bag is just right.
So! Schön dicht zwirbeln.
Gas and oxygen... That
has to sizzle, it has to.
Werner?
- That's Eckat! What does he want?
What is it?
- Come down here!
What now again? I'm coming!
Yes?
- Today we're not working anymore.
Over to the Maurers. They're giving a party.
- Yes, but...
No buts. As an apprentice
you have to obey.
Yes, Eckat.
Everything has to be finished by
tomorrow. How far are your people?
They know.
They're working overtime.
I ordered it that way.
- Perfect.
If you wait a moment, I'll
see about some pipe sections.
Whether they're enough too.
- Yes, yes. That's fine.
Yes! One meter... Äh...
One fifty-five...
What's that nonsense again?
- I measure 1.26!
Eckat! Werner!
Eckat! The Russians are here!
Eckat! I want to go home!
I have to go to
bed. I can't anymore.
I don't want to anymore.
Eckat, where are you?
It's alright, Chief. I'll drive you home.
- Oh, he looks so strange.
What's wrong? What happened?
Are you alright, Chief?
- Did I measure incorrectly?
This way.
- I didn't want to break anything.
Oh dear, that was a
bang. Look at the top floor.
Yes, it's completely gone.
- Luckily, tomorrow is vocational school.
(Music)
(Telephone)
(Burp)
Brösel! You should learn
to speak proper German!
And anyway: Where are your drawings?
I don't pay you for pleasure! The drawing studio is waiting for your designs!
- I'm on my way to the post office.
Everything clear? Goodbye.
Hello!
(Music)
(Phone)
What? Hot water bottles?
Are you crazy, man?
That doesn't interest me!
You will deliver, is that clear?
(Narrator) Now he doesn't have much
time left. Only two and a half weeks.
Should he give up?
- Don't talk nonsense, man!
He won't give up! Listen, Crumbs?
(Music)
(Gerd) I'm turning off
the tap for you, my dear.
Your motorcycle? In the future you won't
even have the money for a decent pair of shoes.
(Music)
Ach.
Ah!
- Good morning, Mr. Engineer!
Can you register my
new turn signal system?
Are you trying to pull a fast one on me? There
are no indicators there! According to the ABE...
Nonsense! This is not a
conventional turn signal system either.
Here in the middle of the handlebars
the sausage magazine is clipped
in, and here a spring mechanism is
activated with the push of a button.
A so-called conservative
sausage blinker.
Am I supposed to sign this off?
- Yes, I will accept it.
Well then, blink left for me.
Well, what's wrong?
- Tastes a little bland.
What about mustard? Is it better now?
Better now? Sausage blinker?
Such nonsense! Get out of here, man!
Don't you like it? Wait! My turn
signal system is variable, you know.
How about peas and carrots?
Or Labskaus?
- No!
You don't like that
either? (Unintelligible)
Because I still have beetroot
with celery. It also goes well!
Leave the premises immediately!
No entry?
- No! Not a bean!
I also have beans with mixed
vegetables! What do you think of that?
No! No! No!
Hey, Herbert! What do you want here?
- Hello. I have a beer can holder here that I want to get registered. - Forget about it.
Is he in a bad mood?
- He's not making any entries today.
(Pubs)
Damn TÜV. Always the same.
There was a crazy guy with such handlebars.
- Look there.
What kind of exhaust system is that?
- That's not original!
And there, the backrest! Neither.
- The footrests either!
Those are forbidden!
- Not bad, your beer can holder.
My point!
- Should I tell you something?
These TÜV guys are just
not quite right. Zero checking.
Do you want a sausage?
- Let's go, dude.
There! Look at it!
- Protective workshop.
I know that.
- Here, Günna! The slob!
Unbelievable!
- Unthinkable!
And there?
Dieter! Dieter! I'm stuck!
Hey, look.
The handlebars!
- Dieter, come on, pull!
That is just catastrophic!
Hey, you guys! Don't mess around like that!
- Install a beer can holder instead.
They don't comply with the regulations!
- They should be taken off the road!
Both of them!
- What? Taken off the road?
That won't work, it's illegal!
That's what a motorcycle looks like!
What? Original junk?
That's how it should be!
What? Chopper? Not with
us! Sharp edges everywhere!
Those guys are ripe for the slammer!
- Now I've had enough!
Something's wrong with you!
Through the bars with
bittersweet chocolate! Ha!
Into a Won with marzipan!
That way they won't get a license plate!
It's no use with them, Herbert.
- I told you so!
Long over there!
- Off we go! Get lost, the shit!
Nice thing, you!
- Still tastes good, the booze.
(Rock music)
(Brakes squealing)
(Speaker) And I also
say: \"Crumbs", I say...
Well, that's it then. The
final end for the Werner film.
(Music)
(Speaker) It's no use. You have
to try again. Don't give up, old man!
Gather your last creative reserves!
Well, Mr. Brösel? How
are we doing today?
Oh, much better, I can see that.
You shouldn't try so hard!
- Hey! I have to let my film...
Stay nice in there.
(Music)
(Speaker) What a smoker's leg can
be good for! The doctor keeps that quiet.
But what the hell. There are
more important things here.
(Music)
Good morning, Mr. Wernersen! Wash! Brush
and soap in the morning, increase well-being!
Nice to wash-wash! Ei, ei, where is he?
Very clear.
Okay, nice to brush your
teeth. And wipe your mouth!
So, now measure the fever.
And keep it nicely in your mouth!
Bye!
Light left on. Old bitch!
(Groans)
(Music)
Make the bed! Pillows! Blanket!
What's going on again?
- Mattress! All messed up!
Everything full of cookie
crumbs! Such inconsideration!
The same theater every morning!
That mustn't be true!
The light left on again.
Off! End!
(Music)
Good morning!
Well? Haven't you peed at all?
- What do you think the toilet is for?
- So, so! You know
damn well that you
are not allowed to get up!
- Take the bottle and piss off!
What?
- Old toad!
That's an impertinence! I'll
tell the chief physician that!
Am I in a madhouse?
Good morning! For breakfast:
a glass of juice or milk?
I want my peace! Turn off the
light, or I'll bite the lamp off here!
Ah!
That's it!
- What does that guy think he is?
The patient has a choleric
attack. Nurse Gertrude,
the sedative injection!
- Yes! At your command!
This will be a dose of
Spirulina sulfate! Hah!
For such rebellious behavior
an enema is also due!
(Music)
No! Oh!
I just want to sleep peacefully!
Elfriede!
Yes!
- I hope we have understood each other.
The visit will be carried out
with the utmost concentration.
Yes, Professor.
(Screaming)
My last beer reserves!
- Where is the bean wax?
He'll see what he gets!
Ah! Help!
Well then, let's see
what it looks like here.
At the next pati...
(Sings) La Paloma ohe!
There comes a time when it has to end.
Come on, sister? Always
bring out the enema! Goodbye!
Ah!
Always these drug-addicted
doctors. Ah, an outboard motor! Ahoy!
(Humming to himself)
Moin, Werner!
- Hello, Andi!
They've got something wrong upstairs
here. Just make sure we get out of here!
Let's get out of here then.
- You'd better do that, man. Give it some gas, dude!
Yeah, let's go!
Where to?
- Let's have a party!
We're going to the beach, pumping booze.
- Yeah, then put in the party diskette! - Okay, I will!
(Music)
Yay!
Into a boat with marzipan!
Hey guys! Look up there! Booze!
I think,
Werner is out of the hospital.
He's definitely going to give you one, you.
- I think that's good, you!
Let's have one ourselves.
- That's a good idea, you!
You know, I kiss hot. You
know, I'm burning right away.
You know that I always achieve
everything, everything. I am a man.
Hey-ey-ey! I am a man!
Oh yes, remember: I am a man!
Why are you treating me like a big child? My kisses
burn hotter than the desert wind. I am a man. Hey-ey-ey!
I am a man!
Oh yes, remember: I am a man!
Werner! Ey!
(Screams)
Hi Werner! Everything
okay! We're tapping a keg!
Look.
He's not back on the steamer yet.
Let him crack up first.
What a tough time. They even
took his last beer reserves from him.
You're not saying. - Because it was time for him to be back with us.
- I know what helps him!
A really strong coffee! Come
on! Throw your bowl at me!
Yeah, good idea! That's really good.
(Rocksong: LET'S DANCE)
Turn it down a bit. Give it here!
Flathead is in the mood!
- Hooray!
(Narrator) No, we are not dreaming: Premiere!
Actually premiere for the Werner film! Brösel made it.
(Singing LA PALOMA)
Hello, boss! Two beers
with strawberry yogurt!
18, 20...
- Yes.
2, 3...
- At least.
4?
- Logical.
21 .644!
- Wech.
21 .648!
- Weg!
I play cross-hand, point on
Visit black to table and chair.
Contra!
- Re.
Deer.
- Elk!
Asshole!
- I'm out.
Very good.
- I'll take that one!
Well, finally! There it is!
Strawberry yogurt! Cheers, Werner!
Comes well in the morning!
Get outta here, the shit!
Do you know what's even better?
- Nope!
(Both) Sugar egg!
- Yeah, boss! We want two sugar eggs!
Yeah, that's better.
- Sugar egg? Uh...
Doesn't stand on the menu. What is that?
- You take a glass, pour in two, three yolks and stir it with sugar!
What's he thinking? Fried, or what? Something
like that! Don't know what sugar-egg is!
Stabbed!
- Come on, pants runner!
No! Card runner!
- Lay it open on the table.
Let's go. I'm out.
I can beat her! You have to take over.
Take over. You have to
take over. Not hand over!
Ah, okay.
Wait a minute. With 3,
play 4, Hand 5, Tailor 6...
Ah! What is that supposed
to mean? Should I puke?
Tell me, old man, don't you have any mix-up?
- Do it yourselves!
I can't handle this.
(Rock music)
(Screaming)
Come on, folding chair! I'm thirsty!
Uh, yes... Wha... wha...
what would you like?
Juice.
- Juice!
Juice!
- Juice.
- Juice!
Have you heard? Sixmo juice!
- Uh...
Apple or...
- Yes! All
banana, you plum!
We also have B... pear.
- Boo!
I don't like to say
this twice:
I want juice!
That's fine! Then I'll make pineapple!
What?
You want to get Anna wet?
If anyone here gets
Anna wet,
then it's me!
Do you know that?
W... why?
- I'll shove the
pear up your ass, you rat!
I'm saying this will be fun.
I hear something.
- I
don't hear anything.
Do you have to say
something?
- Oh! 18.
Yeah.
- 20.
- Dude, from the field!
Buy yourself a mix tomorrow, you.
Yeah, that's better.
Get lost, this shit!
50.
- I have it.
55.
- I have that too.
(Burps)
(Farts)
(Exciting music, screams)
Hello, my little one!
- I'm going crazy. You?
But it was just a dream!
- Oh come on! A dream?
And this beautiful sound recording?
\"Okay. When I get out of
here, I will grant you a wish."
And the king?
- He didn't laugh.
No? Didn't he laugh?
Would you have even scratched a single
line without me? And in the hospital?
Okay, okay. Convinced. So,
what's it about? What do you want?
My motorcycle? You can have it.
- No, no. Nothing so valuable.
I just want you.
- Huh? Me?
Yes! I want to marry you!
- Marry?
(Music: TREULICH GEFÜHRT)
As Schopenhauer says:
Rights halve and duties double.
So are you, Rötger F. Brösel, so... ready, to have
this woman standing next to you with the name...
äh... name... Well?
What are we called again?
You, I think she's from the home.
She doesn't even know her own name.
Well, what am I called then?
You may guess three times.
So tell us your name.
Ah, how good that no one knows
that my name is Rumpelstilzchen.
Then I am forced to
give you a little help.
Your name isn't Alf, is it?
- No.
Steffi Graf?
- Never!
Well, am I wrong in assuming that
your name is something rather unusual?
Have you heard the name Rumpelstiltskin?
- The devil told you that!
Ah!
I am redeemed.
- A miracle!
Thank you, sir! Yeah!
(Music: HALLELUJAH)
My name is recognized.
-
The curse is now lifted.
Now things are getting pleasant.
I
want to see a beer right away!
Hallelujah,
I'm opening
a bottle of beer.
We're getting married today,
which
I'll celebrate with a drink.
Hallelujah,
I'm opening
a bottle of beer.
This will be a great
party,
we'll have another one.
A miracle has
happened,
I saw it exactly.
A miracle came true at
the altar.
That can't be.
Hey man, say
"No"!
First have a beer.
He looked at me! She
already feels like a rocker chick.
He looked at me.
- He looked at me!
Will someone ever understand women?
It's going down tonight, but just barely.
That's our way, we like it hard. Get
out, whether it's a Pils or a wheat beer.
We love booze!
I'm into any beer.
Hallelujah, I'm
opening a bottle of beer.
We're getting married today,
which I'll celebrate with a drink.
Hallelujah, I'm
opening a bottle of beer.
This will be a great party,
we're having another one.
It's about time, man, I'm
drunk. There's just one little thing
missing, then I'll be completely
wasted. Hey, sweetie, are you my wife?
I just asked!
Romance is in the air today.
You're standing on my
foot, come, give me a kiss.
Get lost, you shit, whether
she's black or white.
Whether blond or brown,
we all love women.
Hallelujah,
I'm opening a bottle of beer.
We're getting married today,
which I'll celebrate with a drink.
Hallelujah,
I'm opening a bottle of beer.
This will be a great party,
we'll have another one.
(Phone)
What's up?
Why aren't you at work,
Crumb?
I have the option
for part two!
What?
Oh, man. What do you mean?
Let's just put in another hour.
There's only one thing
left to do: open a keg!
Hard as a rocker,
hard
as a chopper,
hard as a bottle of
beer,
hard it goes from here.
Hard as a rocker,
hard
as a chopper,
hard as a bottle of beer,
it
goes down hard from here.