(Bird chirping)
(Music box sounds, waltz music)
(Waltz melody is
taken over by piano)
Be a good boy and eat.
You don't want to make me sad.
- And hold yourself straight.
- Yes, Mom.
You can also eat here
tonight. There's enough food.
- Do you like the turkey breast?
- Wonderful, Mom. Wonderful.
If you want to sleep here,
your children's room
is always ready for you.
I'll heat up the
purée for you again.
I'm late.
First we eat!
Paul?
Yes, Mom?
Why did you just
take this apartment?
Other boys live at home too.
Yes, Mom.
- Pussi?
- Yes?
Did you bring me your shirts?
Oh no, Mom, this
really doesn't have to be.
My dear child, I have been
washing your shirts for 50 years,
so that you look presentable.
- Get your hair cut.
- Yes, Mom.
Customers look at such things.
You are now the boss
of Winkelmann and Son.
Like your father
and grandfather.
I'm proud of you. You
don't eat anything at all.
I can't anymore.
Excuse me. Do you know
how I can get to Schinkelstraße?
Yes. Schinkel Street...
This is Schinkel Street.
Yes.
(Subtle glockenspiel)
Grid blind is actually
no sheer curtain.
Then just a sheer curtain.
Are the... patterns
from England here yet?
- England?
- Uh, Italy, I mean.
- Oh no. They are just...
- I can also get you something...
Those people over there
are looking for a wardrobe.
- Also, if you want more...
- Can I help you in any way...?
We are looking for
a bedroom wardrobe.
For suits, where you also...
With a rail and clothes pegs.
- A-and shoes.
- I know what you are looking for.
Where is the brochure for
the Danish comedy series?
There in the dresser.
The advantage of the
Danish combined series
is based on their
space-saving dimensions
and their well-thought-out
interior design.
I should actually be able to
show you the Trulleberg model.
Yes, Trulleberg. That's
Trulleberg.
Very solidly built.
- I just wanted to ask...
- I'll be right with you.
What did I have, uhm...? Oh yes.
Another advantage is
the possibility of self-assembly.
- If we first ourselves...
- That's no problem at all.
You lift the deck
plate from the pins.
and let the side
panels swing out. See?
And together again?
Re-clip side panels.
and secure it
with the cotter pin.
Miss, uh,
Hagebusch, where is the bolt?
- for Trulleberg?
- ...35% polyester blend.
Would you hold this for a moment?
It's quite easy with two people.
Perhaps if the gracious
lady here...and if you...?
You just need to lightly
support the deck plate.
- I have a...
- One second, madam.
Where is that bloody
bolt for the Trulleberg?
- In the box. But if you…
- Which box?
Next to the rotting
cotton ripstop.
- A little more precise, please.
- Dresser, middle drawer.
Or something light in cream.
The Danish comedy series
is incidentally available
in almost all colors.
Also in eggshell.
Eggshell fits in everywhere.
How are you otherwise set up?
- Yes, please?
- I would like slips.
- Size 5?
- Um, 6.
That is pure cotton with
a 60% polyester blend.
The model is emphasized in the buttocks
area, so it's a bit tighter in the...
Or do you prefer it a little tighter
in the buttocks and therefore...
- No, no.
- I'll quickly take a look in the warehouse.
- Size 5?
- 6.
Here at least you're
served friendly.
I did not serve you rudely.
- Hey, I beg you!
- Rude service?
No, we were just talking...
I was perhaps a bit inattentive.
Inattentive, if I go
down to the cellar?
- You are not meant.
- I had only said...
You misunderstood.
You will be well
looked after here.
My customers are satisfied.
- If my service...
- I spoke to the lady.
Do you have short-sleeved
house jackets with a braid pattern?
(Absolute silence)
Is anything wrong?
What was it anyway? What
could I have possibly...?
I would like to have the seating
group upholstered in my practice.
A seating group.
And another thing I
wanted to ask about.
But if you are so overloaded...
Perhaps we can sort this
out now over a cup of tea...?
No, that doesn't
work well today.
Oh no, I also have
a club meeting.
And what if I were to stop by
tomorrow with my sample books?
Alright then. I'll
give you my card.
Come on, where did I put
them again? Maybe around 11?
Well then...
- Mr. Winkelmann.
- Excuse me, please.
Psychologist?
Diplom... Psychologist with diploma.
Men are the most primitive, vilest
and stupidest thing that...
Mrs. Mengelberg, you
raised a point there.
- Would you like to elaborate on that?
- Elaborate!
In our open-plan office work
2 ladies and 11 gentlemen.
Every time I from
the customer registry
To go to the purchasing department, I
have to go through accounting.
And then Mr. Wegner from...
touches me from behind.
- That's the most primitive...
- We understand you.
I don't even know what to say.
We want to deal
with the incident...
You get stupid
answers as a woman!
- It's best to say nothing.
- So, Mrs. Mengelberg,
it is hard for you, after
the described impertinence
to express that
opposite Mr. Wegner,
- what you are feeling.
- That is the most primitive...
Let's play out the
incident here in the group,
and you say quite fearlessly,
what you would have always liked
to get rid of towards Mr. Wegner.
Mr. Dr. Giesebrecht,
would you play Mr. Wegner?
You have therefore just touched
Mrs. Mengelberg from behind.
- What?!
- So, Mrs. Mengelberg.
What would you like
to tell Mr. Wegner?
Yes... um... so...
That you don't do that again.
I have never touched
Mrs. Mengelberg!
Mr. Dr. Giesebrecht,
You are now Mr. Wegner
and gave Mrs. Mengelberg a slap.
Ah, I see...
Well, she doesn't
want it any other way.
Mr. Dr. Giesebrecht, You
are indeed the most primitive...
Mr. Wegner! Mrs. Mengelberg,
You are speaking with Mr. Wegner,
not with Mr. Dr. Giesebrecht.
You're going to get one right
in the rear, Mrs. Mengelberg.
- Dr. Giesebrecht!
- Right behind you!
- Mrs. Mengelberg!
- On the rear!
Mr. Dr. Giesebrecht...
- You are the stupidest...
- Mrs. Mengelberg!
- on the rear!
- Women should always...
- Always on the rear!
Oh, excuse me!
Good evening, Mr. Winkelmann.
(Incomprehensible, muttering)
Ah, Mr. Dr. Schmitt! Good
evening, Mr. Winkelmann.
May I take your order?
- 1 beer.
- So how much beer?
- 1 Pils.
- 2 Beers.
- 1 Cola.
- 1 Rosehip tea.
- 1 normal tea.
- With milk or lemon?
Milk.
Excuse me. For
me a quarter dry red.
1 dry red.
- And 1 "Schlemmer" slice.
- 1 "Schlemmer".
Mr. Winkelmann, you are
chairing today's meeting.
Oh what? Yes, um, ah I see.
Yes, then I realize
that we are all present.
The gentlemen politicians
and Ms. Westphal.
That I could already…
Yes, you should hold on to that.
Uhm, in our last club meetings
do we have club
matters and club goals?
outlined by our association,
but we have not yet been
able to agree on a club name,
which clearly expresses
our club's content.
I believe Mr. Kempe had...?
Yes. Our association wants to, yes,
the terms woman and environment.
to bring into carnival thoughts.
I mean, this goal.
should be clearly
included in the club name
- 2 beers, 3 tea, 1 Schlemmer?
- And a quarter of red wine.
1 Cola.
2 beers, 1 cola, 1 wine,
1 Schlemmer, 3 tea.
-2 Tea.
- 1 Rosehip, 1 regular.
- 2 beers, 3 cola...
- 1 cola.
1 Cola, 2 Beer, 1 Wine
1 Schlemmer, 1 Rosehips,
- 1 normal.
- 1 Pils.
- 1 small.
- 1 pilsner, 2 beers, 1 small.
Only 2.2 in total.
Sir, uh, Kempe, you
were just about to...
Yes, I would have a question
regarding the order of the terms,
the integration of the
terms into the sequence...
Please remember what
you want to say, Mr. Kempe.
We should assume that
that the carnival idea
takes precedence,
because Yes the terms
woman and environment
to incorporate
into Carnival ideas.
Mr. Dr. Schnoor.
The term "woman" offers, after all,
Scope for carnival and environment!
Mr. Müller!
Also "Society for Carnival
despite woman and environment”.
- Not at all!   - Ah, I see.
- I'll record this first.
- No, no.
"Carnival in Remembrance
of Woman and Environment"?
Also, I have to...
The terms
woman, environment and carnival
- are 3 very hot irons.
- Mr. Mueller.
- Very hot irons.
- Mr. Müller.
- Mrs. Westphal wants... -
Well, here we are going to...
Very hot irons!
The woman surely has older
rights than the environment!
That must be clearly
stated in the club's name!
Mr. Winkelmann! What have I
been fighting for all these years?!
- Then formulate it once!
- Good God!
I would say: "Association
for the Integration of Terms"
Carnival and environment into the
woman.". That also sticks with one.
- And where is the thought?
- Which thought?
- Very right.
- The term carnival
includes the idea of
the concept of Carnival.
Should I perhaps already
jot this down so far?
We shouldn't decide
anything today yet.
What's in the minutes so far?
"All club members were present."
(Rhythmic clapping)
And again right away,
because it was so beautiful.
5, 6, 7, 8!
(More rhythmic clapping)
Thank you! Well, that was
already Housewives' Special Class!
What a good mood we're in today!
Mr. Romanowski!
Would it be agreeable
to Dr. if we began?
The woman Dr. is going to
get very uncomfortable soon.
- Then you'll get a little something on the rear!
- Not on the rear!
(Upbeat Music)
(Sentimental Music)
(Music turns dramatic)
(Music now very moving)
(Abrupt finale)
Winkelmann?
- Mom, are you asleep yet?
- Yes.
- Ah, I see.
- What is it?
- I just wanted...
- Sleep tight, my Pussi.
- Good night.
So. That's now
1.8 m at 32.50 DM.
250 m at 1.80.
Uh...Mark, uh...meter.
- 250 m?
No. That's not correct.
Uhm...let me see.
- Miss, no...er...
- Hagebusch.
Where are the price lists
for Australian cotton bodies?
I'm a little overwhelmed
at the moment.
You've been in my business for
11 years and you don't know that?
Please take care of this, Sir,
I have an appointment.
As you wish, Mr.,
uh, Winkelmann.
(The doorbell rings)
- Well, you're right on time.
- Yes.
You don't live far from
Merkel. Dieter Merkel.
We'd best go to the
practice right away.
That would be the
seating area here.
Seating group?
Excuse me, Mrs. Tietze,
a seating group is an
upholstered furniture set,
consisting of a
sofa and armchairs.
You have 5 chairs
here with padded seats.
Ah?
What connections
did you have in mind?
I was very satisfied
with the old ones.
That is a very,
very poor quality.
I mean, I can of
course order that,
but you won't enjoy that.
Then why don't you
make a suggestion?
We will tailor everything
to your wishes.
Do you actually know that
you bear a great responsibility,
- if you recommend a color?
- Pardon?
A single woman, who
tends towards depression,
would kill herself in a
purple seating group perhaps.
Even if it's flowered, the
seating group?
I also advise couples,
they have certain
interpersonal difficulties.
And I am sure that one
often through new materials and colors
that living together could be
made much more harmonious.
Oh, Mrs. Cookies, Mrs.,
uh, Mrs. Tietze,
Do you have a few
cookies in the house?
- Cookies?
- It's not that important.
I want to advise a couple
tomorrow on this point.
The company Winkelmann
has been for 63 years...
I would like this consultation.
not simply left to a
decorating company.
I want to proceed according to
modern psychological insights.
I'm just missing the
expertise in the textile industry.
This fall black is
very much in demand.
Why don't you just leave
me your sample books?
The company Winkelmann
is making you an offer.
We visit the customers together,
You conduct the negotiations,
we deliver the reference
material and you get 10%.
You have already
misunderstood me again.
- I could call you.
- No, I'll call you.
Oh, excuse me.
Oh, Mom, this doesn't
suit me at all right now.
And when would it suit you?
If I don't run right now,
I'll be late everywhere.
Was that one of your crazies?
My crazies aren't any
crazier than you and I.
Mr. Bröseke asked me what
you are actually doing.
I never know then what to say.
Psychologist! God in heaven!
- Your father would have...
- Yes, I know, my father
was a higher-ranking
civil servant.
Dad! You have trash cans too.
- Everything's all mixed up!
- He just does what he wants.
- Here come the Schröders.
- Of all things!
- Good day, Mrs. Tietze.
- Good day, Mrs. Schröder.
- My mother, the Schröders.
- Good day.
- Everything mixed up.
My father, Mr. and
Mrs. Schröder.
Bones, plastic, food
waste, Bottles, paper...
My father at the time
the municipal waste
disposal is organized.
As managing director.
- Have a nice day then.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye.   - Goodbye.
Very nice people.
That's all pure wool, sir.
- And what about this?
- That's striped.
Ah, that's striped?
No, if we start only after
dinner, it will be too late.
Hello, Mrs. Winkelmann.
- What is all this lying around here!
- I'll write it down for you.
- Paul?   - Right away, Mom.
He looks a little pale.
He should get more fresh air.
He's gotten a bit
fuller because of that.
3.5 m English
scouring wool at 182,
That makes a total of 637 DM.
Pussi, how much
do you weigh now?
Thank you. My wife
will then call you.
Mom! I had begged you
so much, if I may serve...
- Yes, yes.
- We just want to remind you.
I know, today is
our game night.
Do you remember?
- You have something
there. - And don't call me Pussi.
H...E...
"He". 2 points.
- It's not that much, anyway.
- It's enough for me.
Mechthild, it's your turn.
Wait. Wait!
"Dog nose". What is
that supposed to be?
What is that supposed to be?
That's not a word.
Dog's nose is a word after all.
Dog's nose, Aunt Mechthild.
It's called Dog'S nose.
- I told you so.
- The "E" is missing.
Dog's nose is spelled with "s".
I only have one "E".
Then you just can't put it down.
But it is a common word.
- You're putting something else down now.
- "Dog nose"! Never heard of it!
You're welcome. You're welcome.
(Inaudible)
"Taildog".
Yes. That's 57 points.
Explain to us, what
a "taildog" is.
- What needs explaining?
- I don't know the word, actually.
A taildog is
a dog with a tail.
Ugh, come on, Mechthild!
- Every dog has a tail.
- Please observe the rules.
- We don't say tailpig.
- She always uses such words.
- There are dogs without tails.
- Not in my house.
- Mom is right.
- Your vocabulary is too small.
- Also, Mechthild!
- Yes, yes, yes.
Then I could have put my
jellyfish dumplings down too.
If you don't stick to
the rules of the game,
- It's no fun.
- Am I in school here?
Call me when the ladies
have reached an agreement.
- Paul?
- Yes?
- Are you going to your room?
- Yes, Mom.
- What does he have then?
- Oh, he has nothing.
That's Paul's cucumber!
(Piano music - it sounds as if
someone were practicing piano)
(Bear growls)
Have you been waiting long?
I like to be outdoors.
Then let's go. So, so that we
don't misunderstand each other.
What matters most is that
this couple lives happier.
I know.
You have a lovely
garden, Mrs. Metzer.
Yes, it does a lot of work.
Flowers... a bouquet of flowers
can change an entire room.
- We have more vegetables.
- Vegetables...
Vegetables have
something so fresh.
Excuse me?
And a fresh coat of paint
is like a new beginning.
We wanted to try, after all,
through other colors
in the living area, uh...
to get other problems
under control.
When did you have this
sofa reupholstered last?
Yes, well...it should
be about 23 years.
- Exactly 19.
- That would be an option!
A fresh yellow,
an apple green...
We were actually
very satisfied with gray.
- Mrs. Metzer...
- Satisfied!
I have a gray collection here
from a Belgian company...
- Mr. Winkelmann!
- I know already.
There you have 28 shades
of gray in every quality.
You will be satisfied.
Mouse gray, dust gray,
- Ash gray.
- Mr. Winkelmann!
Steel gray, lead
gray, cement gray...
Mr. and Mrs. Melzer want
something fresh! Yellow or green...
Yes, but with that the
gentlemen were not satisfied.
I'll put this here for you,
so you can see it better.
Excuse me, I would have liked
to speak with Mr. Winkelmann
I'd like to withdraw briefly.
Would you please accompany me?
You didn't understand
what it's about!
Yes, Ms. Melzer was
very satisfied with grey!
From a psychological
point of view
Melzer's are mistaken!
Now we're going back
inside and you just listen!
- But when Melzer's...
- Just listen.
Mr. Winkelmann still has beautiful
tones in yellow and matt green,
which has a very positive effect
on the atmosphere in this room
and thus also affect
your well-being.
We would like the ash grey.
Should I recommend a
really fresh stone gray there?
No! We had talked about
the effect of colors, hadn't we?
Yes. You said that if Mr. Melzer
was in a purple seating group
he would kill his wife.
- What?!
Only not if it's blossomed.
- Waiter?
- One moment.
It was nice, working with you.
How you explained all
of this to the Melzers,
psychically, I mean.
- And I mean...
- Evenin', Mr. Winkelmann.
Good evening,
Dr. Schnoor. And I mean,
that interior
design, my industry,
much more scientific...
Thank you. I actually
just want something small.
Unfortunately I have to go
into the meeting right now.
I am secretary today.
But if you were still
there afterwards?
- Good evening.
- Good evening, Mr. Kempe.
We'd have brains today.
It's not on the menu.
- A mixed salad.
- Good evening.
Good evening, ma'am, uh...
If you were still
around afterward,
I would like to talk
with you sometimes…
Now I'm going to
eat a salad first.
Well then...
I consider it necessary
for reasons of efficiency,
to clearly identify us as
members of the association.
Why mark it then?
Let Mr. Meier-Grabenhorst
finish speaking.
Should I write that down?
I'll tell you then, Mr.
Winkelmann. Please.
I request that we, through
attaching an emblem.
to express our common
goal more clearly.
- An emblem after all!
- What did you expect?
I sat down with some advertising
professionals there once,
the already leading politicians
who have successfully advised.
And we've come up
with something there.
- Perhaps I could...
- Yes, please.
Well...
It is not intrusive
and yet memorable.
Above party lines,
but not apolitical.
I like, that with
losing this..., this...
- Nose.
- Uh, thanks. That's why
the unmasking of our
society can be symbolized.
- Mr. Dr. Schnoor...
- Moment.
As a concern of the
democratic social order.
I remember the order, that
we have as Germans
regarding our history.
Very good. But we should
also record that from Mr. Müller.
- Also, Mr. Winkelmann.
- Yes? How was that?
Subject matter and the
whole story, the entire story...
- with the social order?
- After the overthrow
the predominance of man and
the inclusion of the woman...
Regarding the German
people as an indivisible nation...
And the inclusion of
women in the...
...when activating the
wetlands simultaneously
and the inclusion of
women in the societal...
construction process.
- Not so fast.
Replacement of the man with
simultaneous activation of the woman,
including wetlands
into the German people
as an indivisible nation.
(Toilet flush rumbles)
(Sounds of voices chattering)
Something like this wouldn't
have been allowed here before.
Do you actually know,
How do you look?
Look in a mirror.
Good evening. Ah, there you are!
I was just about to leave.
Good evening, Mr. Winkelmann.
- Good evening. Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
I'm not in any other club.
But through this
common  political work
one gets a glimpse
for the big picture.
Are you particularly
close to a party?
No, but I admire
politicians in general
this intellectual and
human superiority.
Good night, Mr. Winkelmann.
- Good night.
- Well then, um...
- Oh, I wanted to, um, too bad...
I would have
addressed the issues...
I would also find it very kind if
I could invite you for a cup...
I would like it if I could
invite you for a cup of tea...?
Thank you, but that looks bad.
I'm baking a
braided yeast bread!
The next 2 weeks
there's nothing to be done.
Then tomorrow.  I'm baking a
braided yeast bread tomorrow.
and we'll have a
cup of tea. At 5.
Karl-Ernst-von-Halmackenreuter-Str.
3, 2nd floor.
1 cup of tea and 1
braided yeast bread.
I'll try it.
Oh, excuse me, please.
I thought I had this time...
You naturally have problem hair,
But it can handle a new color
once in a while. Something fresh!
I am very satisfied
with my color.
If you take something away
here, it falls quite differently.
You can do such great things.
With a new hairstyle you
feel completely different.
Look here, Mrs. Tietze, I've been
wearing my hair like this for 8 days now,
I feel like a new person.
So! And that's not
something everyone has!
If you say so.
- Ciao.
- Goodbye.
(The doorbell rings)
(The bell rings again)
- Mrs. Tietze?
- Yes.
You didn't expect
me anymore, did you?
Yes, I had only...
May I offer you the...
Thank you. I brought
you something.
- That's very kind of you, that...
- It's nothing, really.
That wouldn't have
been necessary.
Please, sit down
in the living room.
You have it nicely here.
Yes, it's enough for me.
I am usually with my...
That's really walnut veneer.
You can have those too
in oak, mahogany
and birch, flamed.
The cupboard is for self-assembly.
Upon request with table and 2
chairs. That makes a total of...
Oh, how stupid! I have
the prices only on the list.
- Doesn't matter.
- Typical. When you need it.
Is that your mother?
Yes. That's Mom, my mother.
A really, really famous
person. Really famous.
And this here is a sit-and-sleep
combo furniture piece.
Very decent in color.
5 two in white padding.
Please? Ah, yes.
It smells so good here. Is
that the braided bread?
Oh yes. Please have a seat.
- And where are you going?
- To the kitchen.
- Do you like to cook?
- Well, so-so. Mom cooks better.
If you would be so kind
as to wait a moment?
At the upholstered furniture
I could make concessions.
It looks wonderful! Did
you bake it yourself?
Yes. According to a
recipe from my mother.
- Would you like a sherry?
- Just a small one.
(Romantic music)
Our cooperation has
been very good for me.
Well, cooperation...
Are you very attached
to your mother?
Yes, indeed. Everyone
is fond of their mother!
Yes, yes, of course.
Ah, with you one can
really talk about anything.
Just do it.
Then I have to tell
you something now,
What I have only said
once in my life to a woman.
I would like to
be in a barrel with you
ride over Niagara Falls!
That's all I've said
so far to my mother.
Then you should rather
travel with your mother.
Do you know... it doesn't
have to be in the barrel.
But if your mother has already
been looking forward to it so much.
We could just... why
shouldn't one simply...?
- Three in this dumpster?
- No, no pleasure trip.
I have to go to Milan
for business soon.
And if you just came along now?
Business, you mean?
I'm not even thinking about it!
One could still add another day.
Mr. Winkelmann, I have a job!
But not on the
weekend. Mrs. Tietze!
Do you know,
Mechthild, I always say,
The young people
have their own lives.
He is the
youngest Well, no longer.
Paul has always brought me joy.
He just needs to get out a bit.
He always goes to these
fabric clowns in Italy.
And then he constantly had
these representatives in the house.
This morning he wanted the
recipe for my braided yeast bread.
Ah, that's why I
wanted to call him again!
Does it have to be?
Is there a telephone
here, my child?
- At the buffet.
- Well, then I'll pay first.
Do I have to press
anything here, or something?
(Still romantic music)
(Clears throat)
How are you actually
called by your mother?
Mom calls me Pussi.
Pussi...
Do you know what I
have to think about?
If you tell me?
To Mr. Bröseke, the
hairdresser for ladies.
(Phone rings)
- Excuse me, please.
- Please.
Winkelmann?
Pussi? You, I'm sitting
here right now with Mechthild.
and I just thought of something
else for your braided yeast bread.
(Inaudible)
Before you put it
in, brush it with egg yolk.
Yes, Mom, yes?
- I have to go now.
- Wait.
You could also sprinkle
it with chopped almonds.
Mom, we've almost
finished the braid.
- Are the gentlemen still here?
- Just out the door.
Hello?
Did the gentlemen
like the braided yeast bread?
Yes. That means, yesterday it
was less on a representative level.
I would like customer
service in the future more
from a scientific standpoint...
Mrs. Tietze, Dr. Tietze
is a psychologist.
Oh, you didn't have
any visitors yesterday?
Yes, I'm saying yes.
Who?
Dr. Tietze.
How did you explain to the
gentlemen who Mrs. Tietze is?
There weren't any
gentlemen there at all.
That's when I called you,
while you were with this person...
Mom, Dr. Tietze is a scientist.
We work together.
Yes, that's what you
want to tell your mother.
Mom!
And what now?
I intend, to consult
with clients regarding
also the customer
service advising on...
to be advised by Dr. Tietze
So we can't shop alone anymore?
I unfortunately have to
go again next week to...
Ah? The lady must
surely come along then?
Maybe we'll have a few
more nice days, huh?
- Mom!
- I want to tell you something.
Then she can also
iron your shirts.
(Upbeat Music)
(Sings) His sister's name is...
Shit!
- No, that's not her name.
- I always forget her name.
Academics are surely overrated.
I feel sick, when
I think about it,
what I have gotten myself into.
It's not for television.
You are standing
on a small stage.
at a company party in
front of 250 employees
of a medium-sized
plastic processing... thing...
-...operations.
- Yes.
- Clear?
- Clear.
- Can I use the phone?
- Yes, of course.
And Chorus Line again.
(More music)
(Phone rings)
(Music in the background)
Hello?
- Hello?
- Winkelmann.
Here is Margarethe Tietze.
I wanted to thank
you for yesterday.
And for the braided yeast bread.
Did you like him then?
A thousand thanks. Please?
It's so loud here. What?
How could I go
to Italy with you?
Then we fly together
over the Alps, land in Italy,
The state carriage is
ready, I believe I am dreaming.
Do we have far to go?
No, in 20 minutes we'll
be in Casapulchino.
This is Signor Mancinit,
- My Italian agent.
- Good morning, Signora.
Ben arrivati. Prego!
Come with me.
I have gotten a very
nice rental car for you.
Mr. Mancini.
Mr. Mancini. Mr. Mancini?
Would you like to sit
at the front, Signora?
Oh no, rather in the back.
Mr. Mancini, what about
these household goods?
We're coming by my
brother's place.
There we'll hold on for a
moment.  I'll bring him the things.
That's absolutely
no problem at all.
(Waltz music)
Northern Italy is preferably
used for agriculture.
Ah.
(Honking)
(Chicken clucking, dog barking)
Tonella!
Antonella!
Un momento.
You really see more, when
you drive down the side streets.
(Speaking Italian)
Do you speak a foreign language?
English.
With English, you can
get through anywhere.
(Still speaking Italian)
Buon giorno.
(Bottles clinking)
(Bottles clink loudly)
Afterwards I'll eat a huge
portion of Spaghetti Carbonara.
(Bottles clink and clatter)
And afterwards
this warm egg foam.
Um, um... Zabaione.
You'd better not
come into the company.
This is a nice cafe.
Have an espresso. I'll
take care of business.
and then pick you up here.
Don't worry about me.
- Well, then… see you later.
- Signora.
(Bottles clink)
(Italian)
Caffè, Cappuccino?
Alora, Cappuccino.
(Italian)
Prego.
(Door bursts open)
(Everyone is talking in
Italian at the same time)
(Italian)
(Still loud, lively Italian)
Signora!
The new collections
have nothing fresh at all!
No apple green for
example. No apple green.
(Translated into Italian)
These are the colors
of this year's season.
Violet is not harmless.
(Italian)
Why?
Women gather in
purple seating groups.
(Translating)
Single women.
(Italian)
In Turin a soccer player
shot himself on his sofa.
but it was yellow.
What color, uh, sofa color
do most people survive in?
(Translating)
Mrs. Tietze!
That went faster,
than I thought.
I think so too.
(Winkelmann) You seem
to be doing quite well here.
(Tietze) An older gentleman
bought me a shot of schnapps.
And then you had to,
as thanks, perform tricks.
They all balanced eggs there.
Mom and I have been
driving to Italy for 12 years.
No Italian has ever
balanced an egg on a spoon.
Thunderbolt, Mr. Winkelmann!
You're not living badly!
Wait! Mrs. Tietze!
Our hotel is...
...insane!
(Waltz music)
(Music swells)
(Italian)
There's always a lot
going on at weekends.
- What can I do for you?
- I would like...
(Italian)
I would like 2 single
rooms until tomorrow.
Have you reserved?
Ah, no. It...had just
turned out that way.
With a bath or shower?
- I mean, it's probably enough...
- Oh yes, with a bathroom.
Yes, with bathroom.
One with a shower.
What price range would
you have... I mean, um...
With bath 320,000,
with shower 250,000.
That's then 490 and 380 marks.
Oh yes, God Yes, why not?
Or would you have anything
else... or is that with full board?
We are almost fully booked
and the prices are understood.
- Without breakfast. - Sure.
Okay. If you're already on
the road, you might as well...
- Your passports, please.
- Your passport, please.
Would you like a
reservation for the ristorante?
Whether we want to
eat here in the restaurant.
Let's eat over
there  at the pizzeria.
Or would you
rather like it here...?
Oh yes. Let's just stay here.
Here. Yes.
Then please 2 places
for this evening in, uh...
- Restaurant. - As you wish.
Your rooms will be ready soon.
Perhaps you'd
like another drink.
Your luggage will be taken
to your room immediately.
We should order another drink.
until the rooms are ready.
Then I would like a
milkshake with apricots.
I'll take care of it.
My name is Winkelmann.
I would like a milkshake
with apricots and a...
I may now escort
you to your room.
Yes. Thank you very much.
Prego, Signore.
Ah, I would have liked to
see how you are accommodated.
- Perhaps you would like to ...
- Let's just have a look first.
How lovely.
(Bird chirping
penetrates from outside)
Also, you already
have a very safe taste.
I thought to myself, if one's
already here, one should...
don't count pennies.
And the luggage
is already here too.
That is pure cotton.
With a mixture of a
maximum of 10%.
And this is the KB 30
with freezer compartment.
I have that one at home.
Only this one is in mahogany.
There's also a 550-liter model.
With a slightly higher
power consumption.
I could get that for you
with a 20% discount.
I think, you aren't
listening to me at all.
Yes. You want to
get me something.
I could get you the
KB 50 with 20% off.
Oh yes, of course.
That's very kind.
No, that's quite natural.
I only understood
it acoustically.
It doesn't matter. It
wasn't important anyway.
Yes, yes.
Well then, I'll just
take a look in my room.
I still have to unpack.
- I'm calling you.
- Or I'll call you.
I could also drop by.
But then call me beforehand.
Then we'll go down together.
- Yes.
- If that suits you.
Yes, but I'll call
you when I'm done.
Yes, good. Good.
(Makes trumpet
noises with his mouth)
(Bottles clink loudly)
(Honking and traffic noise penetrates
from the street into the room)
Waiter!
- I'll take care of it.
- Prego, Signore.
We would like a large
portion Spaghetti Carbonara.
- And Tagliatelle Funghi.
- We have French Week.
- Everything on the menu.
- They have a French week!
Can you tell me what a
"Poitrine de Beau Voyage" is?
- Not really. Waiter?
- Please?
What is a "Poitrine
de Beau Voyage"?
That is a  "Suprême Chevreuil
a la Soubri Gratinat".
Ah yes. That is a "Suprême
Chevreuil a la Soubri" baked.
- That's it, right?
- Yes.
And a "Mousse Rabelais
à la Lézanne"?
That is a "Queue d'Écrevissage
en Sauce Poupoule Courouse".
- Pu...what?
- Poupoule Courouse.
What is that?
Wait.
This is a "Timbalette Volatile"
aux Fins Herbes
avec Pomerolles Dauphinoisettes
du Creme à la Louis Quatorze."
Then let's just take that.
Twice the Visage de,
the Queue de Visage with the sauce...
Poupoule Courouse.
Do you often travel abroad?
Yes, Mom and I travel a lot.
I have in my practice
various gentlemen,
who also get along
well with their mother.
- With my mother?   - No.
In the mother-son
relationship, the son refers to...
I mean, the mother is in her
reference to her son on the....
... referencing the son.
- Waiter?
- You said that beautifully.
The mother is indeed
the lap, the center...
Waiter, in the
refrigerator in our room
there are always
only half bottles.
I will tell the floor service.
Germans!
Only half bottles
are allowed in KB 30.
- Excuse me?
- I'm sorry. Winkelmann.
- What is it?
- Winkelmann.
I would like to tell you... I
actually never talk about it,
but I have a completely different
relationship with my mother.
I believe she never
particularly loved me and…
Please remember
what you wanted to say.
But the KB 50 is for whole
bottles, lying down and standing up.
That was not clear
to me as a child.
I could send you brochures.
- Excuse me.
- It's alright.
La Queue d'Ecrevissage
Poupoule Courouse.
Thank you very much.
Oh, thank you very much.
That, uh, looks quite sparsely plated.
I have met many people,
but besides Mom and Aunt
Mechthild no one calls me Paul.
(Loud Squeaking)
(Giggles)
(Giggles too)
(Shrill screeching and laughter)
Also, no woman, no other
woman has told Paul about me.
Paul also has
something very intimate.
(Still giggling and shrieking)
(Loud scream)
(Still whinnying)
(Both) Well...
And if I were now to ask you
to tell Paul to come to me?
Only if you then also
said Margarethe to me.
- Well then...
- Good night.
Good night.
(Still screeching and giggling)
(Still giggling)
Cuckoo!
Oh, excuse me, please!
- By mistagke I...
- Zito!
(Italian)
My name is Winkelmann.
- Good morning.
I wouldn't know at all
how I would behave there.
- They were armed. -
You have to stop people
by appearing confident,
throw them off balance.
They immediately realize
that you are superior to them.
But 20 against one?
I just have to be careful,
that I don't let myself
be drawn into violence.
Do you actually mistake
yourself frequently for the door?
Or perhaps you'd rather
not find the right door at all?
Excuse me?
If you want to find your way
through the opening of the other.
from its own center into
the center of the other,
for the realization of
the Self, the holistic Self,
on the path of self-discovery
through the door to You,
also from one's own self
to the you of the other...
to the other You come or find,
uh, want to find,
that's the door then,
the open door, the
right way to open a door.
I know what you mean. One
leaf hangs next to the other,
as you and I, so
small and green.
One falls from
the tree like a fish.
Or like a bird, that
knocks on our door.
Wonderful is all of this.
Paul?
Yes, Mama-Margarethe?
I would have liked to
have you in the picture.
Wait. Hello?
Scusi. Fotografia la signorae me.
Signor...perfavore.
(Shot, pigeons scatter)
Are no machines
flying today at all?
- Yes, but not in Italy.
- That's what I mean.
(Lively Italian)
Scusi. Bagaglio?
Nada.
Il treno per Germania. Treno per
Brennero,  train to Germany.
3:50. Tre cinquanta.
That's what I love
about the Mediterranean.
His attitude towards
work is relaxed.
Not so grim as with us.
He didn't even want money.
His friends are more
important to him than his work.
We can still learn
something from that.
The train should have
been here long ago.
Dove e il treno?
Today no train. Sciopero.
Come se dice? Strike.
Wait. Wait! Who or
what is striking now?
I want to tell you
something, good friend.
My name is Winkelmann.
- and I don't have a sense for...
- Don't get worked up.
Let's go to the airport now.
(Sings with great devotion)
Well, Mom would have
told us something about that!
Please stick your
mother on her hat.
Not at the hat, Mrs.
Tietze. Not at the hat!
It is recommended to
leave the aircraft via a slide.
Why, we've just gotten on.
Mom always says that
matter itself can't fly.
Oh really?
This armchair is absolutely
incapable of flying.
- He's flying anyway.
- That's just crazy.
150 flying armchairs
can one not even
imagine in a dream.
Mom?
(Again bumpy piano music)
Mom!
Ah, you! Has your wife
Dr. given you permission?
There's a man in my room.
You don't need to apologize.
- Mom, there's a...
- You are grown up.
I'm always happy when
you have something planned.
- Who is this gentleman?
- That's Mr. Weber.
- Mr. Weber?
- Yes.
Mr. Weber! My
son would like to greet you.
This really isn't necessary now.
This is Mr. Weber, my son.
- Good day.
- Please have a seat, Mr. Weber.
Thank you, but I
don't want to interrupt.
Mr. Weber is a musician. We
want to make music together.
Dad's picture is on the wing.
My husband died 8 years ago.
I still have the shirts.
Mr. Weber kindly
ironed your shirts.
He found something
out there.  Tell me about it.
One must turn up the
collar, the shirt collar.
from back to front, iron
from the middle to the sides,
so that the opening doesn't
get narrower at the neck.
Mr. Weber is a great help to me.
- Oh?
- Yes, then...
Mr. Weber, shall I fry you some
purée this evening?
If it could just
be a small thing?
And without sauce, please.
Why is he ironing my shirts
and getting something roasted?
I didn't ask about
Mrs. Tietze either.
I have not roasted
anything for Mrs. Tietze.
And what about the
braided yeast bread?
I caught Mr. Weber in my bed!
Mr. Weber is my subtenant.
(The dice rolls away
loudly clattering)
Excuse me, can I
find artists here?
from the event of the
company Kunststoff-Meier?
(Musical music)
(Singing) The
company Plastic-Meier
lay plastic eggs.
made of polyvinyl chloride.
Mr. Meier already
has the hang of it.
He says, the world will become
more beautiful through PVC!
She asked him if she should
fry purée for him!
- Purée?
- Your performance!
- Why purée?
My mother has a lodger.
(Singing) I have a sister,
named Polyester.
She's been sucking
for almost 9 years now.
always the same
yellow plastic candy.
That's top-notch stuff!
Yes, my little
sister, the polyester,
the poly-ethy-lene!
Ha!
Mr. Piesanelli! Mr.
Piesanelli!
My mother can have as
many subtenants as she wants!
Where is that man with the goat?
- Who?
- Mr. Piesanelli!
She is an adult. But
not like that. Not like that!
(Singing) We cultivate our
body with styrofoam.
With real Polyplast and
polyamide.
And whether someone
loves me or not, I don't care.
Mom used to be a singer.
He has a sister,
named Polyester.
She's been sucking on
it for almost 9 years now.
always the same
yellow plastic purée.
That's top-notch stuff!
Yes, his little
sister, the polyester.
The P...V...C!
Ha!
(Scattered applause)
"Uptight psychologist dances
her way to freedom."
Ha-ha-ha!
Mom sings with him and
cooks for him every day.
Margarethe!
I listen carefully. Your
mother sings and cooks.
What do you think of that?
(Sings) I have a sister,
named Polyester...
Good day, Mrs. Tietze.
- Ah, good day.
- Good day.
This is Mr. Winkelmann, Mr.
and Mrs. Schröder.
- Yes, then…goodbye.
- Goodbye.
(Clearing throat)
May Mr. Winkelmann
have a cup of tea?
Would you like a cup of tea?
Yes, gladly. And
some hot water, please.
Why shouldn't he
be allowed any tea?
He could have just
taken something.
What are you taking?
I don't know how these
things are handled today.
At one cousin of mine,
the sister of Uncle Hoppe,
no direct kinship, the one
got cold shocks back then.
Mom, Mr. Winkelmann...
And very strong sedatives.
That didn't help at all.
We did visit her, before she
went into the Closed Ward.
She wasn't allowed
any tea or coffee at all.
- And no alcohol.
- Mom!
Mr. Winkelmann is
not under my care.
That is very sensible.
Please don't misunderstand me,
but my daughter does
something like that just on the side.
My God! He's not
in treatment at all!
I find that irresponsible.
- But nowadays...
- Gerda?
- Ah! Good day, Margarethe.
- That is Mr. Winkelmann.
Tietze. Gerda, do you know,
where this toothpaste tube was?
I would rather not
know that right now.
Wash your hands and sit with us.
(Mrs. Tietze clears her throat)
- Well...
- Mr. Winkelmann is the owner
of a furniture and
decoration store.
Ah, you have a shop?
What's wrong with
Mr. Winkelmann?
He is not in treatment,
but he has a shop.
Maybe I'll still
get a cup of tea.
To be clear: Mr. Winkelmann
is not my patient.
He's not "crazy,"
as you like to put it.
- Aha...
- The tea is gone.
You know where he is.
And maybe your acquaintance
would like some peanuts!
Cookies.
(Choking cough)
He said "Cookies".
Cookies used to be
simply in a cardboard box.
Now it's about plastic. That
makes things complicated.
I think Mr. Winkelmann
isn't so interested in that.
Is "Government Director Gröber"
a name you are familiar with?
I had Mr. Gröber on my
side already in the fall of '77,
but instead they
built a cultural center.
And we're up to
our necks in shit.
- Can't we...?
- Not at the table!
- Margarethe, get some more cookies.
- I don't know where they are.
Do I have to do everything
in this house alone?
Say, what have you
dragged us into now?
I thought you'd be
interested, who I'm with.
With whom what?
We travel and work together.
(Mocking laughter)
Back then there were
at least professionals.
Do you know what I mean?
They understood
something about their field.
Those were professionals
with expertise.
Well, it was really
quite nice with you.
Do you want to leave already?
I think I should
probably go now.
Wait!
My mother would be very happy,
if you were also to come
to us in the next few days.
(Sings) How beautiful,
how beautiful the earth is.
That's what the
little birdies know...
Thank you, Mrs. Winkelmann.
And perhaps again now
"They lift their wings so light and free,
and...
(Sings) They lift their wings
so light and free,
Mom?
They lift their wings so light and free,
And sing such melodies with glee
And sing, and sing...
Mom!
- In the aurel...
- F, Mrs. Winkelmann, F
- Yes, and?
- You sang an A flat.
- Mom!
- And "L," Mrs. Winkelmann.
- "In the laurel" And...
- Mom! I find it wonderful,
that you are making
music with Mr. Weber,
but we have guests coming soon.
We? You have guests.
I told Tietez,
you'd be pleased...
(Sings) That's what
the little birds know
That's what the
little birds know.
We had discussed everything!
- I suppose I may then...
- You stay where you are.
What have we discussed?
That I should invite
Tietze. In your name!
In God's name, I said.
(The doorbell rings)
(It rings again)
Hello! Please come in,
uh, come closer...inside.
I, uh...Mom!
Go ahead and
put it down already.
And go into the living
room. I'll be there right away.
(Squealing)
- Shall I help you?
- No, thank you, I'm fine.
Mom will excuse herself.
She is with a child.
To a sick child.
2 sick children.
From a friend.
To a sick friend.
- Paul?
- Mom?
You should have
treated our guests
at least be able
to offer a place.
That's Mama. Mrs., uh,
Winkelmann. Those are...
- Tietzes.
- Yes.
Oh, how delightful.
Please, Paul, be so kind.
Please sit down.
(Mrs. Winkelmann) Lovely
weather you've brought with you.
Yes.
Last year around this
time we were in Fischbach.
(Mrs. Winkelmann) Fish are all
poisoned these days, aren't they?
At Bensberg.
My husband used to swim a lot.
- Bensberg.
- My husband died eight years ago.
Fourteen days ago, Government
director Gröbe died.
Dr. Krakebusch died last week.
- Did you know him?
- No.
He was honorary president of
the dog breeders' association.
There was a poodle
in the next house...
Paul, Dr. Tietze
hasn't had any tea yet.
Without "Dr.", please.
- Oh?
- My daughter is a psychologist.
Psychologist (Diploma).
I thought Dr. Tietze
was a scientist.
Mom, Mrs. Tietze
treats mainly...
She can explain that to me.
I advise people,  who are
struggling in their private lives
- or professionally...
- Would you like another cup?
No, thank you. My
daughter studied in Hamburg.
- She dances very nicely too.
- Oh, Mom!
- She's dancing!
- Mom studied singing.
Is your son still working?
Since I withdrew,
is my son CEO of our company.
And founder of the department
for decorative fabrics.
Wholesale or does he cut
more pieces off the bale?
- Mommy!
- And Mom studied singing.
Ah, you sing?
Oh yes. But then
when the boy came...
A mother must be ready,  to
make sacrifices for her child.
Isn't that right, my Pussi?
Your wife Mom has
a very beautiful voice.
And what did your son study?
He has anyway not
gotten into the universities
messing around with these
so-called "female students",
who then later open a
massage parlor somewhere
and claim they have patients.
My daughter?!
What's wrong?
Have some, there are still some
Tietze here. I mean treats
- Mr. Tietze.
- Mrs. Winkelmann
You would delight us greatly
if you would sing for us.
My God, I haven't
seen a grade in years.
Just think, Mama, how
happy Mr. Weber would be.
But just something very short.
I would like Ms.
Winkelmann's hospitality.
- No longer strain.
- Mommy!
Mrs. Winkelmann performs
a song by Johannes Brahms.
- It is his Opus 6...
- Yes indeed!
It is his Opus 6, Number 4
in C major and
is titled "Hurrah!"
Johannes Brahms wrote
this song at the age of 19.
and precisely with that
confidence, which is found in young people,
but also in us more
mature people,
as a lighthearted
experience, life experience,
sounds.
(Sings) How beautiful,
how beautiful the earth is
That's what the
little birds know.
The birdies know that.
- I'm getting all...
- Shh!
- I feel sick. -
What's wrong?
Not bad, huh?
They lift their wings so light and free,
And sing such melodies with glee.
Don't you want to
close the windows?
- And sing, and sing!
- I mean, because of the neighbors.
In the lauuuuu...
That is completely pointless.
Mom, Mrs. Tietze just
said it wouldn't be so bad.
- She didn't listen at all.
- I did hear very well,
- what you said about my daughter...
- Mom!
- Paul!
Your visitor would
like to say goodbye.
- That was beautiful!
- Absolutely beautiful.
I don't recall
inviting these people.
- If it were up to me...
- Mom, please!
We have our
wardrobe somewhere...
Now it's getting really cozy!
We would be home already!
Although I would have
been loath to forego it,
To hear Mrs. Winkelmann sing.
I think it was a nice evening,
- So in general...
- Are you coming, Margarethe?
I would still like
to say goodbye.
That's not my hat.
- Paul?
- Yes?
Ach!
I guess I'm not
needed here anymore.
I will probably no
longer be needed here.
(Romantic Waltz Music)
Pussi!
(Ominous Music)