(auto-translated using ollama/gemma)
*Mysterious Sounds*
(Man) And so I have decided
to rethink
to surround myself only with what I love.
Have you ever seriously
dealt with the question
of what you really need?
I have dropped my last name
and now call myself only Marco.
Without a last name, just Marco.
Too much of everything
in our lives.I'm a minimalist.
The less I own,the happier I am.
And the less timeI have to
spend with you, the happier I am.
My girlfriend Selina thinks like me -at least I thought
so, but now I don't know anymore,what I should think.
He should stop thinking,
because he can't do it well anyway.
Is there love in your life?
You know, love is actually quite minimalist:
I give everything and want nothing in return.
That's how I live.
That's why I decided to
rethink everything, completely...
Oh, what's wrong? My sweater!
My clients like to start burning
if they don't get to the point.
It's a designer piece, unique.
So am I, so get to the point!
Selina has been working as a secretary at a law firm
for a few months and has become materialistic now.
Also if she comes with a lot of
money, you can send her to me.
Much worse:
She came home with a car.
With a Porsche!
- Oh dear.
I'm afraid Selina is having an affair
with her boss, that sleazy lawyer.
I'm also worried: that she
won't be able to pay my fee.
I am a minimalist, not poor.
Difficult lawyers
cost extra.
Do you cost even more?
- Yes.
Now you have to deliver.
Find out,
whether my girlfriend is having an affair.
It's actually
never a good sign,
when my clients
give me a lot of money.
* Theme music from "Philip Maloney" *
(Announcer) The hair-raising cases
of Philip Maloney.
Today:
A lawyer rarely comes alone.
With subtitles by SWISS TXT
Watch out!
Now you've almost given me a headache.
Oh no, the two of them.
Good day.
- Good day.
* Loud voices in the background
* What's going on here?
It's just hell today, they don't
usually complain like that.
(Woman) How could this get out?
- (Man) Yeah, how, how, how?
What's the result?
- If you don't know that,
then you don't need to
know it. How can I help you?
I'm doing a survey
with assistants.
It's about minimalism
and free cars.
Did Marco send you?
Tell him it's not
always all about him.
Certainly, but who is it about then?
(Man) You always
have to accuse me.
Ah, Mr. Maloney, Philip Maloney.
We know each other.
- Yes, unfortunately.
He's a lawyer, but not one of the
good ones, if there even are any.
He's a private
detective, but not one
of the good ones, if there even are any.
His wife, also a lawyer.
Together they are
trouble and strife.
What does he want?
- What do you want from us?
Is he here about the case?
- Are you here about the case?
Case?
- We're not answering any questions!
Do you want to say anything else?
- No, he doesn't.
It's extremely inappropriate right now.
- He should leave.
Who is this about?
About me.
Isn't it really about the incredible ...
Albrecht,
you don't speak to Mr. Maloney!
(With so many closed doors
I wondered,
if Selina's secret
really only involved a gifted
Porsche.)
(I had to examine the matter from a new perspective.)
* Mysterious Sounds *
Maloney.
Not now, I'm meditating.
A resident has complained
about a prowler.
I haven't seen anyone.
- You are the prowler, Maloney!
Theoretically he's right,
but practically he's annoying.
Are you here because of the insults?
- No, because of the beautiful view.
Prostitution is a crime.
Go home or
I'll take you to the station.
Yes, yes.
* Mysterious sounds *
* Phone ringing *
Mr. Maloney, I need your help.
It's urgent.
Mrs. Schimpf needs my help?
Attention.
What's wrong with him?
He found her.
Where is the police?
- They're coming right away.
I wanted you to see the
crime scene first.- Why?
Mom?
- Rest nicely.
You surely want to
see the body, don't you?
It looks like a watermelon,
on which a bocce ball hit.
What do you mean?
- She is dead.
Obviously, anything else?
- Art has also suffered.
Is that your husband's
office? Where is he?
You don't know where your husband is?
That makes him suspicious.
What do you want from me? An alibi?
I'd prefer the murderer.
And if you don't find him,
other suspects.
Can't your husband be the murderer?
That doesn't fit his character.
- Did he have an affair with her?
That fits
his character much better.
But I have no proof of that.
Who killed her then?
- You are responsible for that.
The police will be here soon, and they'll think, what
everyone thinks: A lawyer has an affair with his secretary.
She wants to end
it,he can't bear it.
Kill her and flee.
* Sirens *
Albrecht, are you letting the police in?
If I find out
that your husband is the murderer,
I won't keep it to myself.
Selina stayed overnight here,
so maybe Marco wasn't her great love after all.
Oh, wow.
Don't touch, please.
Do you like it?
Yes.
It reminds me somehow of my
mother: gentle, but also very loud.
Exactly, when I ...
- You don't talk to the police.
For any questions, contact me.
- Maybe I can help.
No, you can't help. We
refuse to make a statement.
Maloney, the city's notorious fixer.
What are you doing here again?
Without official summons he does
not have to answer any questions.
If it were that simple ...
- Do you want to see the body?
Who found the body?
My son, he's working
on his artwork.
Very talented, the
young man, very talented!
And where is your husband?
- On a plane, on business trips.
Since when? Now please
don't make it so hard for me.
As the wife of Mr. Schimpf
I don't have to answer you.
That's called the right
to refuse testimony.
And as Mr. Schimpf's lawyer, my
communication is subject
to attorney-client privilege.
Have a nice day.
Have you now become
the lapdog of the Schimpfs?
They're just afraid that the
police won't do a good job.
What can you possibly do wrong?
A lawyer has an affair with a secretary,
she wants to break up, he kills her and flees.
(I didn't feel any better
despite all the money.)
(Actually, I already had a client.)
That happens when
you have love in your life.
That was definitely this insult.
First he has an affair with
Selina and then he kills her.
I don't know if you can
even call that an affair.
What?
Your beloved girlfriend
stayed overnight at the office.
Apparently she reduced the
relationship to less than a minimum.
That was just temporary,she
would have come back.
He seems more like someone
whose favorite toy has been taken away.
She even
left her Porsche here.
She would have come back.
They always do.
- But not this time, hm?
* Mysterious sounds *
(The question is, how possessive
the Minimalist really is.)
(And who Selina was,
who had given her this car.)
(I did what I
always do in these situations.)
Drink, don't drive.
* Expectant Music *
Yeah, we are searching for Schimpf.
Yes, of course. I got the Number.
Yes, yes, yes.
Thank you, thank you very much.
Yes, yes. We will.
We will, thank you.
Maloney, what do you want?
I need to know
who the car belonged to.
* Phone ringing *
Hello?
Ah oui. Yes, yes, yes.
Ah, yes. Yes, yes ... Yes,
yes, yes. Thank you, thank you.
Yes, French.
- Do you want to emigrate?
We are looking for Schimpf.
We have set up an
international task force.
With all these countries
we are in contact.
Everything is interconnected, Maloney.
And what if Schimpf
hasn't flown away at all?
* Phone ringing *
* He speaks in a foreign language. *
So.
Who owned the car before?
- Why do you want to know?
Selina Kaiser got this car
shortly before her death.
That's a real lead, Maloney.
Have you had further training?
Well then, let's scan it.
(Scanner)
Thank you for your input.
Yes, please, please, please.
(Scanner) I said: \"Thank
you for your input."
Oh. Oh, oh, oh.
The car belonged to Henriette Klausen.
Car, Classics, Klausen.
She doesn't just sell cars.
What?
Does she also sell policemen?
Or is that not worth it?
She'll make mincemeat out of you
With dumplings.
*Telephone rings*
I have to go to Mrs. Klausen.
- Who are you?
Maloney, private detective.
- Are you armed?
Only with umbrella, charm and Maloney.
Maloney, private detective.
Great, a real private detective.
Even with a coat.
I'm here about Selina Kaiser.
- And who sent you?
The Holy Ghost.
Why did you give
Selina Kaiser a Porsche?
Mr. Private Detective.
That's not how it works.
Who sent you?
Do you want to frighten me?
- The Schimpfs?
Attack is the best defense.
Mr. Maloney, what
do you want from me?
*Muffled sounds* Oh my
goodness, don't forget to breathe.
Thank you.
I want to know
why you gave Selina
Kaiser a car shortly
before she was murdered.
Murdered?
Murdered, yes.
- By whom?
That's what I'm
trying to find out.
Yes.
Tell me, why did
you give her a car?
In my private escort club there
was a fire a few months ago.
Luckily no one was hurt, but the
insurance company refused
to cover the damages.
The Schimpfs represented
the insurance company.
Selina found out that they
had suppressed evidence.
She just wanted to help.
- And how?
I only know that she
indulged in this insult.
to obtain documents.
- And now she's dead.
Yes. Life is sometimes tragic.
She was like a sister to me.
A sister,  who once
bought something for you?
\"All the sex workers in my club are
self-employed, they only pay for the hotel service.
" So to speak.
Find out, who murdered Selina.
He's in good company with me.
Bring me back the Porsche,
then there will be more of it.
You lost the case against Mrs.
Klausen.
That's no secret, it's
also in the newspaper.
Do you know why?
- Because they were lucky.
Mrs.
Kaiser played Mrs.
Klausen evidence that you
had concealed. Ah, okay.
One could have reckoned with that.
Then the mistake is not with us.
- Perhaps it is. Mr. Schimpf had an affair with Mrs. Kaiser. Does Mrs. Klausen claim that?
Do you know by now where your husband is?
I want to talk to him.
- That's not possible.
Either I speak to your
husband or the police.
Both of these I'd rather not
do, but one of them I have to do.
It's not that simple.We
are being watched.
Arrive in 4 hours.
at the end of Grünwilerstrasse.
Why does everyone think,
in this case, that we are in a gangster film?
* Dull sounds *
My thousands will probably
not make any new friends.
Did it help?
For someone who is so calm
and balanced,
you carry
quite a lot of anger within you.
Not really.
But I found something
under the passenger seat.
Is your anger directed at
people too, or only at vehicles?
Am I a suspect now?
I loved Selina.
Even when you found out
that she worked as an escort?
My Selina was a prostitute?
Nowadays one would rather
say sex worker, but yes.
Sex worker?
That's too much for me.
You get used to
new words quickly.
I need peace now!
(Even if it's only about Marco,
about Marco,
and he's probably
not a good minimalist:
He's more of a murderer.)
(And yet Selina is dead.)
* Screeching brakes *
I didn't expect you.
I'm probably the only one
not being pursued by the police.
So? What are we doing here?
Has your father
hidden in a gas chamber?
My father isn't hiding,
he's just on the run, like gas.
Sometimes I wish he would dissolve into thin air.
Come with me.
Did you actually know Mrs. Kaiser well?
Barely.
And what was the relationship
of your parents to her like?
They didn't trust her.
They trust no one.
Perhaps me, but even then only
because they've known me for so long.
And do you trust your
parents capable of murder?
Do you know why I make art?
Because it wasn't enough for more?
I have been trying for a very long time
to understand who my parents are.
But whenever I look into them,
I only see myself.
I am slowly understanding
why Schimpf doesn't want him to speak to other people.
Do you know how poison works,
Maloney?
Do you know how to answer questions, Mr. Schimpf?
What?
Can you trust your parents
to commit murder?
My parents
have murdered me several times.
Several times.
So, my duty is fulfilled.
You shall walk alone into this hollow alley.
* Mysterious sounds *
Maloney.
Welcome to my branch.
Mr. Schimpf,
why did you run away?
Please, have a seat.
Can I offer you something?
Why doesn't anyone in this family
actually know
how to answer a question?
Why did you flee,
Mr. Schimpf?
My wife informed me
about your inquiries.
The most important question is:
Who has a motive?
- You.
Do I?
You had an affair
with Selina Kaiser.
She sold information.
That's why you lost the case.
What evidence is there?
- The statement of Mrs.
Klausen. Will Mrs.
Klausen testify in court?
You were the last one at the crime scene.
The murderer was the
last one at the crime scene.
What is with this affair?
The affair ...
... does not exist!
That's a figment of
the imagination of the
police officers who read
too many trash novels.
By the way, don't you think,
that I am too old for Selina?
Your wife suspects you of the affair.
And you don't believe me either.
What I believe, doesn't
play a big role here.
Will more money help?
- You can try it.
Who is the murderer?
- All signs point to you.
Don't you have any other
clues or something like that?
Who does this belong to?
- Perhaps the murderer.
That doesn't fit.
Will you tell the police where I am?
- Maybe tomorrow.
First I have to sleep on it.
Mr. Schimpf.
(The longer I
looked at the money,
the less I knew,
what was going on. )
(And who speaks the truth.)
* Ringing *
Maloney,
Schimpf confessed and said
he's Selina's killer. Come!
And he just turned himself in?
Questions
will be answered after the interrogation.
Here.
Listen, watch, learn.
You have to concentrate now.
- Yes, it ...
It is important, that you say
everything into the microphone.
So, please identify
yourself for the record.
Theres Schimpf.
- And Hans Schimpf.
So. From the beginning: What is
your relationship to Mrs. Kaiser?
My client had a
relationship with Mrs. Kaiser.
I thought we loved each other.
- That happens in every couple.
Not with me.
- Then with your wife.
Why did you
kill Mrs. Kaiser?
I found out that she was selling insider information and confronted her.
- He was angry.
Angry?
- I said I would report her.
Then she attacked me.
My client couldn't have expected that.
I defended myself and pushed her away.
- An act of passion.
Anyone would do that. Wouldn't you?
Now comes the twist:
He didn't kill her at all.
It was an accident, self-defense.
Then she stumbled
against Albrecht's sculpture.
A part fell on her head,
then I carried her to the office.
Then I saw that she was dead.
My client panicked and disappeared.
When I was clear-headed
again, I presented myself.
My client is a victim himself.
So, should you have no further questions,
we would like to end the interrogation.
The interrogation is over, you can go.
It wasn't murder at all.
- Now we have to be quick.
Why? - Watch and learn.
The gentleman wants to see
your artwork again, privately.
What do you see?
At first I saw my mother, but now ...
Now I see a goddess of steel.
We humans worship her,
and there are the lifelines.
The lifelines of our ancestors.
This is all very, very confused and messy
and at the same time very,
very simple and simple.
Confused and simple - there
someone looked in the mirror.
Yes, and then of course
climate change, yes!
And finally the deep,
deep, deep loss of all of us.
Very exciting.
Oh, look here.
Is that yours?
Yes, I haven't seen it for ages. Thank you.
All right.
- What do you see in this artwork?
I see a woman who had
an affair with an artist.
He really loved her very much.
She gave him the feeling
that he was a great artist.
But she only wanted to get
at the secret of his parents.
You know a lot about art,
Maloney.
His parents are two
very well-known lawyers.
Ah, like the Schimpfs?
- Exactly.
Ah.
And it wasn't
Mr. Schimpf who had an
affair with Mrs. Kaiser,
but his son, Albrecht.
Technically speaking
also a Mr. Schimpf.
But why did he
then kill Mrs. Kaiser?
Ask him yourself.
Why did you kill Mrs. Kaiser?
I loved Selina.
You say nothing.
We refuse to testify.
This is a private room.
- But ... - You say nothing!
Our client refuses to testify.
I am not your client.
- I'm taking down your service number.
Did I pay too little?
- Our client ...
I am not your
client, I am your son!
Quiet. Quiet!
Quiet! Now there must be quiet!
Whoever interrupts, will
be shot dead on the spot.
So?
She was the only one who
saw something in my art.
I thought that anyway. Or
she wanted me to think that.
Thoughts are strange things.
When my parents lost the case, I
realised Selina had only used me.
She ended the relationship
and laughed at my art.
I broke off a piece
and hit her on the head.
Yes, and why did you
say it was self-defense?
I refuse to make a statement.
- I showed Mr.
Schimpf the ring.
He knew it belonged to his
son and wanted to protect him.
Mr. Albrecht Schimpf, you are under arrest.
You have the right to an attorney.
- I waive that right. Come along. (Some children suffer
because they don't get enough from their parents.)
(Others go to pieces from
an overdose of parents.)
Do you want to take me in your arms again?
*Unintelligible* (Obviously
there are people who blame
me for the broken Porsche.)
* Dull sounds *
Thank you.
(Ultimately, less
is simply just less.)
(There are always a thousand reasons
to feel bad.)
(All the love in the world doesn't help)
That's how it is.
Subtitling: Metatxt
on behalf of SWISS TXT - 2024