}
(People are waiting for different things.)
(I'm waiting for a client who still
has all their marbles.)
There was the corpse.
Not anymore.
I'm not stupid.
The corpse was right here.
That’s what it looked like.
- Yes, not a pretty sight.
Mr. Maloney,
I was so scared,
that I slammed the elevator door shut.
Then the elevator went down
and I brought it back up.
And then the corpse
dissolved into thin air.
Where were you going,
so late at night?
I haven't been able to sleep for weeks,
because I hear voices from the basement.
I pulled myself together,
went to check,
and there greeted me the corpse.
- What did the voices say?
*Gurgling, whimpering*
So.
Sounds like a foreign language.
And are you sure,
that no neighbor slept off their
intoxication in the elevator?
I can tell an alcohol-induced death from
a real corpse.
I'm currently painting a
phantom image. Oh. Abstract.
It's not finished yet.
- And what does the police say?
It's always the same person on the phone,
whom I have to explain everything 3 times.
Then he told me, without a
corpse he's not responsible.
And what am I supposed to do now?
Make sure
I'm not an idiot.
Find the corpse.
* Title music by "Philip Maloney" *
The hair-raising cases
of Philip Maloney.
Today: "The Elevator".
With subtitles by SWISS TXT
(For a reasonable fee,
I am willing,
to accept even invisible corpses
for hard cash.)
(Let's see if the voices in
the basement are of human origin.)
* Unsettling sounds *
Wine.
Someone has locked up the wine.
Perhaps
I can free a bottle.
* Scream *
What are you doing here?
And you?
Are you the house ghost?
Have you seen Edi?
- No, just the Pinot.
Do you have something
to do with his disappearance?
Is Edi the man from the elevator?
Edi is my tomcat. He
is allergic to people.
Who? Him or you?
Now you're thinking, I'm a social
outcast because I live alone with my cat.
Who is really a social outcast,
is the woman on the second floor.
She doesn't even dispose
of her trash properly.
We have designated trash bags here.
* Creaking *
Edi?
* Unsettling sounds *
Metallic rattling.
(Someone who doesn't dispose
of the trash properly
may have other things to hide.)
* Doorbell *
* Footsteps *
Hello?
* Energetic Doorbell *
She might not be home at all.
Or she doesn't want to receive anyone.
You look, as if you
could use a cup of tea.
My appearance is deceiving.
- Inner values count.
I am interested in the inner
workings of the elevator.
A corpse has apparently surfaced there.
- Who says that?
Mrs. Rausch.
- That is clearly a cry for help.
The situation is simply
terrible lonely and ...
And with a corpse
one is less lonely and ...
Did you know that loneliness
is as deadly as smoking?
One has to die of something.
* Laughs * But first,
there’s tea. Come, come.
Sit down.
Perhaps
she has a corpse in the closet.
(One has garbage bags in the closet,
the other disposes of them incorrectly.)
(The house seems
to have a waste problem.)
The table is here.
It's nice here.
A home remedy.
With your own herbs and roots.
Cleansing.
And works wonders.
Do drink the tea,
it’s getting cold.
What are you planning with
those clothes in the closet?
They're for a good cause.
I am very committed to those,
who are not as well off as we are.
Perhaps you could use something.
No.
Did you hear strange noises last night?
Voices from the basement or something
like that?
No, it was actually
a very quiet night.
I slept like an angel.
Drink your tea.
No thank you.
I think
my liver can't handle it.
Adieu.
(I have the feeling,
the elevator here is the only thing
that isn’t leading me around by the nose.)
Have you hidden a body somewhere?
* Unsettling sounds *
(Maybe the stain
is from the body.)
(Or maybe
from a bloody steak.)
(At best,
there’s warm food in the soup kitchen
along with a hot lead - win-win.)
Lentil soup or cauliflower soup?
How about a steak?
- Everything here is vegetarian.
Then a coffee.
- Anything else?
Has anything unusual happened here lately?
Anyone gone missing?
That is a soup kitchen.
People come and go.
Psst, come here.
Don't look so, or they'll notice.
- What will they notice? And who is she?
The angel Cherubim.
Strange things are happening.
Burning wheels,
at least six wings.
And millions of eyes,
looking on.
That's always how it is
before the end of the world.
Haben Sie in der letzten Zeit
wohl zu viel Suppe gegessen?
The angel distributes jobs.
He's recruiting for the apocalypse.
I know everything.
Then you should
maybe write a book.
Is she your cherub?
No, she just asks stupid questions.
Shall we go?
- You may stay.
I must
look for my invisible corpse.
(Without a trace and without a steak
my win-win has
rather turned into a lose-lose.)
(As if that weren't
enough, I'm being pursued.)
Do you want to play hide and seek?
Are you a private detective?
- It says so on the door.
Lea Bleising.
- Great. And what do you want from me?
Wow, you have one of
those, crazy. Totally retro.
I only have one.
- No cell phone?
Cell phones don't
have a battery just
when you need them most.
- A real detective.
What were you doing
at the soup kitchen?
Most soups are boring.
Except alphabet soup.
She has the attention
span of a squirrel.
I followed you.
- (Sarcastically) What? And why?
To find out if you know anything
about Tim's disappearance.
I don't know any Tim.
- He used to study with me.
That's usually a
matter for the police.
Now leave my things alone!
They say he's old
enough to go underground.
So you thought you'd
play detective a little bit?
Exactly.
- Have fun. There’s the door.
I found in a forum
cold cases of other missing persons.
And where were they last seen?
In my office?
- In the soup kitchen.
People
disappear from the soup kitchen?
What if Tim
got involved in a drug ring?
He stumbled upon the secret
of the Big Boss,
they lured him into a trap
and killed him.
* Telephone ringing *
No, I haven’t found your corpse
yet.
I’m coming.
What kind of case is this?
I’m not even sure
if it is one.
What are you investigating?
A corpse has disappeared.
What is our next step?
- Ours? You're looking for Tim.
Maybe he's run away.
What's the address?
You can't come with us.
- Why?
I can't afford
an intern.
Do you not have enough money?
- No, not enough nerves.
Come on!
(I hope she is gone.)
(I prefer invisible corpses
to visible annoyances.)
* Uncomfortable sounds *
How did you find me?
You can be tracked with an app.
* Doorbell rings *
(Mrs. Rausch)
It’s open.
Ah, have you
brought support with you?
Not really.
She ran to me.
Lea Bleising.
I am supporting the investigation.
Look, the composite sketch
is just finished.
Not bad. Everything with wine?
Nero d'Avola, a southern grape.
Pinot is too thin.
So that's our corpse.
- That's Tim!
Well, look...
We're working on the same case.
We'll find the corpse.
May I take this with me?
- Yes, gladly.
Now we need the police to help us.
When you're young, you're
still allowed to have illusions.
* Gentle sounds *
(Speakers) We sink
deep into the ground...
...while we let the breath flow.
We breathe in… And out again.
Hey, what’s that supposed to mean?
Haben wir Ihr
Mittagsschläfchen gestört?
That’s not a nap,
that’s meditation.
You have no idea, Maloney.
It's important, against burnout.
You take care of it not worried
citizens like Mrs. Rausch.
- Rausch ...
Ah, the missing corpse.
- Tim Wiesenbach.
Has been missing for three
weeks. Now he is dead.
Did you paint this, Mrs.…
- Bleising. No, Mrs. Rausch.
Very complex. Bravo.
So, are you doing anything now?
There's nothing to do. Mrs.
Bleising is not entirely accountable.
I am Mrs. Bleising.
I said so. She hears
voices, sees corpses.
An artist, it’s all imagination.
Look in the system, to see if
anyone in the house is suspicious.
Have you ever heard of
data protection, Madam ...
What if Tim was lured into the house under
false pretenses and killed there?
- And why?
Maybe someone in the
house is a cannibal and
occasionally picks a person
from the soup kitchen.
Because he's craving something
other than vegetable soup.
Exactly, Bro.
That would be really good ...
Elevator shaft 5.
Don't touch it.
Ah, here.
Kaja Lutz, previously convicted.
Cannibalism?
- Improper disposal of garbage?
No, she stole a few
utensils from the hospital.
Okay. Enough.
* Gentle sounds *
(Loudspeaker) Feel your body...
He meant, Mrs. Lutz.
Come on, we need to talk to her.
* Uncomfortable sounds *
Maybe she's hiding.
* Elevator *
Creepy.
Did you steal Edi?
No.
Who are you actually?
Lea Bleising, private detective.
Then can you find my Edi?
Oh, a cat!
Please bring him home.
There's also a reward.
We can't take on new cases
we're at risk of burnout.
I'll take care of it.
* Uncomfortable sounds *
* Energetic ringing *
Maybe she's hiding.
You can't run away.
We have a case to solve.
- We don't have anything to solve.
I need
no sidekick with ADHD.
* Awkward sounds *
Mrs. Lutz?
You're not so strict with
the garbage separation?
What are you? A waste detective?
This is my assistant, Mr. Maloney.
Lea Bleising ...
Did you hear something suspicious?
- No.
You stole from the hospital.
Do you have a laboratory
for illegal experiments?
Someone has a vivid
imagination. I like that.
We would like to inspect your trash.
- Why?
In this elevator
a corpse has disappeared.
Has Mrs. Rausch
seen ghosts again?
No, a corpse.
Is it in your bag?
Excuse me?
Do you have a corpse in your bag?
- No.
Okay, cool. Can I look inside?
- Is she crazy?
Listen, I actually think you shouldn’t
interfere in the affairs of your neighbors.
But Mrs. Rausch likes
to consume a little more
than the recommended amount of alcohol.
Of course, there are
one or two side effects.
Anything else?
- No, adieu.
Adieu.
She's lying! We have to follow her.
I'm hungry.
- What kind of detective are you?
A hungry one.
- One has to do everything oneself.
(Over the years, you learn not
to chase every lead immediately.)
(And you can't solve cases
on an empty stomach.)
Nero d'Avola.
A good drop, drinkable.
Is that one of those
who got a job?
They saw him,
the many eyes.
Cherubim took him with him.
He is here.
The corpse?
- Cherubim.
I have started with the book.
- Ah, great.
* Threatening sounds *
I know those.
It certainly looks like
Mrs. Engel
has just started her shift.
So the perfect window of opportunity
for a house call.
The woman
promised Tim a job, then.
But is she also an angel of death?
* Creaking *
It certainly looks like it.
One really shouldn't
interfere in the affairs of others.
(As a child, I wondered how one
gets to the afterlife, when one dies.)
(I wouldn't have thought, that it
would happen with the elevator.)
Where are we going?
To heaven.
Why is it going down then?
Such a high tolerance
for narcotics.
is not good for the liver.
(What kind of detective are you?)
- (A hungry one.)
Everything has to be done yourself.
* Expectant sounds *
* Phone ringing *
Yes?
Okay.
Good.
I'll take care of it.
* Buzzing of flies *
Fuck. I was completely right.
* Busy signal *
Shit.
Okay.
I was right, it was Mrs. Lutz.
I knew she was suspicious.
What are you doing?
Thank God.
You absolutely have to help me.
What's wrong?
Something terrible happened to Mr. Maloney.
It's awful.
* Sobbing *
How did you get in here?
*Uncomfortable sounds*
*Suffocated noises*
Let's get it over with.
- That's easily said,
when you don't do the dirty work yourself.
What's that supposed to mean now?
- What do we do with him?
The same as always.
You can't sell his busted organs to anyone.
He knows too much, he has to go.
*Clears throat* Weren't
you taught that it's
impolite to talk about people
who are present?
Speak of the devil.
- That's more likely you.
*Choked sounds*
She wants to say something.
Is that necessary?
You have Edi on your conscience!
That stupid cat was already
dead before we moved in.
And you just stole it?
- Exactly.
Can we please start now?
Why don't you do something yourself.
Don't act like you're
doing everything alone.
Without the people from the soup
kitchen we wouldn't have anything to sell.
Are you trying to fool me? You
can't get anything more out of it.
Then we’ll just throw it away completely.
- (In pain) Ah.
Ah, my eyes!
Then I’ll just do it myself.
I'm too old for playing doctor.
- This isn’t a game.
This is your end. What
can you still accomplish?
I nothing. But her.
Bro.
Maloney. I’ve been
off work for a long time.
Couldn't you have exposed those
two ladies during office hours?
You are fortunately a civil
servant and can write off overtime.
What exactly happened now?
- It's very simple.
Mrs... Mrs. Kaja Lutz and
Mrs. Christina Engel operated...
an illegal laundry business from
from their organic kitchen.
And what's that supposed to mean?
Notes.
For my first crime novel.
The woman in the house with
the corpse in the elevator,
which the police didn't believe.
- Realistic.
Everyone knows better
than the police again.
It's high time
he understood that.
But please, I mean, how did
the corpse get into the elevator?
Mrs. Engel recruited young people
in the soup kitchen.
Mrs. Lutz sedated them,
together they drove them
with the elevator to the
laundry room and killed her.
When I saw the body,
was she still alive?
That's right. Strictly speaking,
your corpse wasn't a corpse at all.
So you're an idiot.
- Shit.
Mission accomplished.
Thank you.
I’m an idiot.
Alright, make way,
I want to go home.
What should I do with them?
Best to get rid of them.
Your share.
Not necessary.
I solved my own case.
(A new blood detective,
who gets more pay
for a stuffed cat than we do
for solving a murder case -
that gnaws at your self-esteem.)
It’s time to leave.
Where are we going?
- Not "we". You.
Okay. Maybe I’ll actually
do an internship with you.
(Just whiskey left -
that’s good for my health.)
(Who wants
the liver of a boozer?)
(That’s how it’s done.)
Subtitling: Metatxt commissioned
by SWISS TXT - 2025