* Snoring. *
*Phone rings*
*Phone ringing*
Yes?
- (Woman) Mr. Maloney?
Mr. Maloney, I need your help.
- That's what everyone says.
Please. My name is Alder.
I work at the Bel
Etage luxury clinic.
My colleague,
Mr. Rossmann, was murdered.
Who says that?
The police say it was
suicide, but that's not true.
Luxury clinic, you say?
- I’ve organized everything.
You are expected in one
hour under the name Maroni.
Marroni isn't
obvious, is he? or?
Trust no one. I'll
come to you at 10 PM.
Then I'll tell you more.
- Tell me more now.
She hangs up.
Title music by "Philip Maloney"
The Hair-Raising
Cases of Philip Maloney.
Today: "The Clinic".
With subtitles by SWISS TXT
So you are Mr. Maroni?
That is what people tell me.
What do you hope to gain
from a stay in our clinic?
I hear a voice.
- What is this voice telling you?
That I shouldn't trust anyone.
They think everyone is hiding
something and that only you know the truth.
Do you feel lonely?
- Unfortunately not at the moment.
Do you not answer truthfully,
...because you are afraid,
it would rip apart your reality?
At the moment, my patience
is wearing rather thin.
You have built a very
strong wall, Mr. Maroni,
that protects you,
but also locks you in.
Where are you now
with your thoughts?
Here.
- I feel your pain.
And I feel your loneliness too.
But everything will be alright.
I can help you. Here
we treat body and mind.
Then...
You don't always have to
say something, Mr. Maroni.
Just listen and open
yourself up, okay?
Yes, we have a lot, a
lot of work ahead of us.
Restless sounds.
Tomorrow your therapy begins.
Do you enjoy working here?
Why?
Are the working conditions good,
or do you want to
jump off the roof?
Mr. Rossmann had
personal problems.
And you? Do you
want to talk about it?
Good night.
(My client, Mrs. Alder,
doesn't arrive until 10 p.m.)
I did what I always
do in such situations:
Don't lose your mind. And wait.)
*To tick*
Strange.
(If the client doesn’t
come to the detective,
(I guess the detective
has to go to the client.)
Uncomfortable sounds.
Mrs. Alder?
Steps.
Have you come to help me?
Are you Mrs. Alder?
- Mrs. Weber.
Then not.
- You are one of them too.
I am not crazy.
- I never claimed that.
I am only here because of my
father. He has money. I am not crazy.
If she continues like this, I won’t
believe a word she says anymore.
You won't get out of here.
- Hm.
(This clinic is a
strange place.)
(Mrs. Alder didn't show up,
instead a Mrs. Weber did.)
(Mr. Rossmann is dead,
Mrs. Alder says,
it wasn't suicide.)
(And she hasn't shown up.)
(Mann) Good morning.
I am the head of the clinic, I
would like to give you a tour.
Is Mrs. Alder working today?
- Mrs. Alder?
As far as I know, we don't
have a Frau Alder here.
Are you sure?
As head of the clinic, one
knows one’s employees.
Tell me.
Do you have any other questions?
- Do you lock up your patients?
Do you feel trapped?
- A little bit, yes.
Mr. Maroni, I always
say: Don't worry.
Do yoga. Feel free.
*Ringing*
Ah.
I’ll take care of that
for you, Mr. Müller.
You are doing excellent work.
- Thank you.
You can’t trust anyone anymore.
So the gentleman isn’t
the head of the clinic?
Come in. Yoga is about to begin.
Soft sounds.
Have you found the exit yet?
- Do we know each other?
Yesterday night.
- Why are you speaking to me?
That won't work!
- Mrs. Weber, Mrs. Weber.
Deep breath, just
like we practiced.
Let me.
(Various) Om.
Please stand up?
Smoking is unfortunately
prohibited here, excuse me.
Apology accepted.
Break away from your addiction.
Give me the cigarette.
Join in, it will do you good.
Then you see clearly again,
the voices in your head disappear.
Breathe in.
And exhale.
Concentrate on the essentials.
Yes.
- Breathe in.
Breathe out.
Do you miss anyone?
- No.
Look, over there in the bush.
Yes…
Oh.
That is not good
at all for our clinic.
What will the
police think of me?
No fear. They only think they
are police officers themselves.
Maloney. Have you
finally turned yourself in?
I am undercover here.
Do what you want. I'm looking
for the hospital administration.
How can I help?
- You have a corpse in the bushes.
I know that’s not ideal.
Should I release a statement?
Yes, gladly.
- On behalf of the clinic,
the sponsors, and also
personally from me…
Alright, I’ll take
care of it, Mr. Müller.
Good day.
Who is in charge now?
Me.
Her.
You have a
corpse in the bushes.
Are you sure,
that it’s a corpse?
Yes, what else could it be?
- Tell me.
What? No, no, certainly not.
Tell me.
Fascinating. I would like to
do a psychoanalysis with you.
No, no psychoanalysis.
I ask the questions here
and you answer. Yes?
Yes, but without my lawyers, I’m
afraid I’m not answering any questions.
My lords and ladies. Off
to Aqua Fit! Hop, hop, hop.
Maloney. There's a corpse in the bush.
- May I guess? Female.
There are only two possibilities.
- I've heard different.
Does she have a name too?
- Yes, we assume so.
I'm betting on Alder.
- Another one of your clients?
Mrs. Alder has hired me,
because Rossman's death
seemed suspicious to her.
Rossmann, Rossmann,
suicide… This case is closed.
Are you sure?
- He jumped off the roof.
Ah, Maloney, we must be careful.
This directive comes
from the very top.
Do you have any fear?
- Ah, papperlapapp. Maloney!
Are you the presiding officer?
- Yes, indeed.
We represent the clinic.
- What is he doing here?
Always the same: unmasking
murderers. How's the young one doing?
We represent the Bel Etage
Clinic, including patients and staff.
Also me?
- Yes, you too, Mr. Maroni.
Nasty business, Maroni.
Giggle
We are in a very
sensitive environment.
We expect the highest
level of discretion.
Your presence creates unrest.
Think of the patients.
- And female patients.
(While the police officer and the Schimpfs
were thinking about the patients,
I couldn’t stop thinking
about the clinic director.)
Hello?
May I keep you company?
They don't hear any voices at all.
- Not at the moment.
I also need one.
For body and soul.
You can definitely manage
that. I noticed you right away.
You lack that innate
arrogance of the wealthy.
I take that as a compliment.
- Who are you?
Philip Maloney,
private detective.
Mrs. Alder hired you, I presume.
She hadn’t understood
Mr. Rossmann’s suicide.
But she lived in
her own reality.
And now she’s lying
dead there in that bush.
Yes, because she loved the bush.
You have no idea how many
people kill themselves. Unfortunately.
And Mr. Rossmann
jumped down here?
Yes.
One doesn't die, if one
jumps down from here.
Did you want to say something?
One doesn't die, if one
jumps down from here.
One dies faster than one
thinks. Shall I discharge you now?
Or are you staying
a little longer?
I still need more help
for body and spirit.
Well, whatever.
But please adhere to
the rules of the clinic.
Uncomfortable sounds.
The Weber family left the clinic
after the death of Rossmann ...
a large sum of money.
I wonder why?
Have you gotten
lost, Mr. Maroni?
I'm looking for the party basement,
but it's so dark everywhere.
I will help you. No problem.
Distorted sounds
Everything is fine.
Everything is fine, Mr. Maroni.
You are in the
best hands with us.
Om..
Ah.
* Distorted sounds. *
We are watching over you.
*Ringing*
Thank you, I am served.
Oh. Now you did really well.
Yes, but this stuff is
getting to me the wrong way.
We must tell Mrs. Näf.
No.
- Come here.
Mr. Maroni would
like to say something.
I would like to be
discharged as healed.
I’m afraid I can’t support that.
Since Mr. Maroni imagines
himself, to be a private detective,
... unfortunately, I can’t release him.
- There’s only one thing left to do.
Run.
Ah.
But I'm not tired at all.
Psst.
*Distorted sounds.*
* Knocking*
Maloney! *Groaning*
*Knocking.*
At the window!
*Knocking*
I think I’m hallucinating.
Now I can already see
flying police officers.
You look terrible.
Now even the
hallucination is insulting me.
Mrs. Alder had taken
an overdose of sedatives.
Tranquilizers? Here?
They were probably right
about Stockmann’s suicide.
Um, Rossmann.
- I’m really hallucinating now.
We have the corpse of
Rossmann once again exmi... exmu...
...exmatriculated and a huge
stick... stab wound found.
So, not fallen from the roof?
- Yes, but he was already dead before that.
The world has a
sunstroke, Maloney.
Why don't you raid the
clinic and arrest everyone?
Because of the Schimpfs. You are
obstructing all investigations.
I need proof, Maloney.
Neither my body nor my
mind are made for therapy.
I have to get out of here.
- You must stay here.
You must question patients.
- No.
They must have noticed something.
Don’t fall asleep!
Yes. Good.
- Maloney!
Maloney!
*Ringing*
I'm already full. Not as
full as Mrs. Alder, but ...
Excuse me?
- I am not a patient.
Mrs. Alder has hired
me as a private detective,
because Rossmann's death
seemed suspicious to her.
And now she is dead too.
Are you really a private detective?
- Mhm.
Did you know, that the
Weber family ...
after Rossmann’s death, has transferred
a lot of money to this clinic?
Hm.
Have you figured that out?
- Exactly.
But even private detectives
have to take their medication.
Ah!
- So.
So. Now you can relax
in the thermal baths.
(If I don’t get anywhere
with the real clinic director,
I guess I’ll just have to try
my luck with the fake one.)
(One takes what one gets.)
Mr. Maroni.
How can I help you?
- It’s kind of you to ask.
That’s precisely what
distinguishes a good leader.
That’s why I’m here.
- What do you mean?
You must know, I am
here under a false name.
I am actually called Maloney
and am also the head of the clinic.
Isn't that right!
I am here to observe you.
- Me?
How you resolved the incident
at Rossmann with Mrs. Alder.
Highly professional.
- Thank you very much.
Hearing that feels really good.
I had already feared,
to have committed...
a terrible mistake,
when I hid Mrs. Alder...
in the bushes.
- You have done what?
When I found Frau Alder
dead in the basement,
I told myself:
"Now is the time."
"Now you can take responsibility."
So, you have found Mrs. Alder already dead?
Yes. As medical director,
I must ensure that,
... there are no corpses in the basement.
- Of course, you are right.
Did you push
Mr. Rossmann off the roof?
Unfortunately, no.
I would have handled that
completely differently. Terrible.
I don't know exactly,
what happened.
Just that it really
traumatized Mrs. Weber.
Mr. Müller, You have
helped me very much.
Gladly, from colleague to
colleague. All the best for your clinic.
(It was time to get back
into my own skin.)
Leave me alone!
- I'd like that.
But you must help
me, to figure out,
what happened to Mr. Rossmann.
- Rossmann, the miserable one.
He locked me in here,
just like all the others.
But he liked it. I wanted to leave.
He held me back.
Said I belonged locked up.
He insulted me.
Aha.
You know, my family says, I
am behaving conspicuously.
But in our family,
that’s not allowed.
And what happened to Rossmann?
- I defended myself.
You have …
And, is there a murder weapon?
* Uncomfortable sounds. *
Mrs. Näf has tidied up.
Has she, um.
I shouldn’t have told
Mrs. Alden anything.
She was always so kind to me.
It is essential to know,
what the employees are hiding.
Ah.
Then I guess I’ll just
have to use force.
Doesn't that hurt?
Why don't you just
take my badge?
You stay here
and give me a sign, as
soon as Mrs. Näf appears.
(My body and mind couldn’t
concentrate on the search.)
(I need a cigarette.)
If she can hide cigarettes there, then
she can also hide the murder weapon.
Voilà.
What is the meaning
of this, Mr. Maloney?
Mrs. Näf is here.
- Yes, thank you, I see it.
Mrs. Weber told me everything.
They are holding her captive here.
I am not holding anyone captive.
That's what the wealthy families do.
They are happy when they can
drop their spoiled brat(s) here.
And then you thought to yourself,
you can also benefit from it.
I earned the money too.
And does Mrs.
Alder deserve to die?
Nobody deserves to die,
but we must. Sooner or later.
Aha.
Aren’t you taking your
medication anymore?
They struck at body and soul.
And you are, of course,
always the smartest in the room.
Then you also know,
what happens next?
Yes, you are calling Demir.
- Yes.
So sad. I believe, we would
have gotten along so well.
Yes…
Demir, a patient has broken in.
He wants to do something to me.
Please come quickly!
Mrs. Näf?
- Oh, Demir.
Mr. Maroni is a little confused.
He wanted to attack me. Quick!
Demir...
It is all good, Mrs. Näf.
Mrs. Alder was a friend.
* relaxed sounds *
I recommend locking me up.
In me there is so
much criminal energy.
I wonder where she comes from.
Maybe I have narcissistic
personality disorder?
My mom...
- That's enough now.
You are under arrest.
And?
Yes, you did that well.
Bravo.
Please, please!
I stabbed
Mr. Rossmann, arrest me.
No, I can’t do that, Mrs. Weber.
You are not legally sane.
- I am legally sane.
You must arrest me.
In prison, I am free.
Okay, if you absolutely
insist. Arrested.
You must arrest me
too. I was an accomplice.
Take responsibility.
- Fine.
Arrested.
(Thanks to me, the police
have too many people to lock up.)
(And I am finally free.)
(It’s not exactly a Bel Etage.)
(But at least there is nobody
who wants to drug me here.)
(And you don't lose your mind so quickly.)
(That’s how it’s done.)
Subtitling: MetaText on
behalf of SWISS TXT - 2025
}